<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Last updated: 2026-01-29T01:12:36Z -->
<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://arxiv.org/api/p6EyKyP4fMY/66n9Ev8E79F7KlI</id>
  <title>arXiv Query: search_query=all:causal OR all:inference&amp;id_list=&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <updated>2026-01-29T01:12:37Z</updated>
  <link href="https://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query=all:causal+OR+all:inference&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10&amp;id_list=" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage>10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <opensearch:totalResults>131892</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex>0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2601.19866v1</id>
    <title>Discovery of Galactic center ejected star in DESI DR1</title>
    <updated>2026-01-27T18:25:09Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.19866v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2601.19866v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Hypervelocity stars (HVSs) are stars ejected from the Galactic Centre (GC) through tidal interactions with the central supermassive black hole. Formed in the immediate vicinity of Sgr~A$^\ast$, these stars are accelerated to velocities high enough to escape the GC and be observable in the Galactic halo. Using spectroscopy from the Dark Energy Spectroscopic Instrument (DESI) and astrometry from Gaia, we conducted a six-dimensional search for HVSs and identified a compelling candidate, hereafter DESI-312, whose bound trajectory can be confidently traced back to the GC. The star resides in the inner halo and exhibits supersolar metallicity ([Fe/H] $= 0.27\pm 0.09$), distinct from other known stellar populations with radial orbits. Its inferred GC ejection velocity of $698^{+35}_{-27}$ is consistent with a Hills mechanism ejection, supporting an origin in the innermost regions of the Milky Way. We considered alternative origins for the star, including disk ejections from young clusters and globular clusters, but these scenarios fail to explain both its orbit and metallicity. Unlike previously identified A- and B-type HVSs, DESI-312 is a $\sim 1\,M_{\odot}$ star on the main sequence or early subgiant branch, thus enabling a detailed chemical analysis of its atmosphere and offering a rare window - unobscured by dust and crowding - into the composition of the central regions of the Galaxy.</summary>
    <category term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-01-27T18:25:09Z</published>
    <arxiv:comment>12 pages, 5 figures, submitted to A&amp;A, comments are welcome!</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="astro-ph.GA"/>
    <author>
      <name>Manuel Cavieres</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sergey E. Koposov</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Elena Maria Rossi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zephyr Penoyre</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sill Verberne</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2601.19863v1</id>
    <title>Prompt cusps in hierarchical dark matter halos: Implications for annihilation boost</title>
    <updated>2026-01-27T18:21:08Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.19863v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2601.19863v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Recent simulations have identified long-lived ``prompt cusps'' -- compact remnants of early density peaks with inner profiles $ρ\propto r^{-3/2}$. They can survive hierarchical assembly and potentially enhance signals of dark matter annihilation. In this work, we incorporate prompt cusps into the semi-analytic substructure framework \textsc{SASHIMI}, enabling a fully hierarchical, environment-dependent calculation of the annihilation luminosity that consistently tracks subhalos, sub-subhalos, and tidal stripping. We assign prompt cusps to first-generation microhalos and propagate their survival through the merger history, including an explicit treatment of cusps associated with stripped substructure. We find that the substructure hierarchy converges rapidly once a few levels are included, and that prompt cusps can raise the total annihilation boost of Milky-Way--size hosts at $z=0$ to $B\sim O(10)$ for fiducial cusp-occupation assumptions, compared to a subhalo-only baseline of $B_{\rm sh}\sim\mathrm{few}$. Across a wide range of host masses and redshifts, prompt cusps increase the normalization of $B(M_{\rm host},z)$ while largely preserving its mass and redshift trends. Compared to universal-average, peak-based estimates, our fiducial boosts are lower by about an order of magnitude, primarily reflecting a correspondingly smaller inferred cusp abundance in host halos, highlighting the importance of unifying peak-based cusp formation with merger-tree evolution and environmental dependence.</summary>
    <category term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.HE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="hep-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-01-27T18:21:08Z</published>
    <arxiv:comment>17 pages, 4 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="astro-ph.GA"/>
    <author>
      <name>Shin'ichiro Ando</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Martin Moro</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Youyou Li</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2601.19847v1</id>
    <title>Identifying and Transferring Reasoning-Critical Neurons: Improving LLM Inference Reliability via Activation Steering</title>
    <updated>2026-01-27T17:53:01Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.19847v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2601.19847v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Despite the strong reasoning capabilities of recent large language models (LLMs), achieving reliable performance on challenging tasks often requires post-training or computationally expensive sampling strategies, limiting their practical efficiency. In this work, we first show that a small subset of neurons in LLMs exhibits strong predictive correlations with reasoning correctness. Based on this observation, we propose AdaRAS (Adaptive Reasoning Activation Steering), a lightweight test-time framework that improves reasoning reliability by selectively intervening on neuron activations. AdaRAS identifies Reasoning-Critical Neurons (RCNs) via a polarity-aware mean-difference criterion and adaptively steers their activations during inference, enhancing incorrect reasoning traces while avoiding degradation on already-correct cases. Experiments on 10 mathematics and coding benchmarks demonstrate consistent improvements, including over 13% gains on AIME-24 and AIME-25. Moreover, AdaRAS exhibits strong transferability across datasets and scalability to stronger models, outperforming post-training methods without additional training or sampling cost.</summary>
    <category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-01-27T17:53:01Z</published>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="cs.CL"/>
    <author>
      <name>Fangan Dong</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zuming Yan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xuri Ge</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zhiwei Xu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mengqi Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xuanang Chen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ben He</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xin Xin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zhumin Chen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ying Zhou</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2601.19842v1</id>
    <title>Dynamical Evidence for a Billion Solar Mass Black Hole in Galaxy NGC 4061 from ALMA $^{12}$CO(2-1) Kinematics</title>
    <updated>2026-01-27T17:48:22Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.19842v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2601.19842v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>We present the first robust dynamical measurement of the supermassive black hole (SMBH) mass in the massive early-type galaxy NGC 4061 using high-spatial-resolution ALMA observations of the $^{12}$CO(2-1) emission. By combining archival Cycle 6 data with new Cycle 7 observations, we achieve a synthesized beam of $0''.16 \times 0''.13$, comparable to the expected sphere of influence of the central black hole. The molecular gas forms a regularly rotating circumnuclear disk aligned with the prominent dust lane seen in HST imaging. We model the full three-dimensional ALMA data cube using the KinMS forward-modeling framework, exploring both data-driven and analytic prescriptions for the gas surface brightness distribution. Our Bayesian analysis yields a best-fitting SMBH mass of $M_{\rm BH} = (1.17^{+0.08}_{-0.10}\,[{\rm stat.}] \pm 0.43\,[{\rm syst.}]) \times 10^{9}$ M$_\odot$ and an $I$-band stellar mass-to-light ratio of $M/L_{\rm F814W} = 3.46^{+0.07}_{-0.06}\,[{\rm stat.}] \pm 0.10\,[{\rm syst.}]$ M$_\odot$/L$_\odot$. The inferred black hole mass is fully consistent across different modeling assumptions and remains insensitive to plausible radial variations in the $M/L_{\rm F814W}$ profile. Our results resolve the long-standing discrepancy between previous indirect mass estimates based on conflicting stellar velocity dispersion measurements and demonstrate that the exceptionally large dispersion reported in the literature is likely spurious. This study highlights the power of high-resolution ALMA molecular gas kinematics for precision SMBH mass measurements at the high-mass end of the local black hole mass function.</summary>
    <category term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-01-27T17:48:22Z</published>
    <arxiv:comment>26 pages, 16 figures, 10 tables. Submitted to The Astrophysical Journal (ApJ)</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="astro-ph.GA"/>
    <author>
      <name>Dieu D. Nguyen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Long Q. T. Nguyen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Elena Gallo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hai N. Ngo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Que T. Le</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Fabio Pacucci</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tinh Q. T. Le</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tuan N. Le</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tien H. T. Ho</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2601.19822v1</id>
    <title>A Latent Space Framework for Modeling Transient Engine Emissions Using Joint Embedding Predictive Architectures</title>
    <updated>2026-01-27T17:29:05Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.19822v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2601.19822v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Accurately modeling and controlling vehicle exhaust emissions during transient events, such as rapid acceleration, is critical for meeting environmental regulations and optimizing powertrains. Conventional data-driven methods, such as Multilayer Perceptrons (MLPs) and Long Short-Term Memory (LSTM) networks, improve upon phenomenological models but often struggle with the complex nonlinear dynamics of emission formation. These monolithic architectures are sensitive to dataset variability and typically require deep, computationally expensive structures to perform well, limiting their practical utility. This paper introduces a novel approach that overcomes these limitations by modeling emission dynamics within a structured latent space. Leveraging a Joint Embedding Predictive Architecture (JEPA), the proposed framework learns from a rich dataset that combines real-world Portable Emission Measurement System (PEMS) data with high-frequency hardware-in-the-loop measurements. The model abstracts away irrelevant noise, encoding only the key factors governing emission behavior into a compact, robust representation. This results in superior data efficiency and predictive accuracy across diverse transient regimes, significantly outperforming high-performing LSTM baselines in generalization. To ensure suitability for real-world deployment, the JEPA framework is structured to support pruning and post-training quantization. This strategy drastically reduces the computational footprint, minimizing inference time and memory demand with negligible accuracy loss. The result is a highly efficient model ideal for on-board implementation of advanced strategies, such as model predictive control or model-based reinforcement learning, in conventional and hybrid powertrains. These findings offer a clear pathway toward more robust emission control systems for next-generation vehicles.</summary>
    <category term="eess.SY" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-01-27T17:29:05Z</published>
    <arxiv:comment>10 pages, Submitted to the 2026 SAE WCX</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="eess.SY"/>
    <author>
      <name>Ganesh Sundaram</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tobias Gehra</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jonas Ulmen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mirjan Heubaum</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Daniel Görges</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Michael Günthner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2601.19812v1</id>
    <title>An essential building block for cosmological zoom-in perturbation theory</title>
    <updated>2026-01-27T17:14:15Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.19812v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2601.19812v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>The evolution of large-scale structure within the standard model of cosmology is well posed only up to the onset of shell crossing, where particle trajectories appear to intersect. Beyond this point, the evolution equations become non-predictive and perturbative approaches break down. We show that in General Relativity, a matter horizon forms before caustics develop for a well-defined initial over-density on an expanding FLRW spacetime. The matter horizon was first identified by Ellis and Stoeger in 2010 as a dynamical causal boundary that encloses a sub-region of spacetime where structure formation actually takes place. We construct a multi-scale hierarchical framework for the propagation of geodesic congruences that avoids the shell-crossing singularity by cutting the spacetime at the matter horizon and glueing to another spacetime with opposite orientation. We identify a relationship between the multi-scale hierarchical framework and the cosmological zoom-in N-body simulation approach, and relate the local sub-region that decouples from the Hubble flow to the region of interest in cosmological zoom-in N-body simulations. Most importantly, the multi-scale hierarchical framework provides a more robust way of implementing boundary conditions, which could benefit cosmological zoom-in N-body simulation approaches.</summary>
    <category term="astro-ph.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="gr-qc" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-01-27T17:14:15Z</published>
    <arxiv:comment>27 pages, 10 Figures</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="astro-ph.CO"/>
    <author>
      <name>Obinna Umeh</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2601.19793v1</id>
    <title>CASTER: Breaking the Cost-Performance Barrier in Multi-Agent Orchestration via Context-Aware Strategy for Task Efficient Routing</title>
    <updated>2026-01-27T16:52:47Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.19793v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2601.19793v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Graph-based Multi-Agent Systems (MAS) enable complex cyclic workflows but suffer from inefficient static model allocation, where deploying strong models uniformly wastes computation on trivial sub-tasks. We propose CASTER (Context-Aware Strategy for Task Efficient Routing), a lightweight router for dynamic model selection in graph-based MAS. CASTER employs a Dual-Signal Router that combines semantic embeddings with structural meta-features to estimate task difficulty. During training, the router self-optimizes through a Cold Start to Iterative Evolution paradigm, learning from its own routing failures via on-policy negative feedback. Experiments using LLM-as-a-Judge evaluation across Software Engineering, Data Analysis, Scientific Discovery, and Cybersecurity demonstrate that CASTER reduces inference cost by up to 72.4% compared to strong-model baselines while matching their success rates, and consistently outperforms both heuristic routing and FrugalGPT across all domains.</summary>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-01-27T16:52:47Z</published>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="cs.AI"/>
    <author>
      <name>Shanyv Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xuyang Yuan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tao Chen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zijun Zhan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zhu Han</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Danyang Zheng</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Weishan Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Shaohua Cao</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2601.19789v1</id>
    <title>Equation of State of Highly Asymmetric Neutron-Star Matter from Liquid Drop Model and Meson Polytropes</title>
    <updated>2026-01-27T16:51:32Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.19789v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2601.19789v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>We present a unified description of dense matter and neutron-star structure based on simple but physically motivated models. Starting from the thermodynamics of degenerate Fermi gases, we construct an equation of state for cold, catalyzed matter by combining relativistic fermion statistics with the liquid drop model of nuclear binding. The internal stratification of matter in the outer crust is described by $β$-equilibrium, neutron drip and a gradual transition to supranuclear matter. Short-range repulsive interactions inspired by Quantum Hadrodynamics are incorporated at high densities in order to ensure stability and causality. The resulting equation of state is used as input to the Tolman--Oppenheimer--Volkoff equations, yielding self-consistent neutron-star models. We compute macroscopic stellar properties including the mass-radius relation, compactness and surface redshift that can be compared with recent observational data. Despite the simplicity of the underlying microphysics, the model produces neutron-star masses and radii compatible with current observational constraints from X-ray timing and gravitational-wave measurements. This work demonstrates that physically transparent models can already capture the essential features of neutron-star structure and provide valuable insight into the connection between dense-matter physics and astrophysical observables while they can also be used as easy to handle models to test the impact of more complicated phenomena and variations in neutron stars.</summary>
    <category term="nucl-th" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.HE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="hep-th" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-01-27T16:51:32Z</published>
    <arxiv:comment>This article belongs to the Special Issue Nuclear Symmetry Energy: From Finite Nuclei to Neutron Stars</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="nucl-th"/>
    <arxiv:journal_ref>Symmetry, 2026, 18(2), 225</arxiv:journal_ref>
    <author>
      <name>Elissaios Andronopoulos</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Konstantinos N. Gourgouliatos</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:doi>10.3390/sym18020225</arxiv:doi>
    <link rel="related" href="https://doi.org/10.3390/sym18020225" title="doi"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2601.19788v1</id>
    <title>Knowledge-Aware Evolution for Streaming Federated Continual Learning with Category Overlap and without Task Identifiers</title>
    <updated>2026-01-27T16:50:48Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.19788v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2601.19788v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Federated Continual Learning (FCL) leverages inter-client collaboration to balance new knowledge acquisition and prior knowledge retention in non-stationary data. However, existing batch-based FCL methods lack adaptability to streaming scenarios featuring category overlap between old and new data and absent task identifiers, leading to indistinguishability of old and new knowledge, uncertain task assignments for samples, and knowledge confusion.To address this, we propose streaming federated continual learning setting: per federated learning (FL) round, clients process streaming data with disjoint samples and potentially overlapping categories without task identifiers, necessitating sustained inference capability for all prior categories after each FL round.Next, we introduce FedKACE: 1) an adaptive inference model switching mechanism that enables unidirectional switching from local model to global model to achieve a trade-off between personalization and generalization; 2) a adaptive gradient-balanced replay scheme that reconciles new knowledge learning and old knowledge retention under overlapping-class scenarios; 3) a kernel spectral boundary buffer maintenance that preserves high-information and high-boundary-influence samples to optimize cross-round knowledge retention. Experiments across multiple scenarios and regret analysis demonstrate the effectiveness of FedKACE.</summary>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.DC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-01-27T16:50:48Z</published>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="cs.LG"/>
    <author>
      <name>Sixing Tan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xianmin Liu</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2601.19741v1</id>
    <title>Effect of noise characterization on the detection of mHz stochastic gravitational waves</title>
    <updated>2026-01-27T16:01:36Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.19741v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2601.19741v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Pulsar timing arrays' hint for a stochastic gravitational-wave background (SGWB) leverages the expectations of a future detection in the millihertz band, particularly with the LISA space mission. However, finding an SGWB with a single orbiting detector is challenging: It calls for cautious modelling of instrumental noise, which is also mainly stochastic. It was shown that agnostic noise reconstruction methods provide robustness in the detection process. We build on previous work to include more realistic instrumental simulations and additional degrees of freedom in the noise inference model and analyze the impact of LISA's sensitivity to SGWBs. Particularly, we model the two main types of noise sources with separate transfer functions and power spectral density spline fitting. We assess the detectability bounds and their dependence on the flexibility of the noise model and on the prior probability, allowing us to refine previously reported results.</summary>
    <category term="gr-qc" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-01-27T16:01:36Z</published>
    <arxiv:comment>19 pages, 6 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="gr-qc"/>
    <author>
      <name>Nikolaos Karnesis</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Quentin Baghi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jean-Baptiste Bayle</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Nikiforos Galanis</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
