<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Last updated: 2025-07-17T01:01:52Z -->
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3Dall%3Acausal%20inference%26id_list%3D%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=all:causal inference&amp;id_list=&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/SsRksLzRb0LuVhSmQ+N8WbAs+f8</id>
  <updated>2025-07-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">117001</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2507.11539v1</id>
    <updated>2025-07-15T17:59:57Z</updated>
    <published>2025-07-15T17:59:57Z</published>
    <title>Streaming 4D Visual Geometry Transformer</title>
    <summary>  Perceiving and reconstructing 4D spatial-temporal geometry from videos is a
fundamental yet challenging computer vision task. To facilitate interactive and
real-time applications, we propose a streaming 4D visual geometry transformer
that shares a similar philosophy with autoregressive large language models. We
explore a simple and efficient design and employ a causal transformer
architecture to process the input sequence in an online manner. We use temporal
causal attention and cache the historical keys and values as implicit memory to
enable efficient streaming long-term 4D reconstruction. This design can handle
real-time 4D reconstruction by incrementally integrating historical information
while maintaining high-quality spatial consistency. For efficient training, we
propose to distill knowledge from the dense bidirectional visual geometry
grounded transformer (VGGT) to our causal model. For inference, our model
supports the migration of optimized efficient attention operator (e.g.,
FlashAttention) from the field of large language models. Extensive experiments
on various 4D geometry perception benchmarks demonstrate that our model
increases the inference speed in online scenarios while maintaining competitive
performance, paving the way for scalable and interactive 4D vision systems.
Code is available at: https://github.com/wzzheng/StreamVGGT.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Dong Zhuo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Wenzhao Zheng</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jiahe Guo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yuqi Wu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jie Zhou</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jiwen Lu</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Code is available at: https://github.com/wzzheng/StreamVGGT</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2507.11539v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2507.11539v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2507.11535v1</id>
    <updated>2025-07-15T17:58:55Z</updated>
    <published>2025-07-15T17:58:55Z</published>
    <title>Canonical Bayesian Linear System Identification</title>
    <summary>  Standard Bayesian approaches for linear time-invariant (LTI) system
identification are hindered by parameter non-identifiability; the resulting
complex, multi-modal posteriors make inference inefficient and impractical. We
solve this problem by embedding canonical forms of LTI systems within the
Bayesian framework. We rigorously establish that inference in these minimal
parameterizations fully captures all invariant system dynamics (e.g., transfer
functions, eigenvalues, predictive distributions of system outputs) while
resolving identifiability. This approach unlocks the use of meaningful,
structure-aware priors (e.g., enforcing stability via eigenvalues) and ensures
conditions for a Bernstein--von Mises theorem -- a link between Bayesian and
frequentist large-sample asymptotics that is broken in standard forms.
Extensive simulations with modern MCMC methods highlight advantages over
standard parameterizations: canonical forms achieve higher computational
efficiency, generate interpretable and well-behaved posteriors, and provide
robust uncertainty estimates, particularly from limited data.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrey Bryutkin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Matthew E. Levine</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Iñigo Urteaga</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Youssef Marzouk</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">46 pages, 9 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2507.11535v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2507.11535v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.SY" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="eess.SY" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2507.11507v1</id>
    <updated>2025-07-15T17:23:22Z</updated>
    <published>2025-07-15T17:23:22Z</published>
    <title>MIRAGE: KV Cache Optimization through Parameter Remapping for
  Multi-tenant LLM Serving</title>
    <summary>  KV cache accelerates LLM inference by avoiding redundant computation, at the
expense of memory. To support larger KV caches, prior work extends GPU memory
with CPU memory via CPU-offloading. This involves swapping KV cache between GPU
and CPU memory. However, because the cache updates dynamically, such swapping
incurs high CPU memory traffic. We make a key observation that model parameters
remain constant during runtime, unlike the dynamically updated KV cache.
Building on this, we introduce MIRAGE, which avoids KV cache swapping by
remapping, and thereby repurposing, the memory allocated to model parameters
for KV cache. This parameter remapping is especially beneficial in multi-tenant
environments, where the memory used for the parameters of the inactive models
can be more aggressively reclaimed. Exploiting the high CPU-GPU bandwidth
offered by the modern hardware, such as the NVIDIA Grace Hopper Superchip, we
show that MIRAGE significantly outperforms state-of-the-art solutions,
achieving a reduction of 44.8%-82.5% in tail time-between-token latency,
20.7%-99.3% in tail time-to-first-token latency, and 6.6%-86.7% higher
throughput compared to vLLM.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ruihao Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Shagnik Pal</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Vineeth Narayan Pullu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Prasoon Sinha</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jeeho Ryoo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lizy K. John</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Neeraja J. Yadwadkar</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2507.11507v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2507.11507v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.OS" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.OS" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2507.11504v1</id>
    <updated>2025-07-15T17:20:45Z</updated>
    <published>2025-07-15T17:20:45Z</published>
    <title>A Transiting Giant on a 7.7-Year Orbit Revealed by TTVs in the TOI-201
  System</title>
    <summary>  We report the detection and characterization of TOI-201 c, a long-period
transiting companion to the warm Jupiter TOI-201 b. Its presence was first
inferred from high-amplitude transit timing variations (TTVs) in TOI-201 b,
pointing to a massive outer body on a $7.7^{+1.0}_{-0.6}$-year eccentric orbit.
This prediction was confirmed when TESS observed a transit of TOI-201 c,
precisely constraining its orbital geometry. A joint fit to TTVs, transit
photometry, and archival radial velocities yields a mass of
$14.2^{+1.0}_{-1.2}$ $M_{\rm Jup}$ and an eccentricity of
$0.643^{+0.009}_{-0.021}$. The mutual inclination between planets b and c is
$2.9^{+4.8}_{-4.4}$ degrees, indicating a nearly coplanar architecture.
Long-term numerical integrations confirm dynamical stability over gigayear
timescales and predict that transits of TOI-201 b will cease within a few
thousand years. TOI-201 c ranks among the longest-period transiting planets
with well-constrained properties. Its detection via TTVs, followed by a
confirmed transit, represents a rare observational sequence and highlights the
power of TTVs and photometric monitoring to uncover distant companions. The
TOI-201 system offers a valuable laboratory for testing models of giant planet
formation, migration, and secular evolution in multi-planet systems.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Gracjan Maciejewski</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Weronika Łoboda</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Accepted for publication in ApJL on 2025-07-14, submitted on
  2025-06-23</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2507.11504v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2507.11504v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="astro-ph.EP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.EP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2507.11492v1</id>
    <updated>2025-07-15T17:06:35Z</updated>
    <published>2025-07-15T17:06:35Z</published>
    <title>Low-redshift analogues of cosmic noon galaxies as laboratories for
  clumpy star formation</title>
    <summary>  It has been established that a significant fraction of star formation at
high-redshift occurs in clumpy galaxies. The properties of clumps and their
formation mechanisms, however, remain highly debated. In this work we analyze a
sample of 18 Supercompact Ultraviolet Luminous Galaxies observed with the
OSIRIS spectrograph at the Keck Telescope, targeting their Pa-alpha emission.
These galaxies, although at z~0.1-0.2, share many similar properties with
star-forming galaxies at cosmic noon. We find a total of 84 star-forming clumps
with typical sizes of a few hundred parsecs. The star-forming clumps exhibit
low values of velocity shear (~12 km/s) and high velocity dispersion (~70
km/s). The dynamical masses of the clumps are typically higher than gas masses
inferred from the measured star-formation rates of each clump. We also
artificially redshift our data to emulate observations at z=2.2 and allow for a
direct comparison with other galaxies at higher redshift. Our results indicate
that, due to the effects of clump clustering and low-resolution observations,
high-z clumps appear larger at greater cosmological distances. This underscores
the importance of using low-redshift observations to anchor studies at earlier
epochs. Finally, our results support the idea of growing clump sizes in
star-forming galaxies as a function of redshift, although not to scales of kpc
as found by other works without the benefits of adaptive optics or
gravitational lensing.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Jorge M. Santos-Junior</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Thiago S. Goncalves</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Luidhy Santana-Silva</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Arianna Cortesi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Karin Menendez-Delmestre</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Amanda E. de Araujo-Carvalho</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:doi xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">10.3847/1538-4357/add926</arxiv:doi>
    <link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.3847/1538-4357/add926" rel="related"/>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">19 pages, 11 figures, 3 tables, accepted for publication in ApJ</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2507.11492v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2507.11492v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2507.11461v1</id>
    <updated>2025-07-15T16:33:01Z</updated>
    <published>2025-07-15T16:33:01Z</published>
    <title>Deep Equilibrium models for Poisson Imaging Inverse problems via Mirror
  Descent</title>
    <summary>  Deep Equilibrium Models (DEQs) are implicit neural networks with fixed
points, which have recently gained attention for learning image regularization
functionals, particularly in settings involving Gaussian fidelities, where
assumptions on the forward operator ensure contractiveness of standard
(proximal) Gradient Descent operators. In this work, we extend the application
of DEQs to Poisson inverse problems, where the data fidelity term is more
appropriately modeled by the Kullback-Leibler divergence. To this end, we
introduce a novel DEQ formulation based on Mirror Descent defined in terms of a
tailored non-Euclidean geometry that naturally adapts with the structure of the
data term. This enables the learning of neural regularizers within a principled
training framework. We derive sufficient conditions to guarantee the
convergence of the learned reconstruction scheme and propose computational
strategies that enable both efficient training and fully parameter-free
inference. Numerical experiments show that our method outperforms traditional
model-based approaches and it is comparable to the performance of Bregman
Plug-and-Play methods, while mitigating their typical drawbacks - namely,
sensitivity to initialization and careful tuning of hyperparameters. The code
is publicly available at https://github.com/christiandaniele/DEQ-MD.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Christian Daniele</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Silvia Villa</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Samuel Vaiter</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Luca Calatroni</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2507.11461v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2507.11461v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="math.OC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.OC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="65K10, 65J22, 94A08, 47N10" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2507.11456v1</id>
    <updated>2025-07-15T16:27:05Z</updated>
    <published>2025-07-15T16:27:05Z</published>
    <title>Timescales for stochastic barrier crossing: inferring the potential from
  nonequilibrium data</title>
    <summary>  Kramers' rate theory forms a cornerstone for thermally activated barrier
crossing. However, its reliance on equilibrium quantities excludes analysis of
nonequilibrium dynamics at early times. Most works have thus focused on
obtaining rates and transition time and path distributions in equilibrium.
Instead, here we consider early-time nonequilibrium dynamics in a model system
of a particle with overdamped dynamics hopping over the barrier in a
double-well potential, using the Smoluchowski equation (SE) and stochastic path
integral (SPI) mapping of the Langevin equation. We identify several key
timescales relevant to nonequilibrium dynamics and quantify them using the SE
and SPI approaches. The shortest timescale corresponds to equilibration in a
well at time $t \ll \tau_{\rm B}$, where $\tau_{\rm B}$ is the Brownian
diffusion time. The second important timescale is when an inflexion point
appears in the effective potential constructed from the density at $t
\lessapprox \tau_{\rm B}$. Shortly after, the existence of a second potential
well can be inferred from sufficient sampling of the dynamics. Interestingly,
this timescale decreases with increasing barrier height. We find significant
deviations from the equilibrium limit unless $t \gg \tau_{\rm B}$. We further
calculate \red{the} density current at the barrier for bistable and asymmetric
potentials and find that it crosses over to that from equilibrium rate theory
at a time that does not appear to depend on the barrier height. Our results
have important implications for controlling activated processes at finite times
and demonstrate the importance of reaching long enough times to faithfully
construct potential landscapes from experimental or simulation data.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>A. J. Archer</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>T. Ala-Nissila</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>T. J. W. Honour</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>S. P. Fitzgerald</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">21 pages, 7 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2507.11456v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2507.11456v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cond-mat.stat-mech" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.stat-mech" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.chem-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2507.11442v1</id>
    <updated>2025-07-15T16:06:33Z</updated>
    <published>2025-07-15T16:06:33Z</published>
    <title>Identifying galactic binary systems of neutron stars and black holes
  with LISA</title>
    <summary>  The Laser Interferometer Space Antenna (LISA) will detect ~ 100 galactic
binary systems comprised of black holes (BHs) and neutron stars (NSs).
Identifying the nature of the constituents of these binaries as BHs or NSs, and
distinguishing them from $\sim 10^4$ detected double white dwarfs will be
challenging. In the absence of any other information, the inferred values of
the component masses can be used to classify the nature of these objects.
However, short-period galactic binaries $\sim 10^7 - 10^3$ yr from coalescence
produce a quasi-monochromatic signal which carries little information about
their masses. We generate synthetic LISA data sets containing gravitational
waves (GWs) from galactic binary BHs, binary NSs and BHNSs drawn from an
astrophysically realistic population produced through the isolated binary
evolution channel. We process the data with an end-to-end Bayesian inference
pipeline to explore the accuracy with which the individual component masses can
be measured. We find that for $\approx 10\% - 50\%$ of the detected systems
LISA will be able to measure the individual component masses by measuring the
orbital eccentricity, periapse precession frequency, and GW induced frequency
derivative. Typical fractional mass errors are $\approx 1\% - 100\%$ (depending
on the specific value of the source parameters), which will enable in many
circumstances the classification of the objects as BHs or NSs. For these
binaries, LISA will also be able to determine their 3-dimensional position in
the Milky Way. The LISA-detected sample of these double compact objects will
provide new information about the galactic population of BHs and NSs, the star
formation history of the Milky Way and the astrophysical processes leading to
the formation of these systems. However, for a significant fraction of the
LISA-detected binaries the nature of their constituent objects may remain
unclear.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Hannah Middleton</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Panagiota Kolitsidou</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Antoine Klein</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Connor Adam</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Rowan Chalmers</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alberto Vecchio</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">23 pages, 11 figures, 8 tables</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2507.11442v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2507.11442v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="astro-ph.HE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.HE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2507.11435v1</id>
    <updated>2025-07-15T15:57:28Z</updated>
    <published>2025-07-15T15:57:28Z</published>
    <title>FasTUSS: Faster Task-Aware Unified Source Separation</title>
    <summary>  Time-Frequency (TF) dual-path models are currently among the best performing
audio source separation network architectures, achieving state-of-the-art
performance in speech enhancement, music source separation, and cinematic audio
source separation. While they are characterized by a relatively low parameter
count, they still require a considerable number of operations, implying a
higher execution time. This problem is exacerbated by the trend towards bigger
models trained on large amounts of data to solve more general tasks, such as
the recently introduced task-aware unified source separation (TUSS) model.
TUSS, which aims to solve audio source separation tasks using a single,
conditional model, is built upon TF-Locoformer, a TF dual-path model combining
convolution and attention layers. The task definition comes in the form of a
sequence of prompts that specify the number and type of sources to be
extracted. In this paper, we analyze the design choices of TUSS with the goal
of optimizing its performance-complexity trade-off. We derive two more
efficient models, FasTUSS-8.3G and FasTUSS-11.7G that reduce the original
model's operations by 81\% and 73\% with minor performance drops of 1.2~dB and
0.4~dB averaged over all benchmarks, respectively. Additionally, we investigate
the impact of prompt conditioning to derive a causal TUSS model.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Francesco Paissan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Gordon Wichern</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yoshiki Masuyama</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ryo Aihara</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>François G. Germain</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kohei Saijo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jonathan Le Roux</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Accepted to WASPAA 2025</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2507.11435v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2507.11435v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.SD" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.SD" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="eess.AS" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="eess.SP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2507.11417v1</id>
    <updated>2025-07-15T15:44:03Z</updated>
    <published>2025-07-15T15:44:03Z</published>
    <title>Quantifying the Energy Consumption and Carbon Emissions of LLM Inference
  via Simulations</title>
    <summary>  The environmental impact of Large Language Models (LLMs) is rising
significantly, with inference now accounting for more than half of their total
lifecycle carbon emissions. However, existing simulation frameworks, which are
increasingly used to determine efficient LLM deployments, lack any concept of
power and, therefore, cannot accurately estimate inference-related emissions.
We present a simulation framework to assess the energy and carbon implications
of LLM inference under varying deployment setups. First, we extend a
high-fidelity LLM inference simulator with a GPU power model that estimates
power consumption based on utilization metrics, enabling analysis across
configurations like batch size, sequence length, and model parallelism. Second,
we integrate simulation outputs into an energy system co-simulation environment
to quantify carbon emissions under specific grid conditions and explore the
potential of carbon-aware scheduling. Through scenario-based analysis, our
framework reveals how inference parameters affect energy demand and carbon
footprint, demonstrates a renewable offset potential of up to 69.2% in an
illustrative deployment case, and provides a foundation for future carbon-aware
inference infrastructure design.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Miray Özcan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Philipp Wiesner</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Philipp Weiß</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Odej Kao</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Presented at the Workshop on Performance and Energy Efficiency in
  Concurrent and Distributed Systems (PECS) at Euro-PAR'25</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2507.11417v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2507.11417v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.DC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.DC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
