<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Last updated: 2025-08-27T00:54:26Z -->
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3Dall%3Acausal%20inference%26id_list%3D%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=all:causal inference&amp;id_list=&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/SsRksLzRb0LuVhSmQ+N8WbAs+f8</id>
  <updated>2025-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">119638</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.18265v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-25T17:58:17Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-25T17:58:17Z</published>
    <title>InternVL3.5: Advancing Open-Source Multimodal Models in Versatility,
  Reasoning, and Efficiency</title>
    <summary>  We introduce InternVL 3.5, a new family of open-source multimodal models that
significantly advances versatility, reasoning capability, and inference
efficiency along the InternVL series. A key innovation is the Cascade
Reinforcement Learning (Cascade RL) framework, which enhances reasoning through
a two-stage process: offline RL for stable convergence and online RL for
refined alignment. This coarse-to-fine training strategy leads to substantial
improvements on downstream reasoning tasks, e.g., MMMU and MathVista. To
optimize efficiency, we propose a Visual Resolution Router (ViR) that
dynamically adjusts the resolution of visual tokens without compromising
performance. Coupled with ViR, our Decoupled Vision-Language Deployment (DvD)
strategy separates the vision encoder and language model across different GPUs,
effectively balancing computational load. These contributions collectively
enable InternVL3.5 to achieve up to a +16.0\% gain in overall reasoning
performance and a 4.05$\times$ inference speedup compared to its predecessor,
i.e., InternVL3. In addition, InternVL3.5 supports novel capabilities such as
GUI interaction and embodied agency. Notably, our largest model, i.e.,
InternVL3.5-241B-A28B, attains state-of-the-art results among open-source MLLMs
across general multimodal, reasoning, text, and agentic tasks -- narrowing the
performance gap with leading commercial models like GPT-5. All models and code
are publicly released.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Weiyun Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zhangwei Gao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lixin Gu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hengjun Pu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Long Cui</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xingguang Wei</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zhaoyang Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Linglin Jing</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Shenglong Ye</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jie Shao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zhaokai Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zhe Chen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hongjie Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ganlin Yang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Haomin Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Qi Wei</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jinhui Yin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Wenhao Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Erfei Cui</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Guanzhou Chen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zichen Ding</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Changyao Tian</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zhenyu Wu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jingjing Xie</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zehao Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Bowen Yang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yuchen Duan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xuehui Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Songze Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xiangyu Zhao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Haodong Duan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Nianchen Deng</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Bin Fu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yinan He</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yi Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Conghui He</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Botian Shi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Junjun He</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yingtong Xiong</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Han Lv</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lijun Wu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Wenqi Shao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kaipeng Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Huipeng Deng</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Biqing Qi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jiaye Ge</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Qipeng Guo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Wenwei Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Wanli Ouyang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Limin Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Min Dou</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xizhou Zhu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tong Lu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Dahua Lin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jifeng Dai</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Bowen Zhou</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Weijie Su</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kai Chen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yu Qiao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Wenhai Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Gen Luo</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.18265v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.18265v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.18264v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-25T17:57:49Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-25T17:57:49Z</published>
    <title>MMTok: Multimodal Coverage Maximization for Efficient Inference of VLMs</title>
    <summary>  Vision-Language Models (VLMs) demonstrate impressive performance in
understanding visual content with language instruction by converting visual
input to vision tokens. However, redundancy in vision tokens results in the
degenerated inference efficiency of VLMs. While many algorithms have been
proposed to reduce the number of vision tokens, most of them apply only
unimodal information (i.e., vision/text) for pruning and ignore the inherent
multimodal property of vision-language tasks. Moreover, it lacks a generic
criterion that can be applied to different modalities. To mitigate this
limitation, in this work, we propose to leverage both vision and text tokens to
select informative vision tokens by the criterion of coverage. We first
formulate the subset selection problem as a maximum coverage problem.
Afterward, a subset of vision tokens is optimized to cover the text tokens and
the original set of vision tokens, simultaneously. Finally, a VLM agent can be
adopted to further improve the quality of text tokens for guiding vision
pruning. The proposed method MMTok is extensively evaluated on benchmark
datasets with different VLMs. The comparison illustrates that vision and text
information are complementary, and combining multimodal information can surpass
the unimodal baseline with a clear margin. Moreover, under the maximum coverage
criterion on the POPE dataset, our method achieves a 1.87x speedup while
maintaining 98.7% of the original performance on LLaVA-NeXT-13B. Furthermore,
with only four vision tokens, it still preserves 87.7% of the original
performance on LLaVA-1.5-7B. These results highlight the effectiveness of
coverage in token selection.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Sixun Dong</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Juhua Hu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mian Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ming Yin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yanjie Fu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Qi Qian</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Project page: https://project.ironieser.cc/mmtok</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.18264v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.18264v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.18260v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-25T17:53:22Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-25T17:53:22Z</published>
    <title>MIRAGE: Scaling Test-Time Inference with Parallel
  Graph-Retrieval-Augmented Reasoning Chains</title>
    <summary>  Large reasoning models (LRMs) have shown significant progress in test-time
scaling through chain-of-thought prompting. Current approaches like search-o1
integrate retrieval augmented generation (RAG) into multi-step reasoning
processes but rely on a single, linear reasoning chain while incorporating
unstructured textual information in a flat, context-agnostic manner. As a
result, these approaches can lead to error accumulation throughout the
reasoning chain, which significantly limits its effectiveness in medical
question-answering (QA) tasks where both accuracy and traceability are critical
requirements. To address these challenges, we propose MIRAGE (Multi-chain
Inference with Retrieval-Augmented Graph Exploration), a novel test-time
scalable reasoning framework that performs dynamic multi-chain inference over
structured medical knowledge graphs. Specifically, MIRAGE 1) decomposes complex
queries into entity-grounded sub-questions, 2) executes parallel inference
chains, 3) retrieves evidence adaptively via neighbor expansion and multi-hop
traversal, and 4) integrates answers using cross-chain verification to resolve
contradictions. Experiments on three medical QA benchmarks (GenMedGPT-5k,
CMCQA, and ExplainCPE) show that MIRAGE consistently outperforms GPT-4o,
Tree-of-Thought variants, and other retrieval-augmented baselines in both
automatic and human evaluations. Additionally, MIRAGE improves interpretability
by generating explicit reasoning chains that trace each factual claim to
concrete chains within the knowledge graph, making it well-suited for complex
medical reasoning scenarios. The code will be available for further research.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Kaiwen Wei</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Rui Shan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Dongsheng Zou</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jianzhong Yang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Bi Zhao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Junnan Zhu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jiang Zhong</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">10 pages, 8 figures (including tables), plus appendix. Submitted to
  AAAI 2026</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.18260v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.18260v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="I.2.3; I.2.4; I.2.7" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.18224v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-25T17:22:15Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-25T17:22:15Z</published>
    <title>Flash Sparse Attention: An Alternative Efficient Implementation of
  Native Sparse Attention Kernel</title>
    <summary>  Recent progress in sparse attention mechanisms has demonstrated strong
potential for reducing the computational cost of long-context training and
inference in large language models (LLMs). Native Sparse Attention (NSA), a
state-of-the-art approach, introduces natively trainable, hardware-aligned
sparse attention that delivers substantial system-level performance gains while
maintaining accuracy comparable to full attention. However, the kernel
implementation of NSA relies on a query-grouping strategy that is efficient
only with large Grouped Query Attention (GQA) sizes, whereas modern LLMs
typically adopt much smaller GQA groups, which limits the applicability of this
sparse algorithmic advance. In this work, we propose Flash Sparse Attention
(FSA), which includes an alternative kernel design that enables efficient NSA
computation across a wide range of popular LLMs with varied smaller GQA group
sizes on modern GPUs. Compared to vanilla NSA kernel implementation, our
empirical evaluation demonstrates that FSA achieves (i) up to 3.5$\times$ and
on average 1.6$\times$ kernel-level latency reduction, (ii) up to 1.25$\times$
and 1.09$\times$ on average end-to-end training speedup on state-of-the-art
LLMs, and (iii) up to 1.36$\times$ and 1.11$\times$ on average end-to-end
prefill speedup on state-of-the-art LLMs. The source code is open-sourced and
publicly available at
https://github.com/Relaxed-System-Lab/Flash-Sparse-Attention.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ran Yan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Youhe Jiang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Binhang Yuan</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.18224v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.18224v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.DC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.DC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.18213v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-25T17:11:53Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-25T17:11:53Z</published>
    <title>Follow My Hold: Hand-Object Interaction Reconstruction through Geometric
  Guidance</title>
    <summary>  We propose a novel diffusion-based framework for reconstructing 3D geometry
of hand-held objects from monocular RGB images by leveraging hand-object
interaction as geometric guidance. Our method conditions a latent diffusion
model on an inpainted object appearance and uses inference-time guidance to
optimize the object reconstruction, while simultaneously ensuring plausible
hand-object interactions. Unlike prior methods that rely on extensive
post-processing or produce low-quality reconstructions, our approach directly
generates high-quality object geometry during the diffusion process by
introducing guidance with an optimization-in-the-loop design. Specifically, we
guide the diffusion model by applying supervision to the velocity field while
simultaneously optimizing the transformations of both the hand and the object
being reconstructed. This optimization is driven by multi-modal geometric cues,
including normal and depth alignment, silhouette consistency, and 2D keypoint
reprojection. We further incorporate signed distance field supervision and
enforce contact and non-intersection constraints to ensure physical
plausibility of hand-object interaction. Our method yields accurate, robust and
coherent reconstructions under occlusion while generalizing well to in-the-wild
scenarios.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ayce Idil Aytekin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Helge Rhodin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Rishabh Dabral</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Christian Theobalt</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Project page: https://aidilayce.github.io/FollowMyHold-page/</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.18213v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.18213v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.18212v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-25T17:11:28Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-25T17:11:28Z</published>
    <title>Better Language Model-Based Judging Reward Modeling through Scaling
  Comprehension Boundaries</title>
    <summary>  The emergence of LM-based judging reward modeling, represented by generative
reward models, has successfully made reinforcement learning from AI feedback
(RLAIF) efficient and scalable. To further advance this paradigm, we propose a
core insight: this form of reward modeling shares fundamental formal
consistency with natural language inference (NLI), a core task in natural
language understanding. This reframed perspective points to a key path for
building superior reward models: scaling the model's comprehension boundaries.
Pursuing this path, exploratory experiments on NLI tasks demonstrate that the
slot prediction masked language models (MLMs) incorporating contextual
explanations achieve significantly better performance compared to mainstream
autoregressive models. Based on this key finding, we propose ESFP-RM, a
two-stage LM-based judging reward model that utilizes an explanation based slot
framework for prediction to fully leverage the advantages of MLMs. Extensive
experiments demonstrate that in both reinforcement learning from human feedback
(RLHF) and out-of-distribution (OOD) scenarios, the ESFP-RM framework delivers
more stable and generalizable reward signals compared to generative reward
models.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Meiling Ning</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zhongbao Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Junda Ye</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jiabao Guo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Qingyuan Guan</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.18212v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.18212v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.18175v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-25T16:28:18Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-25T16:28:18Z</published>
    <title>Amortized Sampling with Transferable Normalizing Flows</title>
    <summary>  Efficient equilibrium sampling of molecular conformations remains a core
challenge in computational chemistry and statistical inference. Classical
approaches such as molecular dynamics or Markov chain Monte Carlo inherently
lack amortization; the computational cost of sampling must be paid in-full for
each system of interest. The widespread success of generative models has
inspired interest into overcoming this limitation through learning sampling
algorithms. Despite performing on par with conventional methods when trained on
a single system, learned samplers have so far demonstrated limited ability to
transfer across systems. We prove that deep learning enables the design of
scalable and transferable samplers by introducing Prose, a 280 million
parameter all-atom transferable normalizing flow trained on a corpus of peptide
molecular dynamics trajectories up to 8 residues in length. Prose draws
zero-shot uncorrelated proposal samples for arbitrary peptide systems,
achieving the previously intractable transferability across sequence length,
whilst retaining the efficient likelihood evaluation of normalizing flows.
Through extensive empirical evaluation we demonstrate the efficacy of Prose as
a proposal for a variety of sampling algorithms, finding a simple importance
sampling-based finetuning procedure to achieve superior performance to
established methods such as sequential Monte Carlo on unseen tetrapeptides. We
open-source the Prose codebase, model weights, and training dataset, to further
stimulate research into amortized sampling methods and finetuning objectives.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Charlie B. Tan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Majdi Hassan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Leon Klein</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Saifuddin Syed</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Dominique Beaini</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Michael M. Bronstein</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alexander Tong</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kirill Neklyudov</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.18175v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.18175v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.18167v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-25T16:16:42Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-25T16:16:42Z</published>
    <title>DiscussLLM: Teaching Large Language Models When to Speak</title>
    <summary>  Large Language Models (LLMs) have demonstrated remarkable capabilities in
understanding and generating human-like text, yet they largely operate as
reactive agents, responding only when directly prompted. This passivity creates
an "awareness gap," limiting their potential as truly collaborative partners in
dynamic human discussions. We introduce $\textit{DiscussLLM}$, a framework
designed to bridge this gap by training models to proactively decide not just
$\textit{what}$ to say, but critically, $\textit{when}$ to speak. Our primary
contribution is a scalable two-stage data generation pipeline that synthesizes
a large-scale dataset of realistic multi-turn human discussions. Each
discussion is annotated with one of five intervention types (e.g., Factual
Correction, Concept Definition) and contains an explicit conversational trigger
where an AI intervention adds value. By training models to predict a special
silent token when no intervention is needed, they learn to remain quiet until a
helpful contribution can be made. We explore two architectural baselines: an
integrated end-to-end model and a decoupled classifier-generator system
optimized for low-latency inference. We evaluate these models on their ability
to accurately time interventions and generate helpful responses, paving the way
for more situationally aware and proactive conversational AI.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Deep Anil Patel</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Iain Melvin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Christopher Malon</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Martin Renqiang Min</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.18167v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.18167v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.HC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.18165v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-25T16:15:14Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-25T16:15:14Z</published>
    <title>Geometry of effective field theory positivity cones</title>
    <summary>  Positivity bounds are theoretical constraints on the Wilson coefficients of
an effective field theory. These bounds emerge from the requirement that a
given effective field theory must be the low-energy limit of a relativistic
quantum theory that satisfies the fundamental principles of unitarity,
locality, and causality. The task of deriving these bounds can be reformulated
as the geometric problem of finding the extremal representation of a closed
convex cone~$\mathcal C_W$. More precisely, in the presence of multiple
particle flavors, the forward-limit positivity cone $\mathcal C_W$ consists of
all positive semi-definite tensors in $W =\left\{ S \in \mathrm{Sym}^2
(\mathrm{Sym}^2\, V^*)\oplus \mathrm{Sym}^2 \left({\Lambda}^2 V^*\right) : \tau
S = S \right\}
  \subset \mathrm{Sym}^2(V^*\otimes V^*)$, where $\tau$ denotes transposition
in the second and fourth tensor factor and $V\cong\mathbb{R}^n$, where $n$ is
the number of flavors. In this work, we solve this question up to three
flavors, i.e.~$n=3$, proving a full classification of all extremal elements in
these cases. We furthermore study the implications of our findings, deriving
the full positivity bounds for amplitudes with and without additional
symmetries. In the cases with additional symmetries that we consider, we find
that the so-called elastic bounds are sufficient to give rise to the full
positivity bounds.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Quentin Bonnefoy</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Vicente Cortés</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Emanuele Gendy</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Christophe Grojean</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Karim Ritter von Merkl</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Paula Naomi Pilatus</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.18165v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.18165v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="math-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="hep-th" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.AG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.MP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="52A20, 15B48, 81T12" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.18164v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-25T16:13:42Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-25T16:13:42Z</published>
    <title>S2Sent: Nested Selectivity Aware Sentence Representation Learning</title>
    <summary>  The combination of Transformer-based encoders with contrastive learning
represents the current mainstream paradigm for sentence representation
learning. This paradigm is typically based on the hidden states of the last
Transformer block of the encoder. However, within Transformer-based encoders,
different blocks exhibit varying degrees of semantic perception ability. From
the perspective of interpretability, the semantic perception potential of
knowledge neurons is modulated by stimuli, thus rational cross-block
representation fusion is a direction worth optimizing. To balance the semantic
redundancy and loss across block fusion, we propose a sentence representation
selection mechanism S\textsuperscript{2}Sent, which integrates a parameterized
nested selector downstream of the Transformer-based encoder. This selector
performs spatial selection (SS) and nested frequency selection (FS) from a
modular perspective. The SS innovatively employs a spatial squeeze based
self-gating mechanism to obtain adaptive weights, which not only achieves
fusion with low information redundancy but also captures the dependencies
between embedding features. The nested FS replaces GAP with different DCT basis
functions to achieve spatial squeeze with low semantic loss. Extensive
experiments have demonstrated that S\textsuperscript{2}Sent achieves
significant improvements over baseline methods with negligible additional
parameters and inference latency, while highlighting high integrability and
scalability.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Jianxiang Zang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Nijia Mo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yonda Wei</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Meiling Ning</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hui Liu</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.18164v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.18164v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
