<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Last updated: 2026-01-08T01:02:13Z -->
<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://arxiv.org/api/p6EyKyP4fMY/66n9Ev8E79F7KlI</id>
  <title>arXiv Query: search_query=all:causal OR all:inference&amp;id_list=&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <updated>2026-01-08T01:02:31Z</updated>
  <link href="https://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query=all:causal+OR+all:inference&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10&amp;id_list=" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage>10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <opensearch:totalResults>130230</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex>0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03257v1</id>
    <title>Heavy Black-Holes Also Matter in Standard Siren Cosmology</title>
    <updated>2026-01-06T18:59:59Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03257v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2601.03257v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>With the release of the Gravitational-Wave Transient Catalog GWTC-4.0 by the LIGO-Virgo-KAGRA (LVK) collaboration, 218 candidate detections of gravitational waves (GWs) from compact binary coalescences (CBCs) have been reported. This milestone represents a major advancement for GW cosmology, as many methods, particularly those employing the spectral siren approach, critically depend on the number of available sources. We investigate the impact of a novel parametric model describing the full population mass spectrum of CBCs on the estimation of the Hubble constant. This model is designed to test the impact of heavy black holes in GW cosmology. We perform a joint inference of cosmological and population parameters using 142 CBCs from GWTC-4.0 with a false alarm rate smaller than 0.25 per year, using both spectral and dark siren approaches. With spectral sirens, we estimate the Hubble constant to be $H_0 = 78.8^{+19.0}_{-15.3}\,{\rm km s^{-1} Mpc^{-1}}$ (68% CL), while the dark siren method yields $H_0 = 82.5^{+16.8}_{-14.3}\,{\rm km s^{-1} Mpc^{-1}}$ (68% CL). These results improve the uncertainty by approximately 30.4% and 36.2%, respectively. We show that this improvement is linked to the presence of a new mass scale in the binary black hole mass spectrum at $63.3^{+4.8}_{-4.8}\,M_{\odot}$, which provides additional constraints on the Hubble constant. Besides providing the tightest standard-siren constraints on $H_0$, this highlights the importance of a heavy-mass feature in the black hole spectrum.</summary>
    <category term="astro-ph.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="gr-qc" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-01-06T18:59:59Z</published>
    <arxiv:comment>5 pages, 4 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="astro-ph.CO"/>
    <author>
      <name>Grégoire Pierra</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alexander Papadopoulos</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03245v1</id>
    <title>Consistent thermodynamics reconstructed from transitions between nonequilibrium steady-states</title>
    <updated>2026-01-06T18:41:02Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03245v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2601.03245v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Constructing a thermodynamic framework for nonequilibrium systems remains a major challenge, as quantities such as temperature and free energy often become ambiguous when inferred solely from steady-state properties. Here we take a transformation-based approach and experimentally examine transitions between nonequilibrium steady states (NESS). Using an optically trapped microparticle driven by a tunable correlated stochastic force, we generate active-like steady states with controllable noise statistics. By abruptly changing the trap stiffness, we measure the stochastic work, heat, and entropy produced during NESS-to-NESS transformations. We identify a state-dependent effective temperature that restores the second law for these transitions, enabling the definition of a generalized work that incorporates the consequence of the nonequilibrium fluctuations. With this quantity, we derive and experimentally verify a Crooks-like fluctuation relation linking work distributions to a nonequilibrium free-energy difference defined through the effective temperature. Finally, we establish a fluctuation-response relation for the positional variance following stiffness changes. We demonstrate that this relation is key to distinguishing systems that can be described by a unique effective temperature (i.e., those under equilibrium or white-noise conditions) from those under colored-noise, where an equilibrium-like response cannot be restored. These results delineate the applicability and limits of effective-temperature thermodynamics in driven systems.</summary>
    <category term="cond-mat.stat-mech" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.soft" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-01-06T18:41:02Z</published>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="cond-mat.stat-mech"/>
    <author>
      <name>Rémi Goerlich</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Benjamin Sorkin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Dima Boriskovsky</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Luís B Pires</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Benjamin Lindner</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Cyriaque Genet</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yael Roichman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03244v1</id>
    <title>Self-Supervised Learning from Noisy and Incomplete Data</title>
    <updated>2026-01-06T18:40:50Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03244v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2601.03244v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Many important problems in science and engineering involve inferring a signal from noisy and/or incomplete observations, where the observation process is known. Historically, this problem has been tackled using hand-crafted regularization (e.g., sparsity, total-variation) to obtain meaningful estimates. Recent data-driven methods often offer better solutions by directly learning a solver from examples of ground-truth signals and associated observations. However, in many real-world applications, obtaining ground-truth references for training is expensive or impossible. Self-supervised learning methods offer a promising alternative by learning a solver from measurement data alone, bypassing the need for ground-truth references. This manuscript provides a comprehensive summary of different self-supervised methods for inverse problems, with a special emphasis on their theoretical underpinnings, and presents practical applications in imaging inverse problems.</summary>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="eess.IV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-01-06T18:40:50Z</published>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="stat.ML"/>
    <author>
      <name>Julián Tachella</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mike Davies</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03236v1</id>
    <title>MAGMA: A Multi-Graph based Agentic Memory Architecture for AI Agents</title>
    <updated>2026-01-06T18:29:43Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03236v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2601.03236v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Memory-Augmented Generation (MAG) extends Large Language Models with external memory to support long-context reasoning, but existing approaches largely rely on semantic similarity over monolithic memory stores, entangling temporal, causal, and entity information. This design limits interpretability and alignment between query intent and retrieved evidence, leading to suboptimal reasoning accuracy. In this paper, we propose MAGMA, a multi-graph agentic memory architecture that represents each memory item across orthogonal semantic, temporal, causal, and entity graphs. MAGMA formulates retrieval as policy-guided traversal over these relational views, enabling query-adaptive selection and structured context construction. By decoupling memory representation from retrieval logic, MAGMA provides transparent reasoning paths and fine-grained control over retrieval. Experiments on LoCoMo and LongMemEval demonstrate that MAGMA consistently outperforms state-of-the-art agentic memory systems in long-horizon reasoning tasks.</summary>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-01-06T18:29:43Z</published>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="cs.AI"/>
    <author>
      <name>Dongming Jiang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yi Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Guanpeng Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Bingzhe Li</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03233v1</id>
    <title>LTX-2: Efficient Joint Audio-Visual Foundation Model</title>
    <updated>2026-01-06T18:24:41Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03233v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2601.03233v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Recent text-to-video diffusion models can generate compelling video sequences, yet they remain silent -- missing the semantic, emotional, and atmospheric cues that audio provides. We introduce LTX-2, an open-source foundational model capable of generating high-quality, temporally synchronized audiovisual content in a unified manner. LTX-2 consists of an asymmetric dual-stream transformer with a 14B-parameter video stream and a 5B-parameter audio stream, coupled through bidirectional audio-video cross-attention layers with temporal positional embeddings and cross-modality AdaLN for shared timestep conditioning. This architecture enables efficient training and inference of a unified audiovisual model while allocating more capacity for video generation than audio generation. We employ a multilingual text encoder for broader prompt understanding and introduce a modality-aware classifier-free guidance (modality-CFG) mechanism for improved audiovisual alignment and controllability. Beyond generating speech, LTX-2 produces rich, coherent audio tracks that follow the characters, environment, style, and emotion of each scene -- complete with natural background and foley elements. In our evaluations, the model achieves state-of-the-art audiovisual quality and prompt adherence among open-source systems, while delivering results comparable to proprietary models at a fraction of their computational cost and inference time. All model weights and code are publicly released.</summary>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-01-06T18:24:41Z</published>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="cs.CV"/>
    <author>
      <name>Yoav HaCohen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Benny Brazowski</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Nisan Chiprut</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yaki Bitterman</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Kvochko</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Avishai Berkowitz</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Daniel Shalem</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Daphna Lifschitz</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Dudu Moshe</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Eitan Porat</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Eitan Richardson</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Guy Shiran</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Itay Chachy</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jonathan Chetboun</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Michael Finkelson</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Michael Kupchick</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Nir Zabari</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Nitzan Guetta</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Noa Kotler</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ofir Bibi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ori Gordon</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Poriya Panet</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Roi Benita</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Shahar Armon</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Victor Kulikov</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yaron Inger</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yonatan Shiftan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zeev Melumian</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zeev Farbman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03231v1</id>
    <title>Standard Model Higgs Peaks: a Note on the Vacuum Instability during Inflation</title>
    <updated>2026-01-06T18:18:25Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03231v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2601.03231v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>In the Standard Model, the Higgs potential develops an instability at high field values when the quartic self-coupling runs negative. Large quantum fluctuations during cosmic inflation could drive the Higgs field beyond the potential barrier, creating regions that would be catastrophic for our observable universe. We point out that the extreme-value statistics describing the peaks (maxima) of the Higgs values is the correct statistics to infer the condition to avoid vacuum instability. Even if this statistics delivers a bound on the Hubble rate during inflation which is only a factor $\sqrt{2}$ stronger than the one commonly adopted in the literature, it is qualitatively distinct and we believe worthwhile communicating it.</summary>
    <category term="hep-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="gr-qc" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="hep-th" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-01-06T18:18:25Z</published>
    <arxiv:comment>8 pages, 1 figure</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="hep-ph"/>
    <author>
      <name>G. Franciolini</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>A. Kehagias</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>A. Riotto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03227v1</id>
    <title>The Sonar Moment: Benchmarking Audio-Language Models in Audio Geo-Localization</title>
    <updated>2026-01-06T18:13:24Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03227v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2601.03227v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Geo-localization aims to infer the geographic origin of a given signal. In computer vision, geo-localization has served as a demanding benchmark for compositional reasoning and is relevant to public safety. In contrast, progress on audio geo-localization has been constrained by the lack of high-quality audio-location pairs. To address this gap, we introduce AGL1K, the first audio geo-localization benchmark for audio language models (ALMs), spanning 72 countries and territories. To extract reliably localizable samples from a crowd-sourced platform, we propose the Audio Localizability metric that quantifies the informativeness of each recording, yielding 1,444 curated audio clips. Evaluations on 16 ALMs show that ALMs have emerged with audio geo-localization capability. We find that closed-source models substantially outperform open-source models, and that linguistic clues often dominate as a scaffold for prediction. We further analyze ALMs' reasoning traces, regional bias, error causes, and the interpretability of the localizability metric. Overall, AGL1K establishes a benchmark for audio geo-localization and may advance ALMs with better geospatial reasoning capability.</summary>
    <category term="cs.SD" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-01-06T18:13:24Z</published>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="cs.SD"/>
    <author>
      <name>Ruixing Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zihan Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Leilei Sun</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tongyu Zhu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Weifeng Lv</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03217v1</id>
    <title>MalruleLib: Large-Scale Executable Misconception Reasoning with Step Traces for Modeling Student Thinking in Mathematics</title>
    <updated>2026-01-06T17:59:37Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03217v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2601.03217v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Student mistakes in mathematics are often systematic: a learner applies a coherent but wrong procedure and repeats it across contexts. We introduce MalruleLib, a learning-science-grounded framework that translates documented misconceptions into executable procedures, drawing on 67 learning-science and mathematics education sources, and generates step-by-step traces of malrule-consistent student work. We formalize a core student-modeling problem as Malrule Reasoning Accuracy (MRA): infer a misconception from one worked mistake and predict the student's next answer under cross-template rephrasing. Across nine language models (4B-120B), accuracy drops from 66% on direct problem solving to 40% on cross-template misconception prediction. MalruleLib encodes 101 malrules over 498 parameterized problem templates and produces paired dual-path traces for both correct reasoning and malrule-consistent student reasoning. Because malrules are executable and templates are parameterizable, MalruleLib can generate over one million instances, enabling scalable supervision and controlled evaluation. Using MalruleLib, we observe cross-template degradations of 10-21%, while providing student step traces improves prediction by 3-15%. We release MalruleLib as infrastructure for educational AI that models student procedures across contexts, enabling diagnosis and feedback that targets the underlying misconception.</summary>
    <category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-01-06T17:59:37Z</published>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="cs.CL"/>
    <author>
      <name>Xinghe Chen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Naiming Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Shashank Sonkar</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03214v1</id>
    <title>When does entanglement through gravity imply gravitons?</title>
    <updated>2026-01-06T17:54:24Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03214v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2601.03214v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Detection of entanglement through the Newtonian potential has been claimed to support the existence of gravitons, by extrapolating to a thought experiment which demonstrates that complementarity and causality would be in conflict unless quantum fluctuations exist. We critically assess this consistency argument using scalar field models. We show that whether complementarity or no-signalling is violated when quantum fluctuations are neglected, depends on how this approximation is taken, while in both cases entanglement is generated locally in spacetime. We clarify that the correct reading of the paradox requires making a clear distinction between two notions of causality violation: Newtonian action-at-a-distance and the quantum mechanical no-signalling; the latter is pertinent while the former is not. We conclude that the thought experiment (a) does not add to the epistemological relevance of entanglement through Newtonian potentials (b) lends support for the existence of gravitons, if retardation effects are detected in entanglement through gravity.</summary>
    <category term="gr-qc" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-01-06T17:54:24Z</published>
    <arxiv:comment>1 figure</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="gr-qc"/>
    <author>
      <name>Nikolaos Mitrakos</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Maria Papageorgiou</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>T. Rick Perche</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Marios Christodoulou</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03203v1</id>
    <title>Counterfactual Fairness with Graph Uncertainty</title>
    <updated>2026-01-06T17:33:26Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.03203v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2601.03203v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Evaluating machine learning (ML) model bias is key to building trustworthy and robust ML systems. Counterfactual Fairness (CF) audits allow the measurement of bias of ML models with a causal framework, yet their conclusions rely on a single causal graph that is rarely known with certainty in real-world scenarios. We propose CF with Graph Uncertainty (CF-GU), a bias evaluation procedure that incorporates the uncertainty of specifying a causal graph into CF. CF-GU (i) bootstraps a Causal Discovery algorithm under domain knowledge constraints to produce a bag of plausible Directed Acyclic Graphs (DAGs), (ii) quantifies graph uncertainty with the normalized Shannon entropy, and (iii) provides confidence bounds on CF metrics. Experiments on synthetic data show how contrasting domain knowledge assumptions support or refute audits of CF, while experiments on real-world data (COMPAS and Adult datasets) pinpoint well-known biases with high confidence, even when supplied with minimal domain knowledge constraints.</summary>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CY" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-01-06T17:33:26Z</published>
    <arxiv:comment>Peer reviewed pre-print. Presented at the BIAS 2025 Workshop at ECML PKDD</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="cs.LG"/>
    <author>
      <name>Davi Valério</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Chrysoula Zerva</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mariana Pinto</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ricardo Santos</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>André Carreiro</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
