<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Last updated: 2025-08-07T01:03:40Z -->
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3Dall%3Acausal%20inference%26id_list%3D%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=all:causal inference&amp;id_list=&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/SsRksLzRb0LuVhSmQ+N8WbAs+f8</id>
  <updated>2025-08-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">118331</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.03693v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-05T17:59:56Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-05T17:59:56Z</published>
    <title>PAC Apprenticeship Learning with Bayesian Active Inverse Reinforcement
  Learning</title>
    <summary>  As AI systems become increasingly autonomous, reliably aligning their
decision-making to human preferences is essential. Inverse reinforcement
learning (IRL) offers a promising approach to infer preferences from
demonstrations. These preferences can then be used to produce an apprentice
policy that performs well on the demonstrated task. However, in domains like
autonomous driving or robotics, where errors can have serious consequences, we
need not just good average performance but reliable policies with formal
guarantees -- yet obtaining sufficient human demonstrations for reliability
guarantees can be costly. Active IRL addresses this challenge by strategically
selecting the most informative scenarios for human demonstration. We introduce
PAC-EIG, an information-theoretic acquisition function that directly targets
probably-approximately-correct (PAC) guarantees for the learned policy --
providing the first such theoretical guarantee for active IRL with noisy expert
demonstrations. Our method maximises information gain about the regret of the
apprentice policy, efficiently identifying states requiring further
demonstration. We also present Reward-EIG as an alternative when learning the
reward itself is the primary objective. Focusing on finite state-action spaces,
we prove convergence bounds, illustrate failure modes of prior heuristic
methods, and demonstrate our method's advantages experimentally.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ondrej Bajgar</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Dewi S. W. Gould</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jonathon Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alessandro Abate</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Konstantinos Gatsis</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Michael A. Osborne</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Published at RLC 2025</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.03693v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.03693v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.03684v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-05T17:54:52Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-05T17:54:52Z</published>
    <title>SED Fitting of Globular Clusters in NGC 4874: Masses and Metallicities</title>
    <summary>  In most nearby galaxies, photometry of the integrated light of their globular
clusters (GCs) has been obtained in only two filters, yielding just a single
color index. However, NGC 4874, the brightest central galaxy in the Coma
cluster, now has Hubble Space Telescope (HST) photometry available in ten
filters, giving us a special opportunity to test SED fitting procedures on GCs
in distant galaxies. We fitted 29 of the brightest GCs with a library of SEDs
from E-MILES and calculated the best-fit metallicity and mass of each cluster.
Using the fitted masses and luminosities derived from the reddest magnitudes,
in the flat portion of the GC spectrum, we also calculated inferred
mass-to-light ratios for our sample GCs; these were in the range (M/L) $\simeq
2 - 4$, slightly larger than the average values for Milky Way GCs but within
the conventional range.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Kate Hartman</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>William E. Harris</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jinoo Kim</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">14 pages, 11 figures. Accepted for publication in ApJ</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.03684v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.03684v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.03679v2</id>
    <updated>2025-08-06T12:22:27Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-05T17:50:03Z</published>
    <title>Streaming Generated Gaussian Process Experts for Online Learning and
  Control</title>
    <summary>  Gaussian Processes (GPs), as a nonparametric learning method, offer flexible
modeling capabilities and calibrated uncertainty quantification for function
approximations. Additionally, GPs support online learning by efficiently
incorporating new data with polynomial-time computation, making them
well-suited for safety-critical dynamical systems that require rapid
adaptation. However, the inference and online updates of exact GPs, when
processing streaming data, incur cubic computation time and quadratic storage
memory complexity, limiting their scalability to large datasets in real-time
settings. In this paper, we propose a streaming kernel-induced progressively
generated expert framework of Gaussian processes (SkyGP) that addresses both
computational and memory constraints by maintaining a bounded set of experts,
while inheriting the learning performance guarantees from exact Gaussian
processes. Furthermore, two SkyGP variants are introduced, each tailored to a
specific objective, either maximizing prediction accuracy (SkyGP-Dense) or
improving computational efficiency (SkyGP-Fast). The effectiveness of SkyGP is
validated through extensive benchmarks and real-time control experiments
demonstrating its superior performance compared to state-of-the-art approaches.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Zewen Yang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Dongfa Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xiaobing Dai</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Fengyi Yu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Chi Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Bingkun Huang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hamid Sadeghian</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sami Haddadin</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.03679v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.03679v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.SY" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="eess.SY" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.03675v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-05T17:44:15Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-05T17:44:15Z</published>
    <title>A New Approach to Partial Conjunction Analysis in Neuroimaging</title>
    <summary>  The problem of identifying the brain regions activated through a particular
cognitive task is pivotal in neuroimaging. This problem becomes even more
complex if we have several cognitive tasks or several subjects. In this paper,
we view this problem as a partial conjunction (PC) hypotheses testing problem,
i.e., we are testing whether a specific brain region is activated in at least
$\gamma$ (for some pre-fixed $\gamma$) subjects. We propose the application of
a recent advance in the simultaneous statistical inference literature to
activation localization in neuroimaging. We apply the recently proposed
CoFilter method to neuroimaging data to discover brain regions activated in at
least $\gamma$ subjects. Our proposal has two distinct advantages. First, it
alleviates the conservativeness displayed by the traditional multiple testing
procedures in testing PC hypotheses by eliminating many of the conservative PC
$p$-values. Second, it is especially suitable for several high-dimensional
studies, each of which examines a large number of null hypotheses. We also
compare the performance of our proposal with existing methods for testing PC
hypotheses through extensive simulation studies on neuroimaging data and a real
dataset.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Monitirtha Dey</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Anna Vesely</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Thorsten Dickhaus</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.03675v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.03675v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="stat.ME" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ME" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.AP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.03627v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-05T16:45:48Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-05T16:45:48Z</published>
    <title>Learning Event-recording Automata Passively</title>
    <summary>  This paper presents a state-merging algorithm for learning timed languages
definable by Event-Recording Automata (ERA) using positive and negative samples
in the form of symbolic timed words. Our algorithm, LEAP (Learning
Event-recording Automata Passively), constructs a possibly nondeterministic ERA
from such samples based on merging techniques. We prove that determining
whether two ERA states can be merged while preserving sample consistency is an
NP-complete problem, and address this with a practical SMT-based solution. Our
implementation demonstrates the algorithm's effectiveness through examples. We
also show that every ERA-definable language can be inferred using our algorithm
with a suitable sample.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Anirban Majumdar</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sayan Mukherjee</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jean-François Raskin</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Shorter version of this article has been accepted at ATVA 2025</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.03627v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.03627v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.FL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.FL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.03611v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-05T16:27:10Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-05T16:27:10Z</published>
    <title>Block: Balancing Load in LLM Serving with Context, Knowledge and
  Predictive Scheduling</title>
    <summary>  This paper presents Block, a distributed scheduling framework designed to
optimize load balancing and auto-provisioning across instances in large
language model serving frameworks by leveraging contextual information from
incoming requests. Unlike popular model serving systems that rely on monolithic
and heuristic task schedulers, Block operates as a fully distributed,
stateless, and predictive scheduling system to achieve low overhead,
reliability, and scalability. It leverages the deterministic and predictable
characteristics of LLM inferences, such as host configurations, response
lengths, and hardware performance, to make scheduling decisions based on
accurately predicted metrics. Evaluation on a 12 GPUs cluster shows that Block
significantly outperforms heuristic schedulers, boosting serving capacity by up
to 16.7\% and reducing P99 tail latency by up to 49.5\%. These performance
gains remain consistent across diverse models, workloads and configurations.
Code and data are open-sourced.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Wei Da</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Evangelia Kalyvianaki</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">12 pages, 8 figures excluding appendix</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.03611v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.03611v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.DC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.DC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.03598v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-05T16:06:26Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-05T16:06:26Z</published>
    <title>DyCAF-Net: Dynamic Class-Aware Fusion Network</title>
    <summary>  Recent advancements in object detection rely on modular architectures with
multi-scale fusion and attention mechanisms. However, static fusion heuristics
and class-agnostic attention limit performance in dynamic scenes with
occlusions, clutter, and class imbalance. We introduce Dynamic Class-Aware
Fusion Network (DyCAF-Net) that addresses these challenges through three
innovations: (1) an input-conditioned equilibrium-based neck that iteratively
refines multi-scale features via implicit fixed-point modeling, (2) a dual
dynamic attention mechanism that adaptively recalibrates channel and spatial
responses using input- and class-dependent cues, and (3) class-aware feature
adaptation that modulates features to prioritize discriminative regions for
rare classes. Through comprehensive ablation studies with YOLOv8 and related
architectures, alongside benchmarking against nine state-of-the-art baselines,
DyCAF-Net achieves significant improvements in precision, mAP@50, and mAP@50-95
across 13 diverse benchmarks, including occlusion-heavy and long-tailed
datasets. The framework maintains computational efficiency ($\sim$11.1M
parameters) and competitive inference speeds, while its adaptability to scale
variance, semantic overlaps, and class imbalance positions it as a robust
solution for real-world detection tasks in medical imaging, surveillance, and
autonomous systems.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Md Abrar Jahin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Shahriar Soudeep</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>M. F. Mridha</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Nafiz Fahad</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Md. Jakir Hossen</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Accepted to IEEE DSAA 2025 (10 pages, 5 figures)</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.03598v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.03598v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.03594v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-05T15:59:19Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:59:19Z</published>
    <title>CADD: Context aware disease deviations via restoration of brain images
  using normative conditional diffusion models</title>
    <summary>  Applying machine learning to real-world medical data, e.g. from hospital
archives, has the potential to revolutionize disease detection in brain images.
However, detecting pathology in such heterogeneous cohorts is a difficult
challenge. Normative modeling, a form of unsupervised anomaly detection, offers
a promising approach to studying such cohorts where the ``normal'' behavior is
modeled and can be used at subject level to detect deviations relating to
disease pathology. Diffusion models have emerged as powerful tools for anomaly
detection due to their ability to capture complex data distributions and
generate high-quality images. Their performance relies on image restoration;
differences between the original and restored images highlight potential
abnormalities. However, unlike normative models, these diffusion model
approaches do not incorporate clinical information which provides important
context to guide the disease detection process. Furthermore, standard
approaches often poorly restore healthy regions, resulting in poor
reconstructions and suboptimal detection performance. We present CADD, the
first conditional diffusion model for normative modeling in 3D images. To guide
the healthy restoration process, we propose a novel inference inpainting
strategy which balances anomaly removal with retention of subject-specific
features. Evaluated on three challenging datasets, including clinical scans,
which may have lower contrast, thicker slices, and motion artifacts, CADD
achieves state-of-the-art performance in detecting neurological abnormalities
in heterogeneous cohorts.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ana Lawry Aguila</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ayodeji Ijishakin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Eugenio Iglesias</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tomomi Takenaga</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yukihiro Nomura</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Takeharu Yoshikawa</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Osamu Abe</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Shouhei Hanaoka</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.03594v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.03594v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="eess.IV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="eess.IV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.03589v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-05T15:56:36Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:56:36Z</published>
    <title>VITA: Variational Pretraining of Transformers for Climate-Robust Crop
  Yield Forecasting</title>
    <summary>  Accurate crop yield forecasting is essential for global food security.
However, current AI models systematically underperform when yields deviate from
historical trends. This issue arises from key data challenges, including a
major asymmetry between rich pretraining weather datasets and the limited data
available for fine-tuning. We introduce VITA (Variational Inference Transformer
for Asymmetric data), a variational pretraining framework that addresses this
asymmetry. Instead of relying on input reconstruction, VITA uses detailed
weather variables as proxy targets during pretraining and learns to predict
rich atmospheric states through self-supervised feature masking. This allows
the model to be fine-tuned using only basic weather statistics during
deployment. Applied to 763 counties in the U.S. Corn Belt, VITA achieves
state-of-the-art performance in predicting corn and soybean yields across all
evaluation scenarios. While it consistently delivers superior performance under
normal conditions, its advantages are particularly pronounced during extreme
weather years, with statistically significant improvements (paired t-test, $p
\approx 0.01$). Importantly, VITA outperforms prior frameworks like GNN-RNN
using less data, making it more practical for real-world use--particularly in
data-scarce regions. This work highlights how domain-aware AI design can
overcome data limitations and support resilient agricultural forecasting in a
changing climate.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Adib Hasan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mardavij Roozbehani</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Munther Dahleh</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.03589v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.03589v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.03578v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-05T15:46:05Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-05T15:46:05Z</published>
    <title>RadProPoser: A Framework for Human Pose Estimation with Uncertainty
  Quantification from Raw Radar Data</title>
    <summary>  Radar-based human pose estimation (HPE) provides a privacy-preserving,
illumination-invariant sensing modality but is challenged by noisy,
multipath-affected measurements. We introduce RadProPoser, a probabilistic
encoder-decoder architecture that processes complex-valued radar tensors from a
compact 3-transmitter, 4-receiver MIMO radar. By incorporating variational
inference into keypoint regression, RadProPoser jointly predicts 26
three-dimensional joint locations alongside heteroscedastic aleatoric
uncertainties and can be recalibrated to predict total uncertainty. We explore
different probabilistic formulations using both Gaussian and Laplace
distributions for latent priors and likelihoods. On our newly released dataset
with optical motion-capture ground truth, RadProPoser achieves an overall mean
per-joint position error (MPJPE) of 6.425 cm, with 5.678 cm at the 45 degree
aspect angle. The learned uncertainties exhibit strong alignment with actual
pose errors and can be calibrated to produce reliable prediction intervals,
with our best configuration achieving an expected calibration error of 0.021.
As an additional demonstration, sampling from these latent distributions
enables effective data augmentation for downstream activity classification,
resulting in an F1 score of 0.870. To our knowledge, this is the first
end-to-end radar tensor-based HPE system to explicitly model and quantify
per-joint uncertainty from raw radar tensor data, establishing a foundation for
explainable and reliable human motion analysis in radar applications.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Jonas Leo Mueller</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lukas Engel</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Eva Dorschky</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Daniel Krauss</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ingrid Ullmann</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Martin Vossiek</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Bjoern M. Eskofier</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.03578v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.03578v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
