<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Last updated: 2026-01-16T01:02:53Z -->
<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://arxiv.org/api/p6EyKyP4fMY/66n9Ev8E79F7KlI</id>
  <title>arXiv Query: search_query=all:causal OR all:inference&amp;id_list=&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <updated>2026-01-16T01:02:53Z</updated>
  <link href="https://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query=all:causal+OR+all:inference&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10&amp;id_list=" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage>10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <opensearch:totalResults>130898</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex>0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2601.09708v1</id>
    <title>Fast-ThinkAct: Efficient Vision-Language-Action Reasoning via Verbalizable Latent Planning</title>
    <updated>2026-01-14T18:59:59Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.09708v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2601.09708v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Vision-Language-Action (VLA) tasks require reasoning over complex visual scenes and executing adaptive actions in dynamic environments. While recent studies on reasoning VLAs show that explicit chain-of-thought (CoT) can improve generalization, they suffer from high inference latency due to lengthy reasoning traces. We propose Fast-ThinkAct, an efficient reasoning framework that achieves compact yet performant planning through verbalizable latent reasoning. Fast-ThinkAct learns to reason efficiently with latent CoTs by distilling from a teacher, driven by a preference-guided objective to align manipulation trajectories that transfers both linguistic and visual planning capabilities for embodied control. This enables reasoning-enhanced policy learning that effectively connects compact reasoning to action execution. Extensive experiments across diverse embodied manipulation and reasoning benchmarks demonstrate that Fast-ThinkAct achieves strong performance with up to 89.3\% reduced inference latency over state-of-the-art reasoning VLAs, while maintaining effective long-horizon planning, few-shot adaptation, and failure recovery.</summary>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-01-14T18:59:59Z</published>
    <arxiv:comment>Project page: https://jasper0314-huang.github.io/fast-thinkact/</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="cs.CV"/>
    <author>
      <name>Chi-Pin Huang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yunze Man</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zhiding Yu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Min-Hung Chen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jan Kautz</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yu-Chiang Frank Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Fu-En Yang</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2601.09703v1</id>
    <title>ShortCoder: Knowledge-Augmented Syntax Optimization for Token-Efficient Code Generation</title>
    <updated>2026-01-14T18:57:31Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.09703v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2601.09703v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Code generation tasks aim to automate the conversion of user requirements into executable code, significantly reducing manual development efforts and enhancing software productivity. The emergence of large language models (LLMs) has significantly advanced code generation, though their efficiency is still impacted by certain inherent architectural constraints. Each token generation necessitates a complete inference pass, requiring persistent retention of contextual information in memory and escalating resource consumption. While existing research prioritizes inference-phase optimizations such as prompt compression and model quantization, the generation phase remains underexplored. To tackle these challenges, we propose a knowledge-infused framework named ShortCoder, which optimizes code generation efficiency while preserving semantic equivalence and readability. In particular, we introduce: (1) ten syntax-level simplification rules for Python, derived from AST-preserving transformations, achieving 18.1% token reduction without functional compromise; (2) a hybrid data synthesis pipeline integrating rule-based rewriting with LLM-guided refinement, producing ShorterCodeBench, a corpus of validated tuples of original code and simplified code with semantic consistency; (3) a fine-tuning strategy that injects conciseness awareness into the base LLMs. Extensive experimental results demonstrate that ShortCoder consistently outperforms state-of-the-art methods on HumanEval, achieving an improvement of 18.1%-37.8% in generation efficiency over previous methods while ensuring the performance of code generation.</summary>
    <category term="cs.SE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-01-14T18:57:31Z</published>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="cs.SE"/>
    <author>
      <name>Sicong Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yanxian Huang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mingwei Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jiachi Chen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ensheng Shi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yuchi Ma</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hongyu Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yin Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yanlin Wang</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2601.09691v1</id>
    <title>Detection of Oscillations in a Type I X-Ray Burst of 4U 0614+091 with SVOM/ECLAIRs</title>
    <updated>2026-01-14T18:43:28Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.09691v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2601.09691v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>On 2025 January 10, a thermonuclear (Type I) X-ray burst from the neutron star low-mass X-ray binary \textit{4U~0614+091} was detected with the ECLAIRs instrument on board the \textit{SVOM} mission. We present here a time-resolved spectroscopic analysis of the burst, along with the detection of burst oscillations within a 51-second interval during the decay phase. The oscillation frequency is measured to be $ν= 413.674 \pm 0.002\,\mathrm{Hz}$, consistent with previous reports. However, we detect a significant downward frequency drift over the burst duration, characterized by $\dotν = (-4.7 \pm 0.3) \times 10^{-3}\,\mathrm{Hz\,s^{-1}}$. This frequency evolution is atypical compared to those observed in similar burst oscillation sources. We tentatively attribute the observed drift to a Doppler shift induced by orbital motion. Under this interpretation, the inferred orbital period must be shorter than 20 minutes, placing \textit{4U~0614+091} among the most compact known low-mass X-ray binaries.</summary>
    <category term="astro-ph.HE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-01-14T18:43:28Z</published>
    <arxiv:comment>Accepted for publication in APJL</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="astro-ph.HE"/>
    <author>
      <name>Sébastien Le Stum</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Floriane Cangemi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alexis Coleiro</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sébastien Guillot</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jérôme Chenevez</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Philippe Bacon</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Nicolas Bellemont</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Laurent Bouchet</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tristan Bouchet</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Cécile Cavet</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Bertrand Cordier</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Antoine Foisseau</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Olivier Godet</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Andrea Goldwurm</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xu-Hui Han</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Cyril Lachaud</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zhaosheng Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hua-Li Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yu-Lei Qiu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jérôme Rodriguez</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Wen-Jun Tan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>L. Tao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lauryne Verwaerde</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Chen-Wei Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jing Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jianyan Wei</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Chao Wu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Wen-Jin Xie</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Li-Ping Xin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Shaolin Xiong</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Shuang-Nan Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>S. J. Zheng</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:doi>10.3847/2041-8213/ae3174</arxiv:doi>
    <link rel="related" href="https://doi.org/10.3847/2041-8213/ae3174" title="doi"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2601.09678v1</id>
    <title>The impact of waveform systematics and Gaussian noise on the interpretation of GW231123</title>
    <updated>2026-01-14T18:22:32Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.09678v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2601.09678v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>GW231123 is an exceptional gravitational-wave event consistent with the merger of two massive, highly-spinning black holes. Reliable inference of the source properties is crucial for accurate interpretation of its astrophysical implications. However, characterization of GW231123 is challenging: only few signal cycles are observed and different signal models result in systematically different parameters. We investigate whether the interpretation of GW231123 is robust against model systematics and Gaussian detector noise. We show that the model systematics observed in GW231123 can be reproduced for a simulated signal based on the numerical-relativity surrogate model NRSur7dq4. Simulating data using the maximum-likelihood NRSur7dq4 waveform for GW231123 and no noise realization, we closely recover the systematics observed for the real signal. We then explore how the headline properties of GW231123 are impacted by Gaussian detector noise. Using the NRSur7dq4 maximum-likelihood waveform and different noise realizations, we consistently find support for large masses, high spin magnitudes (median $χ_1\geq 0.7$), and high spin precession (median $χ_\mathrm{p}\geq 0.68$). The spin in the direction of the angular momentum ($χ_\mathrm{eff}$) fluctuates more. Finally, again comparing to simulated signals, we show that any differences in the GW231123 inference based on each separate detector are not statistically significant. These results show that the properties of GW231123, and most importantly the high mass and high spin magnitudes inferred by NRSur7dq4, are robust.</summary>
    <category term="gr-qc" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-01-14T18:22:32Z</published>
    <arxiv:comment>18 pages, 11 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="gr-qc"/>
    <author>
      <name>Sophie Bini</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Krzysztof Król</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Katerina Chatziioannou</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Maximiliano Isi</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2601.09667v1</id>
    <title>Collaborative Multi-Agent Test-Time Reinforcement Learning for Reasoning</title>
    <updated>2026-01-14T17:57:43Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.09667v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2601.09667v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Multi-agent systems have evolved into practical LLM-driven collaborators for many applications, gaining robustness from diversity and cross-checking. However, multi-agent RL (MARL) training is resource-intensive and unstable: co-adapting teammates induce non-stationarity, and rewards are often sparse and high-variance. Therefore, we introduce \textbf{Multi-Agent Test-Time Reinforcement Learning (MATTRL)}, a framework that injects structured textual experience into multi-agent deliberation at inference time. MATTRL forms a multi-expert team of specialists for multi-turn discussions, retrieves and integrates test-time experiences, and reaches consensus for final decision-making. We also study credit assignment for constructing a turn-level experience pool, then reinjecting it into the dialogue. Across challenging benchmarks in medicine, math, and education, MATTRL improves accuracy by an average of 3.67\% over a multi-agent baseline, and by 8.67\% over comparable single-agent baselines. Ablation studies examine different credit-assignment schemes and provide a detailed comparison of how they affect training outcomes. MATTRL offers a stable, effective and efficient path to distribution-shift-robust multi-agent reasoning without tuning.</summary>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-01-14T17:57:43Z</published>
    <arxiv:comment>Work in Progress</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="cs.AI"/>
    <author>
      <name>Zhiyuan Hu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yunhai Hu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Juncheng Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Shuyue Stella Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yucheng Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zhen Xu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>See-Kiong Ng</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Anh Tuan Luu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xinxing Xu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Bryan Hooi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Cynthia Breazeal</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hae Won Park</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2601.09660v1</id>
    <title>Constitutive parameter inference using physics-based data-driven modeling in full volume datasets of intact and torn rotator cuff tendons</title>
    <updated>2026-01-14T17:51:44Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.09660v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2601.09660v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>In this work, we characterized the material properties of an animal model of the rotator cuff tendon using full volume datasets of both its intact and injured states by capturing internal strain behavior throughout the tendon. Our experimental setup, involving tension along the fiber direction, activated volumetric, tensile, and shear mechanisms due to the tendon's complex geometry. We implemented an approach to model inference that we refer to as variational system identification (VSI) to solve the weak form of the stress equilibrium equation using these full volume displacements. Three constitutive models were used for parameter inference: a neo-Hookean model, a modified Holzapfel-Gasser-Ogden (HGO) model with higher-order terms in the first and second invariants, and a reduced polynomial model consisting of terms based on the first, second, and fiber-related invariants. Inferred parameters were further refined using an adjoint-based partial differential equation (PDE)-constrained optimization framework. Our results show that the modified HGO model captures the tendon's deformation mechanisms with reasonable accuracy, while the neo-Hookean model fails to reproduce key internal features, particularly the shear behavior in the injured tendon. Surprisingly, the simplified polynomial model performed comparably to the modified HGO formulation using only three terms. These findings suggest that while current constitutive models do not fully replicate the complex internal mechanics of the tendon, they are capable of capturing key trends in both intact and damaged tissue, using a homogeneous modeling approach. Continued model development is needed to bridge this gap and enable clinical-grade, predictive simulations of tendon injury and repair.</summary>
    <category term="physics.bio-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="q-bio.TO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-01-14T17:51:44Z</published>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="physics.bio-ph"/>
    <author>
      <name>Carla Nathaly Villacís Núñez</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Siddhartha Srivastava</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ulrich Scheven</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Asheesh Bedi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Krishna Garikipati</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ellen M. Arruda</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2601.09658v1</id>
    <title>Image2Garment: Simulation-ready Garment Generation from a Single Image</title>
    <updated>2026-01-14T17:47:33Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.09658v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2601.09658v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Estimating physically accurate, simulation-ready garments from a single image is challenging due to the absence of image-to-physics datasets and the ill-posed nature of this problem. Prior methods either require multi-view capture and expensive differentiable simulation or predict only garment geometry without the material properties required for realistic simulation. We propose a feed-forward framework that sidesteps these limitations by first fine-tuning a vision-language model to infer material composition and fabric attributes from real images, and then training a lightweight predictor that maps these attributes to the corresponding physical fabric parameters using a small dataset of material-physics measurements. Our approach introduces two new datasets (FTAG and T2P) and delivers simulation-ready garments from a single image without iterative optimization. Experiments show that our estimator achieves superior accuracy in material composition estimation and fabric attribute prediction, and by passing them through our physics parameter estimator, we further achieve higher-fidelity simulations compared to state-of-the-art image-to-garment methods.</summary>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-01-14T17:47:33Z</published>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="cs.CV"/>
    <author>
      <name>Selim Emir Can</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jan Ackermann</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kiyohiro Nakayama</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ruofan Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tong Wu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yang Zheng</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hugo Bertiche</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Menglei Chai</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Thabo Beeler</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Gordon Wetzstein</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2601.09655v1</id>
    <title>A Closed-Form Surrogate for the Equivalent Diameter of the Kerr Shadow</title>
    <updated>2026-01-14T17:44:54Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.09655v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2601.09655v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>We present a closed-form surrogate for the equivalent diameter of the Kerr black-hole shadow, defined as the diameter of the circle with the same area as the shadow's critical curve. The construction enforces the exact face-on (polar) limit by explicitly separating an analytically computed polar contribution based on the spherical photon-orbit branch where the horizontal impact parameter vanishes. The remaining inclination dependence is captured by a compact 15-parameter polynomial placed inside an exponential correction. The coefficients are determined by ordinary least squares on a deterministic reference grid generated from the Kerr critical-curve area. Over the practical domain of dimensionless spin from 0 to 0.998 and inclination from just above 0 degrees up to 90 degrees (with the exactly polar point treated analytically), the surrogate achieves sub-percent accuracy. On the training grid the median absolute percent error is 0.0105 percent with a worst case of 0.782 percent, and on a denser out-of-sample validation set (including inclinations down to 0.5 degrees) the median, 95th-percentile, and worst-case errors are 0.023 percent, 0.471 percent, and 1.64 percent, respectively. The resulting expression provides fast evaluations of the shadow size without numerical ray tracing, making it convenient for repeated calls in parameter inference and rapid model comparisons.</summary>
    <category term="gr-qc" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-01-14T17:44:54Z</published>
    <arxiv:comment>8 pages, 1 figure</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="gr-qc"/>
    <author>
      <name>Arseny Pantsialei</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2601.09644v1</id>
    <title>A New Constraint on the Optical Depth from the Reionization History Independent of CMB Large-Scale E-Mode Polarization</title>
    <updated>2026-01-14T17:28:14Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.09644v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2601.09644v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Recent studies report a mild discrepancy between baryon acoustic oscillation (BAO) and cosmic microwave background (CMB) measurements within the $Λ$CDM framework. This discrepancy could be explained if the optical depth $τ$ inferred from the CMB large-scale E-mode polarization is underestimated, which may be biased by foreground-subtraction or instrumental systematics. In this work, we present a determination of $τ$ independent of the large-scale E-mode polarization, using the latest measurements of the redshift evolution of the neutral hydrogen fraction $x_\mathrm{HI}(z)$, which is constrained by Lyman-$α$ forest and damping-wing absorption measurements at $z\sim5$-$14$, based on ground-based optical and JWST observations. Combining $x_\mathrm{HI}(z)$ with the Planck CMB power spectra excluding the large-scale E-mode polarization, we obtain $τ=0.0552^{+0.0019}_{-0.0026}$, a stringent constraint consistent with the previous CMB results including the large-scale E-mode. We also evaluate a potential systematic error in our method associated with absorption modeling, obtaining $τ=0.0552^{+0.0075}_{-0.0049}$. Using this constraint on $τ$, we resolve the degeneracy in the $τ$-$Ω_m$ plane and find a $2.4σ$ tension with the DESI DR2 BAO results, thereby confirming the claimed mild discrepancy suggestive of physics beyond $Λ$CDM. Finally, we derive an upper limit on the sum of neutrino masses, $Σm_ν&lt;0.0550\,(0.0717)$ eV at the 95% (99%) confidence level. This limit favors the normal mass ordering and, when combined with the lower limits from neutrino oscillation experiments, yields a further constraint, $Σm_ν=0.0594_{-0.0007}^{+0.0113}$ eV. However, the cosmological upper limit and the oscillation-based lower limit show a mild $2.2σ$ tension, providing an independent indication of possible physics beyond $Λ$CDM.</summary>
    <category term="astro-ph.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-01-14T17:28:14Z</published>
    <arxiv:comment>19 pages, 9 figures, submitted to ApJ</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="astro-ph.CO"/>
    <author>
      <name>Yuta Kageura</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Masami Ouchi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Fumihiro Naokawa</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hiroya Umeda</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Akinori Matsumoto</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yuichi Harikane</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Minami Nakane</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tran Thi Thai</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2601.09634v1</id>
    <title>Human Ancestries Simulation and Inference: a Review of Ancestral Recombination Graph Samplers</title>
    <updated>2026-01-14T17:09:42Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.09634v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2601.09634v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>There is little debate about the importance of the ancestral recombination graph in population genetics. An important theoretical tool, the main obstacle to its widespread usage is the computational cost required to match the ever-increasing scale of the data being analyzed. Many of these difficulties have been overcome in the past two decades, which have consequently seen the development of increasingly sophisticated ARG simulation and inference software. Nonetheless, challenges remain, especially in the area of ancestry inference. This paper is a comprehensive review of ARG samplers that have emerged in the past three decades to meet the need for scalable and flexible ancestry simulation and inference solutions. It specifically focuses on their performance, usability, and the biological realism of the underlying algorithm, and aims primarily to provide a technical overview of the field for researchers seeking to write their own coalescent-with-recombination sampler. As a complement to this article, we have compiled links to software, source code and documentation and made them available at https://www.patrickfournier.ca/arg-samplers-review/graph.</summary>
    <category term="q-bio.PE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-01-14T17:09:42Z</published>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="q-bio.PE"/>
    <author>
      <name>Patrick Fournier</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Fabrice Larribe</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
