<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Last updated: 2026-01-06T01:01:56Z -->
<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://arxiv.org/api/p6EyKyP4fMY/66n9Ev8E79F7KlI</id>
  <title>arXiv Query: search_query=all:causal OR all:inference&amp;id_list=&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <updated>2026-01-06T01:01:56Z</updated>
  <link href="https://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query=all:causal+OR+all:inference&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10&amp;id_list=" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage>10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <opensearch:totalResults>129953</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex>0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2601.00795v1</id>
    <title>XRISM finds the Changing-Look AGN NGC 1365 in an extended low state: A dense, highly ionized outflow obscures the central source</title>
    <updated>2026-01-02T18:59:21Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.00795v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2601.00795v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>We present the first XRISM/Resolve observations of the active galactic nucleus, NGC 1365, obtained in 2024 February and July. NGC 1365 is known for rapid transitions between Compton-thick and Compton-thin states, along with strong absorption from a highly ionized wind. During our observations, the source is found in a persistent low-flux state, characterized by a decrease in hard-X-ray luminosity and significant line-of-sight obscuration. In this state, XRISM/Resolve reveals clear Fe\,\textsc{xxv} and Fe\,\textsc{xxvi} absorption lines together with, for the first time in this source, corresponding emission lines. These features may arise either from reemission from a photoionized wind (P Cygni profile) or from collisionally ionized gas associated with outflow-driven shocks in the interstellar medium. We estimate the wind launch radius to be approximately $10^{16}~\mathrm{cm}$ ($\sim 10^4 R_{\mathrm{g}}$), consistent with the location of the X-ray broad-line region. We also resolve a broadened Fe K$α$ line by $σ\sim 1300$ km s$^{-1}$ placing it at similar scales to the wind, consistent with radii inferred from disk-broadening models and the variability of the Fe K$α$ broad line. The similarity of the Fe K$α$ profile to the H$β$ wing and broad Pa$α$ width indicates that the X-ray-emitting region is likely cospatial with the optical/IR broad-line region and originates from the same gas.</summary>
    <category term="astro-ph.HE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-01-02T18:59:21Z</published>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="astro-ph.HE"/>
    <author>
      <name>Fatima Zaidouni</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Erin Kara</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Peter Kosec</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ehud Behar</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Mushotzky</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Michael Koss</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Anna Juráňová</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Elias Kammoun</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Laura W. Brenneman</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Joheen Chakraborty</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ken Ebisawa</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Megan E. Eckart</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew C. Fabian</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yasushi Fukazawa</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Javier A. García</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Liyi Gu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Megan Masterson</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Shoji Ogawa</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Takashi Okajima</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Stéphane Paltani</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Daniele Rogantini</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yuichi Terashima</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Brian J. Williams</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Satoshi Yamada</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:doi>10.3847/2041-8213/ae307d</arxiv:doi>
    <link rel="related" href="https://doi.org/10.3847/2041-8213/ae307d" title="doi"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2601.00776v1</id>
    <title>TWICE: Tree-based Wage Inference with Clustering and Estimation</title>
    <updated>2026-01-02T18:15:27Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.00776v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2601.00776v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>How much do worker skills, firm pay policies, and their interaction contribute to wage inequality? Standard approaches rely on latent fixed effects identified through worker mobility, but sparse networks inflate variance estimates, additivity assumptions rule out complementarities, and the resulting decompositions lack interpretability. We propose TWICE (Tree-based Wage Inference with Clustering and Estimation), a framework that models the conditional wage function directly from observables using gradient-boosted trees, replacing latent effects with interpretable, observable-anchored partitions. This trades off the ability to capture idiosyncratic unobservables for robustness to sampling noise and out-of-sample portability. Applied to Portuguese administrative data, TWICE outperforms linear benchmarks out of sample and reveals that sorting and non-additive interactions explain substantially more wage dispersion than implied by standard AKM estimates.</summary>
    <category term="econ.GN" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-01-02T18:15:27Z</published>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="econ.GN"/>
    <author>
      <name>Aslan Bakirov</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Francesco Del Prato</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Paolo Zacchia</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2601.00767v1</id>
    <title>Dynamical Dark Energy Imprints in the Lyman-Alpha Forest</title>
    <updated>2026-01-02T17:56:46Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.00767v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2601.00767v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>The nature of dark energy (DE) remains elusive, even though it constitutes the dominant energy-density component of the Universe and drives the late-time acceleration of cosmic expansion. By combining measurements of the expansion history from baryon acoustic oscillations, supernova surveys, and cosmic microwave background data, the Dark Energy Spectroscopic Instrument (DESI) Collaboration has inferred that the DE equation of state may evolve over time. The profound implications of a time-variable, ``dynamical" DE (DDE) that departs from a cosmological constant motivate the need for independent observational tests. In this work, we use cosmological hydrodynamical simulations of structure formation to investigate how DDE affects the properties of the Lyman-Alpha ``forest'' of absorption features produced by neutral hydrogen in the cosmic web. We find that DDE models consistent with the DESI constraints induce a spectral tilt in the forest transmitted flux power spectrum, imprinting a scale- and redshift-dependent signature relative to standard Lambda-CDM cosmologies. These models also yield higher intergalactic medium temperatures and reduced Lyman-Alpha opacity compared to Lambda-CDM. We discuss the observational implications of these trends as potential avenues for independent confirmation of DDE.</summary>
    <category term="astro-ph.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.IM" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-01-02T17:56:46Z</published>
    <arxiv:comment>23 pages, 13 figures, submitted to Physical Review D</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="astro-ph.CO"/>
    <author>
      <name>Diego Garza</name>
      <arxiv:affiliation>University of California, Santa Cruz</arxiv:affiliation>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Brant Robertson</name>
      <arxiv:affiliation>University of California, Santa Cruz</arxiv:affiliation>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Piero Madau</name>
      <arxiv:affiliation>University of California, Santa Cruz</arxiv:affiliation>
      <arxiv:affiliation>Università degli Studi di Milano-Bicocca</arxiv:affiliation>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Nick Gnedin</name>
      <arxiv:affiliation>University of Chicago</arxiv:affiliation>
      <arxiv:affiliation>Fermi national Accelerator Laboratory</arxiv:affiliation>
      <arxiv:affiliation>Kavli Institute for Cosmological Physics</arxiv:affiliation>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Matthew W. Abbruzo</name>
      <arxiv:affiliation>University of Pittsburgh</arxiv:affiliation>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Evan Schneider</name>
      <arxiv:affiliation>University of Pittsburgh</arxiv:affiliation>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Reuben D. Budiardja</name>
      <arxiv:affiliation>Oak Ridge National Laboratory</arxiv:affiliation>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>James B. White</name>
      <arxiv:affiliation>Oak Ridge National Laboratory</arxiv:affiliation>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Robert Caddy</name>
      <arxiv:affiliation>Princeton University</arxiv:affiliation>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Bruno Villasenor</name>
      <arxiv:affiliation>Advanced Micro Devices</arxiv:affiliation>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2601.00760v1</id>
    <title>Gradient-free ensemble transform methods for generalized Bayesian inference in generative models</title>
    <updated>2026-01-02T17:34:43Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.00760v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2601.00760v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Bayesian inference in complex generative models is often obstructed by the absence of tractable likelihoods and the infeasibility of computing gradients of high-dimensional simulators. Existing likelihood-free methods for generalized Bayesian inference typically rely on gradient-based optimization or reparameterization, which can be computationally expensive and often inapplicable to black-box simulators. To overcome these limitations, we introduce a gradient-free ensemble transform Langevin dynamics method for generalized Bayesian inference using the maximum mean discrepancy. By relying on ensemble-based covariance structures rather than simulator derivatives, the proposed method enables robust posterior approximation without requiring access to gradients of the forward model, making it applicable to a broader class of likelihood-free models. The method is affine invariant, computationally efficient, and robust to model misspecification. Through numerical experiments on well-specified chaotic dynamical systems, and misspecified generative models with contaminated data, we demonstrate that the proposed method achieves comparable or improved accuracy relative to existing gradient-based methods, while substantially reducing computational cost.</summary>
    <category term="stat.AP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-01-02T17:34:43Z</published>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="stat.AP"/>
    <author>
      <name>Diksha Bhandari</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sebastian Reich</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2601.00748v1</id>
    <title>A Machine Learning Framework for Off Ball Defensive Role and Performance Evaluation in Football</title>
    <updated>2026-01-02T17:10:36Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.00748v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2601.00748v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Evaluating off-ball defensive performance in football is challenging, as traditional metrics do not capture the nuanced coordinated movements that limit opponent action selection and success probabilities. Although widely used possession value models excel at appraising on-ball actions, their application to defense remains limited. Existing counterfactual methods, such as ghosting models, help extend these analyses but often rely on simulating "average" behavior that lacks tactical context. To address this, we introduce a covariate-dependent Hidden Markov Model (CDHMM) tailored to corner kicks, a highly structured aspect of football games. Our label-free model infers time-resolved man-marking and zonal assignments directly from player tracking data. We leverage these assignments to propose a novel framework for defensive credit attribution and a role-conditioned ghosting method for counterfactual analysis of off-ball defensive performance. We show how these contributions provide a interpretable evaluation of defensive contributions against context-aware baselines.</summary>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-01-02T17:10:36Z</published>
    <arxiv:comment>40 pages, 16 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="cs.LG"/>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Groom</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Shuo Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Francisco Belo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Axl Rice</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Liam Anderson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2601.00739v1</id>
    <title>Continuous time asymptotic representations for adaptive experiments</title>
    <updated>2026-01-02T16:40:42Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.00739v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2601.00739v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>This article develops a continuous-time asymptotic framework for analyzing adaptive experiments -- settings in which data collection and treatment assignment evolve dynamically in response to incoming information. A key challenge in analyzing fully adaptive experiments, where the assignment policy is updated after each observation, is that the sequence of policy rules often lack a well-defined asymptotic limit. To address this, we focus instead on the empirical allocation process, which captures the fraction of observations assigned to each treatment over time. We show that, under general conditions, any adaptive experiment and its associated empirical allocation process can be approximated by a limit experiment defined by Gaussian diffusions with unknown drifts and a corresponding continuous-time allocation process. This limit representation facilitates the analysis of optimal decision rules by reducing the dimensionality of the state-space and leveraging the tractability of Gaussian diffusions. We apply the framework to derive optimal estimators, analyze in-sample regret for adaptive experiments, and construct e-processes for anytime-valid inference. Notably, we introduce the first definition of any-time and any-experiment valid inference for multi-treatment settings.</summary>
    <category term="econ.EM" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-01-02T16:40:42Z</published>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="econ.EM"/>
    <author>
      <name>Karun Adusumilli</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2601.00722v1</id>
    <title>Qubits and Vacuum Amplitudes</title>
    <updated>2026-01-02T15:34:42Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.00722v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2601.00722v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>High-energy colliders, such as the Large Hadron Collider (LHC) at CERN, are genuine quantum machines, so, in line with Richard Feynman's original motivation for Quantum Computing, the scattering processes that take place there are natural candidates to be simulated on a quantum system. Potential applications range from quantum machine learning methods for collider data analysis, to faster and more precise evaluations of intricate multiloop Feynman diagrams, more efficient jet clustering, improved simulations of parton showers, and many other tasks. In this work, the focus will be on two specific applications: first, the identification of the causal structure of multiloop vacuum amplitudes, a key ingredient of the Loop-Tree Duality and an area with deep connections to graph theory; and second, the integration and sampling of high-dimensional functions. The latter constitutes a first step toward the realization of a fully fledged quantum event generator operating at high perturbative orders.</summary>
    <category term="hep-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="hep-ex" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-01-02T15:34:42Z</published>
    <arxiv:comment>Presented at Matter To The Deepest Recent Developments In Physics Of Fundamental Interactions XLVI International Conference of Theoretical Physics, 14-19 September 2025, Katowice, Poland</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="hep-ph"/>
    <author>
      <name>Germán Rodrigo</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2601.00696v1</id>
    <title>Bayesian Inverse Games with High-Dimensional Multi-Modal Observations</title>
    <updated>2026-01-02T14:23:38Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.00696v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2601.00696v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Many multi-agent interaction scenarios can be naturally modeled as noncooperative games, where each agent's decisions depend on others' future actions. However, deploying game-theoretic planners for autonomous decision-making requires a specification of all agents' objectives. To circumvent this practical difficulty, recent work develops maximum likelihood techniques for solving inverse games that can identify unknown agent objectives from interaction data. Unfortunately, these methods only infer point estimates and do not quantify estimator uncertainty; correspondingly, downstream planning decisions can overconfidently commit to unsafe actions. We present an approximate Bayesian inference approach for solving the inverse game problem, which can incorporate observation data from multiple modalities and be used to generate samples from the Bayesian posterior over the hidden agent objectives given limited sensor observations in real time. Concretely, the proposed Bayesian inverse game framework trains a structured variational autoencoder with an embedded differentiable Nash game solver on interaction datasets and does not require labels of agents' true objectives. Extensive experiments show that our framework successfully learns prior and posterior distributions, improves inference quality over maximum likelihood estimation-based inverse game approaches, and enables safer downstream decision-making without sacrificing efficiency. When trajectory information is uninformative or unavailable, multimodal inference further reduces uncertainty by exploiting additional observation modalities.</summary>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.GT" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-01-02T14:23:38Z</published>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="cs.LG"/>
    <author>
      <name>Yash Jain</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xinjie Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lasse Peters</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>David Fridovich-Keil</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ufuk Topcu</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2601.00694v1</id>
    <title>A Vision-and-Knowledge Enhanced Large Language Model for Generalizable Pedestrian Crossing Behavior Inference</title>
    <updated>2026-01-02T14:13:28Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.00694v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2601.00694v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Existing paradigms for inferring pedestrian crossing behavior, ranging from statistical models to supervised learning methods, demonstrate limited generalizability and perform inadequately on new sites. Recent advances in Large Language Models (LLMs) offer a shift from numerical pattern fitting to semantic, context-aware behavioral reasoning, yet existing LLM applications lack domain-specific adaptation and visual context. This study introduces Pedestrian Crossing LLM (PedX-LLM), a vision-and-knowledge enhanced framework designed to transform pedestrian crossing inference from site-specific pattern recognition to generalizable behavioral reasoning. By integrating LLaVA-extracted visual features with textual data and transportation domain knowledge, PedX-LLM fine-tunes a LLaMA-2-7B foundation model via Low-Rank Adaptation (LoRA) to infer crossing decisions. PedX-LLM achieves 82.0% balanced accuracy, outperforming the best statistical and supervised learning methods. Results demonstrate that the vision-augmented module contributes a 2.9% performance gain by capturing the built environment and integrating domain knowledge yields an additional 4.1% improvement. To evaluate generalizability across unseen environments, cross-site validation was conducted using site-based partitioning. The zero-shot PedX-LLM configuration achieves 66.9% balanced accuracy on five unseen test sites, outperforming the baseline data-driven methods by at least 18 percentage points. Incorporating just five validation examples via few-shot learning to PedX-LLM further elevates the balanced accuracy to 72.2%. PedX-LLM demonstrates strong generalizability to unseen scenarios, confirming that vision-and-knowledge-enhanced reasoning enables the model to mimic human-like decision logic and overcome the limitations of purely data-driven methods.</summary>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-01-02T14:13:28Z</published>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="cs.AI"/>
    <author>
      <name>Qingwen Pu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kun Xie</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hong Yang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Guocong Zhai</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2601.00680v1</id>
    <title>Sigmoid Head for Quality Estimation under Language Ambiguity</title>
    <updated>2026-01-02T13:12:28Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.00680v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2601.00680v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Language model (LM) probability is not a reliable quality estimator, as natural language is ambiguous. When multiple output options are valid, the model's probability distribution is spread across them, which can misleadingly indicate low output quality. This issue is caused by two reasons: (1) LMs' final output activation is softmax, which does not allow multiple correct options to receive high probabilities simultaneuously and (2) LMs' training data is single, one-hot encoded references, indicating that there is only one correct option at each output step. We propose training a module for Quality Estimation on top of pre-trained LMs to address these limitations. The module, called Sigmoid Head, is an extra unembedding head with sigmoid activation to tackle the first limitation. To tackle the second limitation, during the negative sampling process to train the Sigmoid Head, we use a heuristic to avoid selecting potentially alternative correct tokens. Our Sigmoid Head is computationally efficient during training and inference. The probability from Sigmoid Head is notably better quality signal compared to the original softmax head. As the Sigmoid Head does not rely on human-annotated quality data, it is more robust to out-of-domain settings compared to supervised QE.</summary>
    <category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-01-02T13:12:28Z</published>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="cs.CL"/>
    <author>
      <name>Tu Anh Dinh</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jan Niehues</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
