<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Last updated: 2025-03-20T00:51:25Z -->
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3Dall%3Acausal%20inference%26id_list%3D%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=all:causal inference&amp;id_list=&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/SsRksLzRb0LuVhSmQ+N8WbAs+f8</id>
  <updated>2025-03-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">109073</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14492v1</id>
    <updated>2025-03-18T17:57:54Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-18T17:57:54Z</published>
    <title>Cosmos-Transfer1: Conditional World Generation with Adaptive Multimodal
  Control</title>
    <summary>  We introduce Cosmos-Transfer, a conditional world generation model that can
generate world simulations based on multiple spatial control inputs of various
modalities such as segmentation, depth, and edge. In the design, the spatial
conditional scheme is adaptive and customizable. It allows weighting different
conditional inputs differently at different spatial locations. This enables
highly controllable world generation and finds use in various world-to-world
transfer use cases, including Sim2Real. We conduct extensive evaluations to
analyze the proposed model and demonstrate its applications for Physical AI,
including robotics Sim2Real and autonomous vehicle data enrichment. We further
demonstrate an inference scaling strategy to achieve real-time world generation
with an NVIDIA GB200 NVL72 rack. To help accelerate research development in the
field, we open-source our models and code at
https://github.com/nvidia-cosmos/cosmos-transfer1.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name> NVIDIA</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name> :</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hassan Abu Alhaija</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jose Alvarez</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Maciej Bala</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tiffany Cai</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tianshi Cao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Liz Cha</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Joshua Chen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mike Chen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Francesco Ferroni</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sanja Fidler</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Dieter Fox</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yunhao Ge</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jinwei Gu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ali Hassani</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Michael Isaev</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Pooya Jannaty</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Shiyi Lan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tobias Lasser</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Huan Ling</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ming-Yu Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xian Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yifan Lu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alice Luo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Qianli Ma</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hanzi Mao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Fabio Ramos</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xuanchi Ren</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tianchang Shen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Shitao Tang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ting-Chun Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Wu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jiashu Xu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Stella Xu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kevin Xie</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yuchong Ye</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xiaodong Yang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xiaohui Zeng</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yu Zeng</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14492v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2503.14492v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14484v1</id>
    <updated>2025-03-18T17:54:14Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-18T17:54:14Z</published>
    <title>Gricean Norms as a Basis for Effective Collaboration</title>
    <summary>  Effective human-AI collaboration hinges not only on the AI agent's ability to
follow explicit instructions but also on its capacity to navigate ambiguity,
incompleteness, invalidity, and irrelevance in communication. Gricean
conversational and inference norms facilitate collaboration by aligning unclear
instructions with cooperative principles. We propose a normative framework that
integrates Gricean norms and cognitive frameworks -- common ground, relevance
theory, and theory of mind -- into large language model (LLM) based agents. The
normative framework adopts the Gricean maxims of quantity, quality, relation,
and manner, along with inference, as Gricean norms to interpret unclear
instructions, which are: ambiguous, incomplete, invalid, or irrelevant. Within
this framework, we introduce Lamoids, GPT-4 powered agents designed to
collaborate with humans. To assess the influence of Gricean norms in human-AI
collaboration, we evaluate two versions of a Lamoid: one with norms and one
without. In our experiments, a Lamoid collaborates with a human to achieve
shared goals in a grid world (Doors, Keys, and Gems) by interpreting both clear
and unclear natural language instructions. Our results reveal that the Lamoid
with Gricean norms achieves higher task accuracy and generates clearer, more
accurate, and contextually relevant responses than the Lamoid without norms.
This improvement stems from the normative framework, which enhances the agent's
pragmatic reasoning, fostering effective human-AI collaboration and enabling
context-aware communication in LLM-based agents.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Fardin Saad</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Pradeep K. Murukannaiah</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Munindar P. Singh</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Accepted to AAMAS 2025. 8 pages (excl. references), 9 figures/tables.
  (Appendix: 5 pages, 6 figures/tables). Code available at:
  https://github.com/fardinsaad/Gricean-Norms</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14484v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2503.14484v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.MA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.MA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14477v1</id>
    <updated>2025-03-18T17:51:04Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-18T17:51:04Z</published>
    <title>Calibrating Verbal Uncertainty as a Linear Feature to Reduce
  Hallucinations</title>
    <summary>  LLMs often adopt an assertive language style also when making false claims.
Such ``overconfident hallucinations'' mislead users and erode trust. Achieving
the ability to express in language the actual degree of uncertainty around a
claim is therefore of great importance. We find that ``verbal uncertainty'' is
governed by a single linear feature in the representation space of LLMs, and
show that this has only moderate correlation with the actual ``semantic
uncertainty'' of the model. We apply this insight and show that (1) the
mismatch between semantic and verbal uncertainty is a better predictor of
hallucinations than semantic uncertainty alone and (2) we can intervene on
verbal uncertainty at inference time and reduce hallucinations on short-form
answers, achieving an average relative reduction of 32%.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ziwei Ji</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lei Yu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yeskendir Koishekenov</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yejin Bang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Anthony Hartshorn</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alan Schelten</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Cheng Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Pascale Fung</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Nicola Cancedda</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14477v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2503.14477v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14476v1</id>
    <updated>2025-03-18T17:49:06Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-18T17:49:06Z</published>
    <title>DAPO: An Open-Source LLM Reinforcement Learning System at Scale</title>
    <summary>  Inference scaling empowers LLMs with unprecedented reasoning ability, with
reinforcement learning as the core technique to elicit complex reasoning.
However, key technical details of state-of-the-art reasoning LLMs are concealed
(such as in OpenAI o1 blog and DeepSeek R1 technical report), thus the
community still struggles to reproduce their RL training results. We propose
the $\textbf{D}$ecoupled Clip and $\textbf{D}$ynamic s$\textbf{A}$mpling
$\textbf{P}$olicy $\textbf{O}$ptimization ($\textbf{DAPO}$) algorithm, and
fully open-source a state-of-the-art large-scale RL system that achieves 50
points on AIME 2024 using Qwen2.5-32B base model. Unlike previous works that
withhold training details, we introduce four key techniques of our algorithm
that make large-scale LLM RL a success. In addition, we open-source our
training code, which is built on the verl framework, along with a carefully
curated and processed dataset. These components of our open-source system
enhance reproducibility and support future research in large-scale LLM RL.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Qiying Yu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zheng Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ruofei Zhu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yufeng Yuan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xiaochen Zuo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yu Yue</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tiantian Fan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Gaohong Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lingjun Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xin Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Haibin Lin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zhiqi Lin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Bole Ma</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Guangming Sheng</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yuxuan Tong</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Chi Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mofan Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Wang Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hang Zhu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jinhua Zhu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jiaze Chen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jiangjie Chen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Chengyi Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hongli Yu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Weinan Dai</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yuxuan Song</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xiangpeng Wei</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hao Zhou</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jingjing Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Wei-Ying Ma</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ya-Qin Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lin Yan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mu Qiao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yonghui Wu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mingxuan Wang</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Project Page: https://dapo-sia.github.io/</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14476v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2503.14476v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14469v1</id>
    <updated>2025-03-18T17:45:32Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-18T17:45:32Z</published>
    <title>Attribution Score Alignment in Explainable Data Management</title>
    <summary>  Different attribution-scores have been proposed to quantify the relevance of
database tuples for a query answer from a database. Among them, we find Causal
Responsibility, the Shapley Value, the Banzhaf Power-Index, and the Causal
Effect. They have been analyzed in isolation, mainly in terms of computational
properties. In this work, we start an investigation into the alignment of these
scores on the basis of the queries at hand; that is, on whether they induce
compatible rankings of tuples. We are able to identify vast classes of queries
for which some pairs of scores are always aligned, and others for which they
are not. It turns out that the presence of exogenous tuples makes a crucial
difference in this regard.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Felipe Azua</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Leopoldo Bertossi</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14469v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2503.14469v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.DB" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.DB" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14460v1</id>
    <updated>2025-03-18T17:36:26Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-18T17:36:26Z</published>
    <title>Low-Metallicity Star Formation Survey in Sh2-284 (LZ-STAR). I. Ordered
  massive star formation in the outer Galaxy</title>
    <summary>  Star formation is a fundamental, yet poorly understood, process of the
Universe. It is important to study how star formation occurs in different
galactic environments. Thus, here, in the first of a series of papers, we
introduce the Low-Metallicity Star Formation (LZ-STAR) survey of the Sh2-284
(hereafter S284) region, which, at $Z\sim 0.3-0.5Z_\odot$, is one of the
lowest-metallicity star-forming regions of our Galaxy. LZ-STAR is a
multi-facility survey, including observations with {\it JWST}, {\it ALMA}, {\it
HST}, {\it Chandra} and {\it Gemini}. As a starting point, we report {\it JWST}
and {\it ALMA} observations of one of the most massive protostars in the
region, S284p1. The observations of shock-excited molecular hydrogen reveal a
symmetric, bipolar outflow originating from the protostar, spanning several
parsecs, and fully covered by the {\it JWST} field of view and the {\it ALMA}
observations of CO(2-1) emission. This allows us to infer that the protostar
has maintained a relatively stable orientation of disk accretion over its
formation history. The {\it JWST} near-IR continuum observations detect a
centrally illuminated bipolar outflow cavity around the protostar, as well as a
surrounding cluster of low-mass young stars. We develop new radiative transfer
models of massive protostars designed for the low metallicity of S284. Fitting
these models to the protostar's spectral energy distribution implies a current
protostellar mass of $\sim11\:M_\odot$ has formed from an initially
$\sim100\:M_\odot$ core over the last $\sim3\times10^5$ years. Overall, these
results indicate that massive stars can form in an ordered manner in
low-metallicity, protocluster environments.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Yu Cheng</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jonathan C. Tan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Morten Andersen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Rubén Fedriani</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yichen Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Massimo Robberto</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zhi-Yun Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kei E. I. Tanaka</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">19 pages, 12 figures, submitted to ApJ, comments welcome</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14460v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2503.14460v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14459v1</id>
    <updated>2025-03-18T17:33:10Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-18T17:33:10Z</published>
    <title>Doubly robust identification of treatment effects from multiple
  environments</title>
    <summary>  Practical and ethical constraints often require the use of observational data
for causal inference, particularly in medicine and social sciences. Yet,
observational datasets are prone to confounding, potentially compromising the
validity of causal conclusions. While it is possible to correct for biases if
the underlying causal graph is known, this is rarely a feasible ask in
practical scenarios. A common strategy is to adjust for all available
covariates, yet this approach can yield biased treatment effect estimates,
especially when post-treatment or unobserved variables are present. We propose
RAMEN, an algorithm that produces unbiased treatment effect estimates by
leveraging the heterogeneity of multiple data sources without the need to know
or learn the underlying causal graph. Notably, RAMEN achieves doubly robust
identification: it can identify the treatment effect whenever the causal
parents of the treatment or those of the outcome are observed, and the node
whose parents are observed satisfies an invariance assumption. Empirical
evaluations on synthetic and real-world datasets show that our approach
outperforms existing methods.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Piersilvio De Bartolomeis</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Julia Kostin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Javier Abad</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yixin Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Fanny Yang</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Accepted for presentation at the International Conference on Learning
  Representations (ICLR) 2025</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14459v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2503.14459v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ME" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14456v1</id>
    <updated>2025-03-18T17:31:05Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-18T17:31:05Z</published>
    <title>RWKV-7 "Goose" with Expressive Dynamic State Evolution</title>
    <summary>  We present RWKV-7 "Goose", a new sequence modeling architecture, along with
pre-trained language models that establish a new state-of-the-art in downstream
performance at the 3 billion parameter scale on multilingual tasks, and match
current SoTA English language performance despite being trained on dramatically
fewer tokens than other top 3B models. Nevertheless, RWKV-7 models require only
constant memory usage and constant inference time per token. RWKV-7 introduces
a newly generalized formulation of the delta rule with vector-valued gating and
in-context learning rates, as well as a relaxed value replacement rule. We show
that RWKV-7 can perform state tracking and recognize all regular languages,
while retaining parallelizability of training. This exceeds the capabilities of
Transformers under standard complexity conjectures, which are limited to
$\mathsf{TC}^0$. To demonstrate RWKV-7's language modeling capability, we also
present an extended open source 3.1 trillion token multilingual corpus, and
train four RWKV-7 models ranging from 0.19 billion to 2.9 billion parameters on
this dataset.
  To foster openness, reproduction, and adoption, we release our models and
dataset component listing at https://huggingface.co/RWKV, and our training and
inference code at https://github.com/RWKV/RWKV-LM all under the Apache 2.0
License.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Bo Peng</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ruichong Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Daniel Goldstein</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Eric Alcaide</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Haowen Hou</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Janna Lu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>William Merrill</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Guangyu Song</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kaifeng Tan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Saiteja Utpala</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Nathan Wilce</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Johan S. Wind</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tianyi Wu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Daniel Wuttke</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Christian Zhou-Zheng</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14456v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2503.14456v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="I.2.0; I.2.7" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14454v1</id>
    <updated>2025-03-18T17:30:26Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-18T17:30:26Z</published>
    <title>The Atacama Cosmology Telescope: DR6 Constraints on Extended
  Cosmological Models</title>
    <summary>  We use new cosmic microwave background (CMB) primary temperature and
polarization anisotropy measurements from the Atacama Cosmology Telescope (ACT)
Data Release 6 (DR6) to test foundational assumptions of the standard
cosmological model and set constraints on extensions to it. We derive
constraints from the ACT DR6 power spectra alone, as well as in combination
with legacy data from Planck. To break geometric degeneracies, we include ACT
and Planck CMB lensing data and baryon acoustic oscillation data from DESI
Year-1, and further add supernovae measurements from Pantheon+ for models that
affect the late-time expansion history. We verify the near-scale-invariance
(running of the spectral index $d n_s/d\ln k = 0.0062 \pm 0.0052$) and
adiabaticity of the primordial perturbations. Neutrino properties are
consistent with Standard Model predictions: we find no evidence for new light,
relativistic species that are free-streaming ($N_{\rm eff} = 2.86 \pm 0.13$,
which combined with external BBN data becomes $N_{\rm eff} = 2.89 \pm 0.11$),
for non-zero neutrino masses ($\sum m_\nu &lt; 0.082$ eV at 95% CL), or for
neutrino self-interactions. We also find no evidence for self-interacting dark
radiation ($N_{\rm idr} &lt; 0.134$), early-universe variation of fundamental
constants, early dark energy, primordial magnetic fields, or modified
recombination. Our data are consistent with standard BBN, the FIRAS-inferred
CMB temperature, a dark matter component that is collisionless and with only a
small fraction allowed as axion-like particles, a cosmological constant, and
the late-time growth rate predicted by general relativity. We find no
statistically significant preference for a departure from the baseline
$\Lambda$CDM model. In general, models introduced to increase the Hubble
constant or to decrease the amplitude of density fluctuations inferred from the
primary CMB are not favored by our data.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Erminia Calabrese</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>J. Colin Hill</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hidde T. Jense</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Adrien La Posta</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Irene Abril-Cabezas</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Graeme E. Addison</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Peter A. R. Ade</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Simone Aiola</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tommy Alford</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>David Alonso</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mandana Amiri</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Rui An</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zachary Atkins</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jason E. Austermann</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Eleonora Barbavara</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Nicola Barbieri</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Nicholas Battaglia</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Elia Stefano Battistelli</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>James A. Beall</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Rachel Bean</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ali Beheshti</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Benjamin Beringue</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tanay Bhandarkar</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Emily Biermann</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Boris Bolliet</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>J Richard Bond</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Valentina Capalbo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Felipe Carrero</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Stephen Chen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Grace Chesmore</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hsiao-mei Cho</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Steve K. Choi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Susan E. Clark</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Nicholas F. Cothard</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kevin Coughlin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>William Coulton</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Devin Crichton</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kevin T. Crowley</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Omar Darwish</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mark J. Devlin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Dicker</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Cody J. Duell</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Shannon M. Duff</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Adriaan J. Duivenvoorden</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jo Dunkley</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Rolando Dunner</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Carmen Embil Villagra</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Max Fankhanel</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Gerrit S. Farren</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Simone Ferraro</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Allen Foster</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Rodrigo Freundt</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Brittany Fuzia</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Patricio A. Gallardo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xavier Garrido</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Martina Gerbino</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Serena Giardiello</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ajay Gill</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jahmour Givans</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Vera Gluscevic</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Samuel Goldstein</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Joseph E. Golec</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yulin Gong</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yilun Guan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mark Halpern</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Harrison</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Matthew Hasselfield</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Adam He</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Erin Healy</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Shawn Henderson</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Brandon Hensley</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Carlos Hervías-Caimapo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Gene C. Hilton</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Matt Hilton</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Adam D. Hincks</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Renée Hložek</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Shuay-Pwu Patty Ho</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>John Hood</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Erika Hornecker</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zachary B. Huber</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Johannes Hubmayr</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kevin M. Huffenberger</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>John P. Hughes</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Margaret Ikape</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kent Irwin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Giovanni Isopi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Neha Joshi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ben Keller</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Joshua Kim</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kenda Knowles</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Brian J. Koopman</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Arthur Kosowsky</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Darby Kramer</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Aleksandra Kusiak</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alex Lague</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Victoria Lakey</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Massimiliano Lattanzi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Eunseong Lee</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yaqiong Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zack Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Michele Limon</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Martine Lokken</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Thibaut Louis</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Marius Lungu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Niall MacCrann</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Amanda MacInnis</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mathew S. Madhavacheril</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Diego Maldonado</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Felipe Maldonado</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Maya Mallaby-Kay</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Gabriela A. Marques</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Joshiwa van Marrewijk</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Fiona McCarthy</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jeff McMahon</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yogesh Mehta</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Felipe Menanteau</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kavilan Moodley</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Thomas W. Morris</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tony Mroczkowski</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sigurd Naess</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Toshiya Namikawa</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Federico Nati</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Simran K. Nerval</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Laura Newburgh</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Andrina Nicola</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Michael D. Niemack</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Michael R. Nolta</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>John Orlowski-Scherer</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Luca Pagano</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lyman A. Page</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Shivam Pandey</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Bruce Partridge</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Karen Perez Sarmiento</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Heather Prince</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Roberto Puddu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Frank J. Qu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Damien C. Ragavan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Bernardita Ried Guachalla</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Keir K. Rogers</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Felipe Rojas</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tai Sakuma</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Emmanuel Schaan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Benjamin L. Schmitt</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Neelima Sehgal</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Shabbir Shaikh</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Blake D. Sherwin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Carlos Sierra</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jon Sievers</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Cristóbal Sifón</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sara Simon</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Rita Sonka</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>David N. Spergel</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Suzanne T. Staggs</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Emilie Storer</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kristen Surrao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Eric R. Switzer</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Niklas Tampier</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Leander Thiele</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Robert Thornton</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hy Trac</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Carole Tucker</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Joel Ullom</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Leila R. Vale</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alexander Van Engelen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jeff Van Lanen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Cristian Vargas</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Eve M. Vavagiakis</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kasey Wagoner</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yuhan Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lukas Wenzl</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Edward J. Wollack</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kaiwen Zheng</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">56+32 pages, 46+9 figures, abstract abridged here. Part of ACT DR6
  suite of papers submitted to JCAP. Data located at
  https://lambda.gsfc.nasa.gov/product/act/actadv_prod_table.html</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14454v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2503.14454v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="astro-ph.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="gr-qc" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="hep-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14445v1</id>
    <updated>2025-03-18T17:24:19Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-18T17:24:19Z</published>
    <title>Bolt3D: Generating 3D Scenes in Seconds</title>
    <summary>  We present a latent diffusion model for fast feed-forward 3D scene
generation. Given one or more images, our model Bolt3D directly samples a 3D
scene representation in less than seven seconds on a single GPU. We achieve
this by leveraging powerful and scalable existing 2D diffusion network
architectures to produce consistent high-fidelity 3D scene representations. To
train this model, we create a large-scale multiview-consistent dataset of 3D
geometry and appearance by applying state-of-the-art dense 3D reconstruction
techniques to existing multiview image datasets. Compared to prior multiview
generative models that require per-scene optimization for 3D reconstruction,
Bolt3D reduces the inference cost by a factor of up to 300 times.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Stanislaw Szymanowicz</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jason Y. Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Pratul Srinivasan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ruiqi Gao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Arthur Brussee</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Aleksander Holynski</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ricardo Martin-Brualla</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jonathan T. Barron</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Philipp Henzler</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Project page: https://szymanowiczs.github.io/bolt3d</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14445v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2503.14445v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
