<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Last updated: 2025-03-29T00:51:58Z -->
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3Dall%3Acausal%20inference%26id_list%3D%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=all:causal inference&amp;id_list=&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/SsRksLzRb0LuVhSmQ+N8WbAs+f8</id>
  <updated>2025-03-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">109640</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.21782v1</id>
    <updated>2025-03-27T17:59:58Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-27T17:59:58Z</published>
    <title>Mobile-VideoGPT: Fast and Accurate Video Understanding Language Model</title>
    <summary>  Video understanding models often struggle with high computational
requirements, extensive parameter counts, and slow inference speed, making them
inefficient for practical use. To tackle these challenges, we propose
Mobile-VideoGPT, an efficient multimodal framework designed to operate with
fewer than a billion parameters. Unlike traditional video large multimodal
models (LMMs), Mobile-VideoGPT consists of lightweight dual visual encoders,
efficient projectors, and a small language model (SLM), enabling real-time
throughput. To further improve efficiency, we present an Attention-Based Frame
Scoring mechanism to select the key-frames, along with an efficient token
projector that prunes redundant visual tokens and preserves essential
contextual cues. We evaluate our model across well-established six video
understanding benchmarks (e.g., MVBench, EgoSchema, NextQA, and PercepTest).
Our results show that Mobile-VideoGPT-0.5B can generate up to 46 tokens per
second while outperforming existing state-of-the-art 0.5B-parameter models by 6
points on average with 40% fewer parameters and more than 2x higher throughput.
Our code and models are publicly available at:
https://github.com/Amshaker/Mobile-VideoGPT.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Abdelrahman Shaker</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Muhammad Maaz</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Chenhui Gou</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hamid Rezatofighi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Salman Khan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Fahad Shahbaz Khan</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Technical Report. Project Page:
  https://amshaker.github.io/Mobile-VideoGPT</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.21782v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2503.21782v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.21758v1</id>
    <updated>2025-03-27T17:57:07Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-27T17:57:07Z</published>
    <title>Lumina-Image 2.0: A Unified and Efficient Image Generative Framework</title>
    <summary>  We introduce Lumina-Image 2.0, an advanced text-to-image generation framework
that achieves significant progress compared to previous work, Lumina-Next.
Lumina-Image 2.0 is built upon two key principles: (1) Unification - it adopts
a unified architecture (Unified Next-DiT) that treats text and image tokens as
a joint sequence, enabling natural cross-modal interactions and allowing
seamless task expansion. Besides, since high-quality captioners can provide
semantically well-aligned text-image training pairs, we introduce a unified
captioning system, Unified Captioner (UniCap), specifically designed for T2I
generation tasks. UniCap excels at generating comprehensive and accurate
captions, accelerating convergence and enhancing prompt adherence. (2)
Efficiency - to improve the efficiency of our proposed model, we develop
multi-stage progressive training strategies and introduce inference
acceleration techniques without compromising image quality. Extensive
evaluations on academic benchmarks and public text-to-image arenas show that
Lumina-Image 2.0 delivers strong performances even with only 2.6B parameters,
highlighting its scalability and design efficiency. We have released our
training details, code, and models at
https://github.com/Alpha-VLLM/Lumina-Image-2.0.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Qi Qin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Le Zhuo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yi Xin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ruoyi Du</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zhen Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Bin Fu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yiting Lu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jiakang Yuan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xinyue Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Dongyang Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xiangyang Zhu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Manyuan Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Will Beddow</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Erwann Millon</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Victor Perez</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Wenhai Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Conghui He</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Bo Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xiaohong Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hongsheng Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yu Qiao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Chang Xu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Peng Gao</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Tech Report, 21 pages, 12 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.21758v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2503.21758v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.21720v1</id>
    <updated>2025-03-27T17:34:25Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-27T17:34:25Z</published>
    <title>Collab: Controlled Decoding using Mixture of Agents for LLM Alignment</title>
    <summary>  Alignment of Large Language models (LLMs) is crucial for safe and trustworthy
deployment in applications. Reinforcement learning from human feedback (RLHF)
has emerged as an effective technique to align LLMs to human preferences and
broader utilities, but it requires updating billions of model parameters, which
is computationally expensive. Controlled Decoding, by contrast, provides a
mechanism for aligning a model at inference time without retraining. However,
single-agent decoding approaches often struggle to adapt to diverse tasks due
to the complexity and variability inherent in these tasks. To strengthen the
test-time performance w.r.t the target task, we propose a mixture of
agent-based decoding strategies leveraging the existing off-the-shelf aligned
LLM policies. Treating each prior policy as an agent in the spirit of mixture
of agent collaboration, we develop a decoding method that allows for
inference-time alignment through a token-level selection strategy among
multiple agents. For each token, the most suitable LLM is dynamically chosen
from a pool of models based on a long-term utility metric. This
policy-switching mechanism ensures optimal model selection at each step,
enabling efficient collaboration and alignment among LLMs during decoding.
Theoretical analysis of our proposed algorithm establishes optimal performance
with respect to the target task represented via a target reward for the given
off-the-shelf models. We conduct comprehensive empirical evaluations with
open-source aligned models on diverse tasks and preferences, which demonstrates
the merits of this approach over single-agent decoding baselines. Notably,
Collab surpasses the current SoTA decoding strategy, achieving an improvement
of up to 1.56x in average reward and 71.89% in GPT-4 based win-tie rate.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Souradip Chakraborty</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sujay Bhatt</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Udari Madhushani Sehwag</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Soumya Suvra Ghosal</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jiahao Qiu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mengdi Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Dinesh Manocha</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Furong Huang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alec Koppel</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sumitra Ganesh</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Accepted to ICLR 2025</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.21720v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2503.21720v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.21714v1</id>
    <updated>2025-03-27T17:26:32Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-27T17:26:32Z</published>
    <title>As easy as PIE: understanding when pruning causes language models to
  disagree</title>
    <summary>  Language Model (LM) pruning compresses the model by removing weights, nodes,
or other parts of its architecture. Typically, pruning focuses on the resulting
efficiency gains at the cost of effectiveness. However, when looking at how
individual data points are affected by pruning, it turns out that a particular
subset of data points always bears most of the brunt (in terms of reduced
accuracy) when pruning, but this effect goes unnoticed when reporting the mean
accuracy of all data points. These data points are called PIEs and have been
studied in image processing, but not in NLP. In a study of various NLP
datasets, pruning methods, and levels of compression, we find that PIEs impact
inference quality considerably, regardless of class frequency, and that BERT is
more prone to this than BiLSTM. We also find that PIEs contain a high amount of
data points that have the largest influence on how well the model generalises
to unseen data. This means that when pruning, with seemingly moderate loss to
accuracy across all data points, we in fact hurt tremendously those data points
that matter the most. We trace what makes PIEs both hard and impactful to
inference to their overall longer and more semantically complex text. These
findings are novel and contribute to understanding how LMs are affected by
pruning. The code is available at: https://github.com/pietrotrope/AsEasyAsPIE
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Pietro Tropeano</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Maria Maistro</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tuukka Ruotsalo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Christina Lioma</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Accepted to NAACL 2025 (Findings)</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.21714v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2503.21714v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.21706v1</id>
    <updated>2025-03-27T17:20:35Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-27T17:20:35Z</published>
    <title>Flashlights: Prospects for constraining the Initial Mass Function around
  cosmic noon with caustic-crossing events</title>
    <summary>  The Flashlights program with the Hubble Space Telescope imaged the six Hubble
Frontier Fields galaxy clusters in two epochs and detected twenty transients.
These are primarily expected to be caustic-crossing events (CCEs) where bright
stars in distant lensed galaxies, typically at redshift $z\approx1$--3, get
temporarily magnified close to cluster caustics. Since CCEs are generally
biased toward more massive and luminous stars, they offer a unique route for
probing the high end of the stellar mass function. We take advantage of the
Flashlights event statistics to place preliminary constraints on the stellar
initial mass function (IMF) around cosmic noon. The photometry (along with
spectral information) of lensed arcs is used to infer their various stellar
properties, and stellar synthesis models are used to evolve a recent stellar
population in them. We estimate the microlens surface density near each arc
and, together with existing lens models and simple formalism for CCEs,
calculate the expected rate for a given IMF. We find that, on average, a
Salpeter-like IMF ($\alpha=2.35$) underpredicts the number of observed CCEs by
a factor of ${\sim}0.7$, and a top-heavy IMF ($\alpha=1.00$) overpredicts by a
factor of ${\sim}1.7$, suggesting that the average IMF slope may lie somewhere
in between. However, given the large uncertainties associated with estimating
the stellar populations, these results are strongly model-dependent.
Nevertheless, we introduce a useful framework for constraining the IMF using
CCEs. Observations with JWST are already yielding many more CCEs and will soon
enable more stringent constraints on the IMF at a range of redshifts.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ashish Kumar Meena</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sung Kei Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Zitrin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Patrick L. Kelly</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Broadhurst</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Wenlei Chen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jose M. Diego</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alexei V. Filippenko</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lukas J. Furtak</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Liliya L. R. Williams</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">14 pages. 6 figures. Comments welcome</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.21706v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2503.21706v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.21702v1</id>
    <updated>2025-03-27T17:06:09Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-27T17:06:09Z</published>
    <title>Enabling Robust Exoplanet Atmospheric Retrievals with Gaussian Processes</title>
    <summary>  Atmospheric retrievals are essential tools for interpreting exoplanet
transmission and eclipse spectra, enabling quantitative constraints on the
chemical composition, aerosol properties, and thermal structure of planetary
atmospheres. The James Webb Space Telescope (JWST) offers unprecedented
spectral precision, resolution, and wavelength coverage, unlocking
transformative insights into the formation, evolution, climate, and potential
habitability of planetary systems. However, this opportunity is accompanied by
challenges: modeling assumptions and unaccounted-for noise or signal sources
can bias retrieval outcomes and their interpretation. To address these
limitations, we introduce a Gaussian Process (GP)-aided atmospheric retrieval
framework that flexibly accounts for unmodeled features in exoplanet spectra,
whether global or localized. We validate this method on synthetic JWST
observations and show that GP-aided retrievals reduce bias in inferred
abundances and better capture model-data mismatches than traditional
approaches. We also introduce the concept of mean squared error to quantify the
trade-off between bias and variance, arguing that this metric more accurately
reflects retrieval performance than bias alone. We then reanalyze the
NIRISS/SOSS JWST transmission spectrum of WASP-96 b, finding that GP-aided
retrievals yield broader constraints on CO$_2$ and H$_2$O, alleviating tension
between previous retrieval results and equilibrium predictions. Our GP
framework provides precise and accurate constraints while highlighting regions
where models fail to explain the data. As JWST matures and future facilities
come online, a deeper understanding of the limitations of both data and models
will be essential, and GP-enabled retrievals like the one presented here offer
a principled path forward.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Yoav Rotman</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Luis Welbanks</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Michael R. Line</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Peter McGill</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Michael Radica</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Matthew C. Nixon</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Submitted to AAS Journals, 25 pages, 13 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.21702v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2503.21702v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="astro-ph.EP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.EP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.IM" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.21699v1</id>
    <updated>2025-03-27T17:04:33Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-27T17:04:33Z</published>
    <title>MAVERIX: Multimodal Audio-Visual Evaluation Reasoning IndeX</title>
    <summary>  Frontier models have either been language-only or have primarily focused on
vision and language modalities. Although recent advancements in models with
vision and audio understanding capabilities have shown substantial progress,
the field lacks a standardized evaluation framework for thoroughly assessing
their cross-modality perception performance. We introduce MAVERIX~(Multimodal
Audio-Visual Evaluation Reasoning IndeX), a novel benchmark with 700 videos and
2,556 questions explicitly designed to evaluate multimodal models through tasks
that necessitate close integration of video and audio information. MAVERIX
uniquely provides models with audiovisual tasks, closely mimicking the
multimodal perceptual experiences available to humans during inference and
decision-making processes. To our knowledge, MAVERIX is the first benchmark
aimed explicitly at assessing comprehensive audiovisual integration.
Experiments with state-of-the-art models, including Gemini 1.5 Pro and o1, show
performance approaching human levels (around 70% accuracy), while human experts
reach near-ceiling performance (95.1%). With standardized evaluation protocols,
a rigorously annotated pipeline, and a public toolkit, MAVERIX establishes a
challenging testbed for advancing audiovisual multimodal intelligence.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Liuyue Xie</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>George Z. Wei</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Avik Kuthiala</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ce Zheng</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ananya Bal</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mosam Dabhi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Liting Wen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Taru Rustagi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ethan Lai</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sushil Khyalia</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Rohan Choudhury</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Morteza Ziyadi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xu Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hao Yang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>László A. Jeni</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.21699v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2503.21699v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.SD" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.SD" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.21694v1</id>
    <updated>2025-03-27T16:59:15Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-27T16:59:15Z</published>
    <title>Progressive Rendering Distillation: Adapting Stable Diffusion for
  Instant Text-to-Mesh Generation without 3D Data</title>
    <summary>  It is highly desirable to obtain a model that can generate high-quality 3D
meshes from text prompts in just seconds. While recent attempts have adapted
pre-trained text-to-image diffusion models, such as Stable Diffusion (SD), into
generators of 3D representations (e.g., Triplane), they often suffer from poor
quality due to the lack of sufficient high-quality 3D training data. Aiming at
overcoming the data shortage, we propose a novel training scheme, termed as
Progressive Rendering Distillation (PRD), eliminating the need for 3D
ground-truths by distilling multi-view diffusion models and adapting SD into a
native 3D generator. In each iteration of training, PRD uses the U-Net to
progressively denoise the latent from random noise for a few steps, and in each
step it decodes the denoised latent into 3D output. Multi-view diffusion
models, including MVDream and RichDreamer, are used in joint with SD to distill
text-consistent textures and geometries into the 3D outputs through score
distillation. Since PRD supports training without 3D ground-truths, we can
easily scale up the training data and improve generation quality for
challenging text prompts with creative concepts. Meanwhile, PRD can accelerate
the inference speed of the generation model in just a few steps. With PRD, we
train a Triplane generator, namely TriplaneTurbo, which adds only $2.5\%$
trainable parameters to adapt SD for Triplane generation. TriplaneTurbo
outperforms previous text-to-3D generators in both efficiency and quality.
Specifically, it can produce high-quality 3D meshes in 1.2 seconds and
generalize well for challenging text input. The code is available at
https://github.com/theEricMa/TriplaneTurbo.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Zhiyuan Ma</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xinyue Liang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Rongyuan Wu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xiangyu Zhu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zhen Lei</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lei Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Accepted to CVPR 2025.
  Code:https://github.com/theEricMa/TriplaneTurbo.
  Demo:https://huggingface.co/spaces/ZhiyuanthePony/TriplaneTurbo</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.21694v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2503.21694v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.GR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.GR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.21687v1</id>
    <updated>2025-03-27T16:54:22Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-27T16:54:22Z</published>
    <title>Exploiting synergies between JWST and cosmic 21-cm observations to
  uncover star formation in the early Universe</title>
    <summary>  In the current era of JWST, we continue to uncover a wealth of information
about the Universe deep into the Epoch of Reionization. In this work, we run a
suite of simulations using the code 21cmSPACE, to explore the astrophysical
properties of galaxies in the early Universe, and their impact on high-redshift
observables. We use multi-wavelength observational data including the global
21-cm signal and power spectrum limits from SARAS~3 and HERA respectively,
present-day diffuse X-ray and radio backgrounds, and UV luminosity functions
(UVLFs) from HST and JWST in the range $z=6-14.5$ to derive our constraints. We
constrain a flexible model of halo-mass and redshift dependent star-formation
efficiency (SFE), defined as the gas fraction converted into stars, and find
that it is best described by little to no redshift evolution at $z\approx6-10$
and rapid evolution at $z\approx10-15$. We derive Bayesian functional posterior
distributions for the SFE across this redshift range, inferring that a halo of
mass $M_h=10^{10}\text{M}_\odot$ has an efficiency of $2-3\%$ at $z\lesssim10$,
$12\%$ at $z=12$ and $26\%$ at $z=15$. We also find, through synergy between
SARAS~3 and UVLFs, that the minimum circular velocity for star-formation in
halos is $V_c = 16.9^{+25.7}_{-9.5}\text{km s}^{-1}$ or equivalently
$\log_{10}(M_\text{crit}/\text{M}_\odot) = 8.29^{+1.21}_{-1.08}$ at $z=6$.
Alongside these star-formation constraints, we find the X-ray and radio
efficiencies of early galaxies to be $f_X = 0.5^{+6.3}_{-0.3}$ and $f_r
\lesssim 11.7$ respectively, improving upon existing works that do not use UVLF
data. Our results demonstrate the critical role of UVLFs in constraining the
early Universe, and its synergies with 21-cm observations, alongside other
multi-wavelength observational datasets.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Jiten Dhandha</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Thomas Gessey-Jones</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Harry T. J. Bevins</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Pochinda</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Anastasia Fialkov</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sandro Tacchella</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Eloy de Lera Acedo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Saurabh Singh</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Rennan Barkana</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">28 pages, 13 figures, 6 tables. Submitted to MNRAS. All comments
  welcome</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.21687v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2503.21687v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.21673v1</id>
    <updated>2025-03-27T16:41:14Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-27T16:41:14Z</published>
    <title>A friendly introduction to triangular transport</title>
    <summary>  Decision making under uncertainty is a cross-cutting challenge in science and
engineering. Most approaches to this challenge employ probabilistic
representations of uncertainty. In complicated systems accessible only via data
or black-box models, however, these representations are rarely known. We
discuss how to characterize and manipulate such representations using
triangular transport maps, which approximate any complex probability
distribution as a transformation of a simple, well-understood distribution. The
particular structure of triangular transport guarantees many desirable
mathematical and computational properties that translate well into solving
practical problems. Triangular maps are actively used for density estimation,
(conditional) generative modelling, Bayesian inference, data assimilation,
optimal experimental design, and related tasks. While there is ample literature
on the development and theory of triangular transport methods, this manuscript
provides a detailed introduction for scientists interested in employing measure
transport without assuming a formal mathematical background. We build intuition
for the key foundations of triangular transport, discuss many aspects of its
practical implementation, and outline the frontiers of this field.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Maximilian Ramgraber</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Daniel Sharp</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mathieu Le Provost</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Youssef Marzouk</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">46 pages, 17 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.21673v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2503.21673v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="stat.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.ao-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ME" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="62-01, 62-02, 60-08, 65C05, 62F15, 65C20" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
