<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Last updated: 2025-08-08T01:03:35Z -->
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3Dall%3Acausal%20inference%26id_list%3D%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=all:causal inference&amp;id_list=&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/SsRksLzRb0LuVhSmQ+N8WbAs+f8</id>
  <updated>2025-08-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">118406</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.04703v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-06T17:59:50Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-06T17:59:50Z</published>
    <title>Stochastic Taylor expansion via Poisson point processes</title>
    <summary>  We generalize Taylor's theorem by introducing a stochastic formulation based
on an underlying Poisson point process model. We utilize this approach to
propose a novel non-linear regression framework and perform statistical
inference of the model parameters. Theoretical properties of the proposed
estimator are also proven, including its convergence, uniformly almost surely,
to the true function. The theory is presented for the univariate and
multivariate cases, and we exemplify the proposed methodology using several
examples via simulations and an application to stock market data.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Weichao Wu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Athanasios C. Micheas</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">44 pages, 10 figures, 7 tables, Stochastic formulation of Taylor's
  theorem, function approximation, non-linear regression model</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.04703v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.04703v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="stat.ME" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ME" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.ST" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.AP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.TH" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.04690v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-06T17:53:24Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-06T17:53:24Z</published>
    <title>Controlled regularity at future null infinity from past asymptotic
  initial data: the wave equation</title>
    <summary>  We study the relationship between asymptotic characteristic initial data for
the wave equation at past null infinity and the regularity of the solution at
future null infinity on the Minkowski spacetime. By constructing estimates on a
causal rectangle reaching the conformal boundary, we prove that the solution
admits an asymptotic expansion near null and spatial infinity whose regularity
is controlled quantitatively in terms of the regularity of the data at past
null infinity. In particular, our method gives rise to solutions to the wave
equation in a neighbourhood of spatial infinity satisfying the peeling
behaviour, for data on past null infinity with non-compact support. Our
approach makes use of Friedrich's conformal representation of spatial infinity
in which we prove delicate non-degenerate Gr\"onwall estimates. We describe the
relationship between the solution and the data both in terms of Friedrich's
conformal coordinates and the usual physical coordinates on Minkowski space.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Jordan Marajh</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Grigalius Taujanskas</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Juan A. Valiente Kroon</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">30 pages, 2 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.04690v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.04690v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="gr-qc" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="gr-qc" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.AP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.04675v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-06T17:41:44Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-06T17:41:44Z</published>
    <title>Water Detection in the Interstellar Object 3I/ATLAS</title>
    <summary>  We report the first detection of water activity in the third confirmed
interstellar object, 3I/ATLAS, based on ultraviolet imaging with the \emph{Neil
Gehrels-Swift Observatory}. Observations acquired with the Ultraviolet/Optical
Telescope on 2025 July 31st - Aug 1st revealed OH (A$^2\Sigma$ -- X$^2\Pi$)
emission near 3085~\AA. The water production rate results highly depend on the
reddening assumption. For a reddening of 38.6\% between 5437.8~\AA\ and
3325.7~\AA, the water production rate is $(1.35 \pm 0.27) \times 10^{27} $
molecules\,s$^{-1}$ (40~kg\,s$^{-1}$) at a heliocentric distance of 3.51~au.
This places 3I/ATLAS among the few comets with confirmed OH emission beyond
3~au, where water ice sublimation is typically inefficient. The inferred
production rate is consistent with an active area of at least 19~km$^2$,
assuming equilibrium sublimation. Based on current upper limits of the nucleus'
radius, this requires that over 20\% of the surface is active, which is larger
than activity levels observed in most solar system comets. Contemporaneous
near-infrared spectroscopy indicates the presence of large icy grains in the
coma, which may serve as an extended source of water vapor. The detection of OH
emission prior to any CN detection is unusual and may reflect differences in
grain-driven outgassing or volatile inventory compared to typical comets. While
similar behavior has been observed in solar system comets, the mechanisms
controlling distant activity and the storage and release of volatiles remain
poorly understood. If 3I/ATLAS' coma continues to be dominated by H$_2$O,
supporting the early and low-metallicity formation hypothesis, the derived
large size of the nucleus could be indicative of a key knowledge gap in
low-metallicity system planetesimal formation and loss mechanisms.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Zexi Xing</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Shawn Oset</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>John Noonan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Dennis Bodewits</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Submitted to ApJL, 9 pages, 2 figures, 1 table</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.04675v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.04675v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="astro-ph.EP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.EP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.04663v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-06T17:30:44Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-06T17:30:44Z</published>
    <title>HierarchicalPrune: Position-Aware Compression for Large-Scale Diffusion
  Models</title>
    <summary>  State-of-the-art text-to-image diffusion models (DMs) achieve remarkable
quality, yet their massive parameter scale (8-11B) poses significant challenges
for inferences on resource-constrained devices. In this paper, we present
HierarchicalPrune, a novel compression framework grounded in a key observation:
DM blocks exhibit distinct functional hierarchies, where early blocks establish
semantic structures while later blocks handle texture refinements.
HierarchicalPrune synergistically combines three techniques: (1) Hierarchical
Position Pruning, which identifies and removes less essential later blocks
based on position hierarchy; (2) Positional Weight Preservation, which
systematically protects early model portions that are essential for semantic
structural integrity; and (3) Sensitivity-Guided Distillation, which adjusts
knowledge-transfer intensity based on our discovery of block-wise sensitivity
variations. As a result, our framework brings billion-scale diffusion models
into a range more suitable for on-device inference, while preserving the
quality of the output images. Specifically, when combined with INT4 weight
quantisation, HierarchicalPrune achieves 77.5-80.4% memory footprint reduction
(e.g., from 15.8 GB to 3.2 GB) and 27.9-38.0% latency reduction, measured on
server and consumer grade GPUs, with the minimum drop of 2.6% in GenEval score
and 7% in HPSv2 score compared to the original model. Last but not least, our
comprehensive user study with 85 participants demonstrates that
HierarchicalPrune maintains perceptual quality comparable to the original model
while significantly outperforming prior works.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Young D. Kwon</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Rui Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sijia Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Da Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sourav Bhattacharya</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Stylianos I. Venieris</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.04663v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.04663v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.04647v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-06T17:15:03Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-06T17:15:03Z</published>
    <title>Stochastic Calculus for Pathwise Observables of Markov-Jump Processes:
  Unification of Diffusion and Jump Dynamics</title>
    <summary>  Path-wise observables--functionals of stochastic trajectories--are at the
heart of time-average statistical mechanics and are central to thermodynamic
inequalities such as uncertainty relations, speed limits, and
correlation-bounds. They provide a means of thermodynamic inference in the
typical situation, when not all dissipative degrees of freedom in a system are
experimentally accessible. So far, theories focusing on path-wise observables
have been developing in two major directions, diffusion processes and
Markov-jump dynamics, in a virtually disjoint manner. Moreover, even the
respective results for diffusion and jump dynamics were derived with a
patchwork of different approaches that are predominantly indirect. Stochastic
calculus was recently shown to provide a direct approach to path-wise
observables of diffusion processes, while a corresponding framework for jump
dynamics remained elusive. In our work we develop, in an exact parallelism with
continuous-space diffusion, a complete stochastic calculus for path-wise
observables of Markov-jump processes. We formulate a "Langevin equation" for
jump processes, define general path-wise observables, and establish their
covariation structure, whereby we fully account for transients and
time-inhomogeneous dynamics. We prove the known kinds of thermodynamic
inequalities in their most general form and discus saturation conditions. We
determine the response of path-wise observables to general (incl. thermal)
perturbations and carry out the continuum limit to achieve the complete
unification of diffusion and jump dynamics. Our results open new avenues in the
direction of discrete-state analogs of generative diffusion models and the
learning of stochastic thermodynamics from fluctuating trajectories.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Lars Torbjørn Stutzer</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Cai Dieball</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Aljaž Godec</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.04647v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.04647v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cond-mat.stat-mech" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.stat-mech" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.PR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.04643v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-06T17:07:59Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-06T17:07:59Z</published>
    <title>Experimental device-independent certification of indefinite causal order</title>
    <summary>  Understanding the physical world fundamentally relies on the assumption that
events are temporally ordered, with past events serving as causes for future
ones. However, quantum mechanics permits events to occur in a superposition of
causal orders, providing new types of quantum resources for quantum information
tasks. Previous demonstrations of indefinite causal order have relied on a
process known as quantum switch and depended on specific assumptions about the
devices used in the laboratory. Recently, a theoretical scheme for the
certification of indefinite causal order in the quantum switch has been
obtained solely from the output statistics of the devices, analogous to the
device-independent proofs of nonlocality through violations of the Bell
inequality. Here, we report an experimental verification of the causal
inequality using spacelike-separated entangled photons, where one photon
functions as the control qubit in a quantum switch and the other serves as an
additional observer. Through local measurement statistics, we observe a
violation of the causal inequality by 24 standard deviations. This work
provides evidence for a device-independent certification of indefinite causal
order, relying solely on observed correlations without requiring device
characterization. Our results pave the way toward a complete understanding of
indefinite causal order and its potential applications in quantum information
processing.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Dengke Qu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Quan Lin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lei Xiao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xiang Zhan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Peng Xue</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.04643v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.04643v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.04630v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-06T16:57:06Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-06T16:57:06Z</published>
    <title>CaPulse: Detecting Anomalies by Tuning in to the Causal Rhythms of Time
  Series</title>
    <summary>  Time series anomaly detection has garnered considerable attention across
diverse domains. While existing methods often fail to capture the underlying
mechanisms behind anomaly generation in time series data. In addition, time
series anomaly detection often faces several data-related inherent challenges,
i.e., label scarcity, data imbalance, and complex multi-periodicity. In this
paper, we leverage causal tools and introduce a new causality-based framework,
CaPulse, which tunes in to the underlying causal pulse of time series data to
effectively detect anomalies. Concretely, we begin by building a structural
causal model to decipher the generation processes behind anomalies. To tackle
the challenges posed by the data, we propose Periodical Normalizing Flows with
a novel mask mechanism and carefully designed periodical learners, creating a
periodicity-aware, density-based anomaly detection approach. Extensive
experiments on seven real-world datasets demonstrate that CaPulse consistently
outperforms existing methods, achieving AUROC improvements of 3% to 17%, with
enhanced interpretability.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Yutong Xia</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yingying Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yuxuan Liang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lunting Fan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Qingsong Wen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Roger Zimmermann</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.04630v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.04630v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.04597v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-06T16:16:58Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-06T16:16:58Z</published>
    <title>Pseudo Depth Meets Gaussian: A Feed-forward RGB SLAM Baseline</title>
    <summary>  Incrementally recovering real-sized 3D geometry from a pose-free RGB stream
is a challenging task in 3D reconstruction, requiring minimal assumptions on
input data. Existing methods can be broadly categorized into end-to-end and
visual SLAM-based approaches, both of which either struggle with long sequences
or depend on slow test-time optimization and depth sensors. To address this, we
first integrate a depth estimator into an RGB-D SLAM system, but this approach
is hindered by inaccurate geometric details in predicted depth. Through further
investigation, we find that 3D Gaussian mapping can effectively solve this
problem. Building on this, we propose an online 3D reconstruction method using
3D Gaussian-based SLAM, combined with a feed-forward recurrent prediction
module to directly infer camera pose from optical flow. This approach replaces
slow test-time optimization with fast network inference, significantly
improving tracking speed. Additionally, we introduce a local graph rendering
technique to enhance robustness in feed-forward pose prediction. Experimental
results on the Replica and TUM-RGBD datasets, along with a real-world
deployment demonstration, show that our method achieves performance on par with
the state-of-the-art SplaTAM, while reducing tracking time by more than 90\%.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Linqing Zhao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xiuwei Xu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yirui Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hao Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Wenzhao Zheng</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yansong Tang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Haibin Yan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jiwen Lu</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">IROS 2025</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.04597v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.04597v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.04585v2</id>
    <updated>2025-08-07T03:38:23Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-06T16:08:22Z</published>
    <title>UniTalker: Conversational Speech-Visual Synthesis</title>
    <summary>  Conversational Speech Synthesis (CSS) is a key task in the user-agent
interaction area, aiming to generate more expressive and empathetic speech for
users. However, it is well-known that "listening" and "eye contact" play
crucial roles in conveying emotions during real-world interpersonal
communication. Existing CSS research is limited to perceiving only text and
speech within the dialogue context, which restricts its effectiveness.
Moreover, speech-only responses further constrain the interactive experience.
To address these limitations, we introduce a Conversational Speech-Visual
Synthesis (CSVS) task as an extension of traditional CSS. By leveraging
multimodal dialogue context, it provides users with coherent audiovisual
responses. To this end, we develop a CSVS system named UniTalker, which is a
unified model that seamlessly integrates multimodal perception and multimodal
rendering capabilities. Specifically, it leverages a large-scale language model
to comprehensively understand multimodal cues in the dialogue context,
including speaker, text, speech, and the talking-face animations. After that,
it employs multi-task sequence prediction to first infer the target utterance's
emotion and then generate empathetic speech and natural talking-face
animations. To ensure that the generated speech-visual content remains
consistent in terms of emotion, content, and duration, we introduce three key
optimizations: 1) Designing a specialized neural landmark codec to tokenize and
reconstruct facial expression sequences. 2) Proposing a bimodal speech-visual
hard alignment decoding strategy. 3) Applying emotion-guided rendering during
the generation stage. Comprehensive objective and subjective experiments
demonstrate that our model synthesizes more empathetic speech and provides
users with more natural and emotionally consistent talking-face animations.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Yifan Hu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Rui Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yi Ren</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xiang Yin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Haizhou Li</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">15 pages, 8 figures, Accepted by ACM MM 2025</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.04585v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.04585v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="eess.AS" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="eess.AS" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.04583v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-06T16:07:29Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-06T16:07:29Z</published>
    <title>Measuring the Carbon Footprint of Cryptographic Privacy-Enhancing
  Technologies</title>
    <summary>  Privacy-enhancing technologies (PETs) have attracted significant attention in
response to privacy regulations, driving the development of applications that
prioritize user data protection. At the same time, the information and
communication technology (ICT) sector faces growing pressure to reduce its
environmental footprint, particularly its carbon emissions. While numerous
studies have assessed the energy footprint of various ICT applications, the
environmental footprint of cryptographic PETs remains largely unexplored.
  Our work addresses this gap by proposing a standardized methodology for
evaluating the carbon footprint of PETs. To demonstrate this methodology, we
focus on PETs supporting client-server applications as they are the simplest to
deploy. In particular, we measure the energy consumption and carbon footprint
increase induced by five cryptographic PETs (compared to their non-private
equivalent): HTTPS web browsing, encrypted machine learning (ML) inference,
encrypted ML training, encrypted databases, and encrypted emails. Our findings
reveal significant variability in carbon footprint increases, ranging from a
twofold increase in HTTPS web browsing to a 100,000-fold increase in encrypted
ML.
  Our study provides essential data to help decision-makers assess
privacy-carbon trade-offs in such applications. Finally, we outline key
research directions for developing PETs that balance strong privacy protection
with environmental sustainability.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Marc Damie</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mihai Pop</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Merijn Posthuma</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.04583v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.04583v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
