<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Last updated: 2025-09-19T00:53:46Z -->
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3Dall%3Acausal%20inference%26id_list%3D%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=all:causal inference&amp;id_list=&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/SsRksLzRb0LuVhSmQ+N8WbAs+f8</id>
  <updated>2025-09-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">121171</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14234v1</id>
    <updated>2025-09-17T17:59:42Z</updated>
    <published>2025-09-17T17:59:42Z</published>
    <title>Compute as Teacher: Turning Inference Compute Into Reference-Free
  Supervision</title>
    <summary>  Where do learning signals come from when there is no ground truth in
post-training? We propose turning exploration into supervision through Compute
as Teacher (CaT), which converts the model's own exploration at inference-time
into reference-free supervision by synthesizing a single reference from a group
of parallel rollouts and then optimizing toward it. Concretely, the current
policy produces a group of rollouts; a frozen anchor (the initial policy)
reconciles omissions and contradictions to estimate a reference, turning extra
inference-time compute into a teacher signal. We turn this into rewards in two
regimes: (i) verifiable tasks use programmatic equivalence on final answers;
(ii) non-verifiable tasks use self-proposed rubrics-binary, auditable criteria
scored by an independent LLM judge, with reward given by the fraction
satisfied. Unlike selection methods (best-of-N, majority, perplexity, or judge
scores), synthesis may disagree with the majority and be correct even when all
rollouts are wrong; performance scales with the number of rollouts. As a
test-time procedure, CaT improves Gemma 3 4B, Qwen 3 4B, and Llama 3.1 8B (up
to +27% on MATH-500; +12% on HealthBench). With reinforcement learning
(CaT-RL), we obtain further gains (up to +33% and +30%), with the trained
policy surpassing the initial teacher signal.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Dulhan Jayalath</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Shashwat Goel</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Thomas Foster</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Parag Jain</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Suchin Gururangan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Cheng Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Anirudh Goyal</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alan Schelten</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">22 pages, 8 figures, 2 tables</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14234v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2509.14234v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14229v1</id>
    <updated>2025-09-17T17:58:28Z</updated>
    <published>2025-09-17T17:58:28Z</published>
    <title>Spacing Test for Fused Lasso</title>
    <summary>  This study addresses the unresolved problem of selecting the regularization
parameter in the fused lasso. In particular, we extend the framework of the
Spacing Test proposed by Tibshirani et al. to the fused lasso, providing a
theoretical foundation for post-selection inference by characterizing the
selection event as a polyhedral constraint. Based on the analysis of the
solution path of the fused lasso using a LARS-type algorithm, we derive exact
conditional $p$-values for the selected change-points. Our method broadens the
applicability of the Spacing Test from the standard lasso to fused penalty
structures. Furthermore, through numerical experiments comparing the proposed
method with sequential versions of AIC and BIC as well as cross-validation, we
demonstrate that the proposed approach properly controls the type I error while
achieving high detection power. This work offers a theoretically sound and
computationally practical solution for parameter selection and post-selection
inference in structured signal estimation problems. Keywords: Fused Lasso,
Regularization parameter selection, Spacing Test for Lasso, Selective
inference, Change-point detection
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Rieko Tasaka</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tatsuya Kimura</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Joe Suzuki</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14229v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2509.14229v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="math.ST" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.ST" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.TH" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14225v1</id>
    <updated>2025-09-17T17:56:20Z</updated>
    <published>2025-09-17T17:56:20Z</published>
    <title>Defending Diffusion Models Against Membership Inference Attacks via
  Higher-Order Langevin Dynamics</title>
    <summary>  Recent advances in generative artificial intelligence applications have
raised new data security concerns. This paper focuses on defending diffusion
models against membership inference attacks. This type of attack occurs when
the attacker can determine if a certain data point was used to train the model.
Although diffusion models are intrinsically more resistant to membership
inference attacks than other generative models, they are still susceptible. The
defense proposed here utilizes critically-damped higher-order Langevin
dynamics, which introduces several auxiliary variables and a joint diffusion
process along these variables. The idea is that the presence of auxiliary
variables mixes external randomness that helps to corrupt sensitive input data
earlier on in the diffusion process. This concept is theoretically investigated
and validated on a toy dataset and a speech dataset using the Area Under the
Receiver Operating Characteristic (AUROC) curves and the FID metric.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Benjamin Sterling</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yousef El-Laham</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mónica F. Bugallo</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">5 pages, 2 figures, 1 table</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14225v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2509.14225v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14218v1</id>
    <updated>2025-09-17T17:51:40Z</updated>
    <published>2025-09-17T17:51:40Z</published>
    <title>Adaptive Off-Policy Inference for M-Estimators Under Model
  Misspecification</title>
    <summary>  When data are collected adaptively, such as in bandit algorithms, classical
statistical approaches such as ordinary least squares and $M$-estimation will
often fail to achieve asymptotic normality. Although recent lines of work have
modified the classical approaches to ensure valid inference on adaptively
collected data, most of these works assume that the model is correctly
specified. We propose a method that provides valid inference for M-estimators
that use adaptively collected bandit data with a (possibly) misspecified
working model. A key ingredient in our approach is the use of flexible machine
learning approaches to stabilize the variance induced by adaptive data
collection. A major novelty is that our procedure enables the construction of
valid confidence sets even in settings where treatment policies are unstable
and non-converging, such as when there is no unique optimal arm and standard
bandit algorithms are used. Empirical results on semi-synthetic datasets
constructed from the Osteoarthritis Initiative demonstrate that the method
maintains type I error control, while existing methods for inference in
adaptive settings do not cover in the misspecified case.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>James Leiner</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Robin Dunn</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Aaditya Ramdas</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">36 pages, 6 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14218v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2509.14218v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="stat.ME" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ME" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.ST" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.OT" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.TH" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14206v1</id>
    <updated>2025-09-17T17:37:25Z</updated>
    <published>2025-09-17T17:37:25Z</published>
    <title>Looking into the faintEst WIth MUSE (LEWIS): Exploring the nature of
  ultra-diffuse galaxies in the Hydra-I cluster IV. A study of the Globular
  Cluster population in four UDGs</title>
    <summary>  As old stellar systems, globular clusters (GCs) are key fossil tracers of
galaxy formation and interaction histories. This paper is part of the LEWIS
project, an integral-field spectroscopic survey of ultra-diffuse galaxies
(UDGs) in the Hydra I cluster. We use MUSE spectroscopy and new VIRCAM $H$-band
imaging data to study the GC populations and dark matter content in four dwarf
galaxies. We retrieved line-of-sight velocities for all sources in the observed
MUSE fields. Since the spectroscopic measurements are limited to relatively
bright sources, we developed a multi-band photometric procedure to identify
additional GC candidates too faint for spectroscopic confirmation. GC
candidates were selected using a combination of photometric properties and
morphometric criteria. Additionally, the $H$-band observations were used to
constrain the stellar masses of the studied galaxies. Based on the
spectroscopic classification, we confirm one GC in UDG3, two in UDG7, and four
in UDG11, while UDG9 has no spectroscopically confirmed bright GCs. We identify
four intra-cluster GCs in the vicinity of UDG3 and UDG11, and one ultra-compact
dwarf with a radial velocity only $\Delta v = -85 \pm 10\mathrm{km\ s^{-1}}$
relative to UDG7, suggesting it may be bound to it. Considering completeness
corrections and accounting for possible contamination, from photometry we
estimate that the number of GCs ranges between 0 and $\sim40$ for the
investigated UDGs. Their specific frequencies suggest that three out of four
UDGs are either GC-rich, similar to those in the Coma cluster, or belong to an
intermediate population as seen in the Perseus cluster. Dark matter content
estimates, inferred from GC counts and stellar mass, indicate that these
galaxies are dark-matter dominated, with dynamical-to-stellar mass ratios of
$M_{\mathrm{dyn}} / M_\star \sim 10-1000$.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Marco Mirabile</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Michele Cantiello</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Marina Rejkuba</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Steffen Mieske</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Enrichetta Iodice</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Chiara Buttitta</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Maria Luisa Buzzo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Johanna Hartke</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Goran Doll</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Luca Rossi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Magda Arnaboldi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Marica Branchesi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Giuseppe D'Ago</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jesus Falcon-Barroso</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Katja Fahrion</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Duncan A. Forbes</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Marco Gullieuszik</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Michael Hilker</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Felipe S. Lohmann</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Maurizio Paolillo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Gabriele Riccio</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Richtler</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Marilena Spavone</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">25 pages, 24 figures, 7 tables. Accepted for publication in A&amp;A</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14206v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2509.14206v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14204v1</id>
    <updated>2025-09-17T17:36:17Z</updated>
    <published>2025-09-17T17:36:17Z</published>
    <title>Large deviations for probability graphons</title>
    <summary>  We establish a large deviation principle (LDP) for probability graphons,
which are symmetric functions from the unit square into the space of
probability measures. This notion extends classical graphons and provides a
flexible framework for studying the limit behavior of large dense weighted
graphs. In particular, our result generalizes the seminal work of Chatterjee
and Varadhan (2011), who derived an LDP for Erd\H{o}s-R\'enyi random graphs via
graphon theory. We move beyond their binary (Bernoulli) setting to encompass
arbitrary edge-weight distributions. Specifically, we analyze the distribution
on probability graphons induced by random weighted graphs in which edges are
sampled independently from a common reference probability measure supported on
a compact Polish space. We prove that this distribution satisfies an LDP with a
good rate function, expressed as an extension of the Kullback-Leibler
divergence between probability graphons and the reference measure. This theorem
can also be viewed as a Sanov-type result in the graphon setting. Our work
provides a rigorous foundation for analyzing rare events in weighted networks
and supports statistical inference in structured random graph models under
distributional edge uncertainty.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Pierfrancesco Dionigi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Giulio Zucal</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Preprint, comments are very welcome. 55 pages</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14204v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2509.14204v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="math.PR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.PR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.stat-mech" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.FA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.data-an" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="05C80, 60F10 (Primary) 60B20, 60B10, 60C05, 28A33 (Secondary)" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14201v1</id>
    <updated>2025-09-17T17:35:07Z</updated>
    <published>2025-09-17T17:35:07Z</published>
    <title>Active Inference Framework for Closed-Loop Sensing, Communication, and
  Control in UAV Systems</title>
    <summary>  Integrated sensing and communication (ISAC) is a core technology for 6G, and
its application to closed-loop sensing, communication, and control (SCC)
enables various services. Existing SCC solutions often treat sensing and
control separately, leading to suboptimal performance and resource usage. In
this work, we introduce the active inference framework (AIF) into SCC-enabled
unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV) systems for joint state estimation, control, and
sensing resource allocation. By formulating a unified generative model, the
problem reduces to minimizing variational free energy for inference and
expected free energy for action planning. Simulation results show that both
control cost and sensing cost are reduced relative to baselines.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Guangjin Pan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Liping Bai</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zhuojun Tian</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hui Chen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mehdi Bennis</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Henk Wymeersch</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">5 pages, 2 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14201v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2509.14201v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="eess.SP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="eess.SP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.NI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.SY" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="eess.SY" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14183v1</id>
    <updated>2025-09-17T17:16:57Z</updated>
    <published>2025-09-17T17:16:57Z</published>
    <title>Index Date Imputation For Survival Outcomes for Externally Controlled
  Trials</title>
    <summary>  Externally controlled trials (ECTs) compare outcomes between a single-arm
trial and external controls drawn from sources such as historical trials,
registries, or observational studies. In survival analysis, a major challenge
arises when the time origin (index date) differs across groups, for example,
when treatment initiation occurs after a delay in the single-arm trial but is
undefined in the external controls. This misalignment can bias treatment effect
estimates and distort causal interpretation. We propose a novel statistical
method, Index Date Imputation (IDI), that imputes comparable index dates for
external control patients using the estimated distribution of treatment
initiation times from the single-arm cohort. To address population-level
confounding, IDI is combined with propensity score weighting or matching,
yielding balanced and temporally aligned cohorts for survival comparison. We
detail diagnostics for covariate balance and truncation bias, and evaluate
performance via extensive simulations. Applying IDI to a randomized oncology
trial, we demonstrate that the method recovers the known treatment effect
despite artificial index date misalignment. IDI provides a principled framework
for time-to-event analyses in ECTs and is broadly applicable in oncology and
rare disease settings.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Q. Le Coent</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>G. L. Rosner</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>M-C. Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>C. Hu</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14183v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2509.14183v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="stat.ME" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ME" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.AP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14166v1</id>
    <updated>2025-09-17T16:49:46Z</updated>
    <published>2025-09-17T16:49:46Z</published>
    <title>Reaction-diffusion models of invasive tree pest spread: quantifying the
  spread of oak processionary moth in the UK</title>
    <summary>  UK woodlands, forests, and urban treescapes are under threat from invasive
species, exacerbated by climate change, trade, and transport. Invasive tree
pests debilitate their host and disrupt forest ecosystems, thus it is
imperative to quantitatively model and predict their spread. Addressing this,
we represent the spatial distribution of the pest as a population density field
which evolves according to a spatiotemporal reaction-diffusion equation. We
solve this intractable system of equations numerically and, from the solution,
we determine first arrival times of the pest at locations in the field. The
adopted model permits us to obtain the expansion rate of pest spread directly
from the model parameters, which we infer in the Bayesian paradigm, using a
Markov chain Monte Carlo scheme. We apply our framework to the ongoing spread
of oak processionary moth in the UK, an outbreak which continues to grow
despite management efforts. We demonstrate that our approach effectively
captures the spread of the pest and that this has occurred at a non-constant
expansion rate. The proposed framework is a powerful tool for quantitatively
modelling the spread of an invasive tree pest and could underpin future
prediction and management approaches.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Jamie P. McKeown</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Laura E. Wadkin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Nick G. Parker</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Golightly</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew W. Baggaley</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">19 pages, 8 figures, 2 tables</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14166v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2509.14166v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="q-bio.PE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="q-bio.PE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="q-bio.QM" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="92D40, 92-10" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14165v1</id>
    <updated>2025-09-17T16:48:00Z</updated>
    <published>2025-09-17T16:48:00Z</published>
    <title>Where Do Tokens Go? Understanding Pruning Behaviors in STEP at High
  Resolutions</title>
    <summary>  Vision Transformers (ViTs) achieve state-of-the-art performance in semantic
segmentation but are hindered by high computational and memory costs. To
address this, we propose STEP (SuperToken and Early-Pruning), a hybrid
token-reduction framework that combines dynamic patch merging and token pruning
to enhance efficiency without significantly compromising accuracy. At the core
of STEP is dCTS, a lightweight CNN-based policy network that enables flexible
merging into superpatches. Encoder blocks integrate also early-exits to remove
high-confident supertokens, lowering computational load. We evaluate our method
on high-resolution semantic segmentation benchmarks, including images up to
1024 x 1024, and show that when dCTS is applied alone, the token count can be
reduced by a factor of 2.5 compared to the standard 16 x 16 pixel patching
scheme. This yields a 2.6x reduction in computational cost and a 3.4x increase
in throughput when using ViT-Large as the backbone. Applying the full STEP
framework further improves efficiency, reaching up to a 4x reduction in
computational complexity and a 1.7x gain in inference speed, with a maximum
accuracy drop of no more than 2.0%. With the proposed STEP configurations, up
to 40% of tokens can be confidently predicted and halted before reaching the
final encoder layer.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Michal Szczepanski</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Martyna Poreba</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Karim Haroun</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.14165v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2509.14165v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
