<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Last updated: 2025-06-13T00:58:10Z -->
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3Dall%3Acausal%20inference%26id_list%3D%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=all:causal inference&amp;id_list=&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/SsRksLzRb0LuVhSmQ+N8WbAs+f8</id>
  <updated>2025-06-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">114828</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2506.09996v1</id>
    <updated>2025-06-11T17:59:58Z</updated>
    <published>2025-06-11T17:59:58Z</published>
    <title>From Judgment to Interference: Early Stopping LLM Harmful Outputs via
  Streaming Content Monitoring</title>
    <summary>  Though safety alignment has been applied to most large language models
(LLMs), LLM service providers generally deploy a subsequent moderation as the
external safety guardrail in real-world products. Existing moderators mainly
practice a conventional full detection, which determines the harmfulness based
on the complete LLM output, causing high service latency. Recent works pay more
attention to partial detection where moderators oversee the generation midway
and early stop the output if harmfulness is detected, but they directly apply
moderators trained with the full detection paradigm to incomplete outputs,
introducing a training-inference gap that lowers the performance. In this
paper, we explore how to form a data-and-model solution that natively supports
partial detection. For the data, we construct FineHarm, a dataset consisting of
29K prompt-response pairs with fine-grained annotations to provide reasonable
supervision for token-level training. Then, we propose the streaming content
monitor, which is trained with dual supervision of response- and token-level
labels and can follow the output stream of LLM to make a timely judgment of
harmfulness. Experiments show that SCM gains 0.95+ in macro F1 score that is
comparable to full detection, by only seeing the first 18% of tokens in
responses on average. Moreover, the SCM can serve as a pseudo-harmfulness
annotator for improving safety alignment and lead to a higher harmlessness
score than DPO.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Yang Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Qiang Sheng</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yehan Yang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xueyao Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Cao</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">22 pages, 7 figures, and 9 tables</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2506.09996v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2506.09996v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CY" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2506.09991v1</id>
    <updated>2025-06-11T17:59:23Z</updated>
    <published>2025-06-11T17:59:23Z</published>
    <title>Multiverse: Your Language Models Secretly Decide How to Parallelize and
  Merge Generation</title>
    <summary>  Autoregressive Large Language Models (AR-LLMs) frequently exhibit implicit
parallelism in sequential generation. Inspired by this, we introduce
Multiverse, a new generative model that enables natively parallel generation.
Multiverse internalizes a MapReduce paradigm, generating automatically through
three stages: (i) a Map stage for adaptive task decomposition, (ii) a Process
stage for parallel subtask execution, and (iii) a Reduce stage for lossless
result synthesis. Next, we build a real-world Multiverse reasoning model with
co-design of data, algorithm, and system, enabling rapid and seamless transfer
from frontier AR-LLMs. Starting from sequential reasoning chains, we create
Multiverse 1K by converting them into structured training data using an
automated LLM-assisted pipeline, avoiding costly human annotations.
Algorithmically, we design Multiverse Attention to separate parallel reasoning
steps while keeping compatibility with causal attention for efficient training.
Systematically, we implement Multiverse Engine to enable parallel inference. It
features a dedicated scheduler that dynamically switches between sequential and
parallel generation, triggered directly by the model. After a 3-hour
fine-tuning with 1K examples, our Multiverse-32B stands as the only
open-sourced non-AR model achieving performance on par with leading AR-LLMs of
the same scale, evidenced by AIME24 &amp; 25 scores of 54% and 46%, respectively.
Moreover, our budget control experiments show that Multiverse-32B exhibits
superior scaling, outperforming AR-LLMs by 1.87% on average using the same
context length. Such scaling further leads to practical efficiency gain,
achieving up to 2x speedup across varying batch sizes. We have open-sourced the
entire Multiverse ecosystem, including data, model weights, engine, supporting
tools, as well as complete data curation prompts and detailed training and
evaluation recipes.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Xinyu Yang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yuwei An</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hongyi Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tianqi Chen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Beidi Chen</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2506.09991v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2506.09991v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2506.09984v1</id>
    <updated>2025-06-11T17:57:09Z</updated>
    <published>2025-06-11T17:57:09Z</published>
    <title>InterActHuman: Multi-Concept Human Animation with Layout-Aligned Audio
  Conditions</title>
    <summary>  End-to-end human animation with rich multi-modal conditions, e.g., text,
image and audio has achieved remarkable advancements in recent years. However,
most existing methods could only animate a single subject and inject conditions
in a global manner, ignoring scenarios that multiple concepts could appears in
the same video with rich human-human interactions and human-object
interactions. Such global assumption prevents precise and per-identity control
of multiple concepts including humans and objects, therefore hinders
applications. In this work, we discard the single-entity assumption and
introduce a novel framework that enforces strong, region-specific binding of
conditions from modalities to each identity's spatiotemporal footprint. Given
reference images of multiple concepts, our method could automatically infer
layout information by leveraging a mask predictor to match appearance cues
between the denoised video and each reference appearance. Furthermore, we
inject local audio condition into its corresponding region to ensure
layout-aligned modality matching in a iterative manner. This design enables the
high-quality generation of controllable multi-concept human-centric videos.
Empirical results and ablation studies validate the effectiveness of our
explicit layout control for multi-modal conditions compared to implicit
counterparts and other existing methods.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Zhenzhi Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jiaqi Yang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jianwen Jiang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Chao Liang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Gaojie Lin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zerong Zheng</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ceyuan Yang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Dahua Lin</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">TL;DR: The first multi-person dialogue video generation method from
  pairs of reference image and audio via explicit layout-aligned condition
  injection. See project page https://zhenzhiwang.github.io/interacthuman/ for
  more details</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2506.09984v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2506.09984v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.SD" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2506.09958v1</id>
    <updated>2025-06-11T17:31:38Z</updated>
    <published>2025-06-11T17:31:38Z</published>
    <title>Kvasir-VQA-x1: A Multimodal Dataset for Medical Reasoning and Robust
  MedVQA in Gastrointestinal Endoscopy</title>
    <summary>  Medical Visual Question Answering (MedVQA) is a promising field for
developing clinical decision support systems, yet progress is often limited by
the available datasets, which can lack clinical complexity and visual
diversity. To address these gaps, we introduce Kvasir-VQA-x1, a new,
large-scale dataset for gastrointestinal (GI) endoscopy. Our work significantly
expands upon the original Kvasir-VQA by incorporating 159,549 new
question-answer pairs that are designed to test deeper clinical reasoning. We
developed a systematic method using large language models to generate these
questions, which are stratified by complexity to better assess a model's
inference capabilities. To ensure our dataset prepares models for real-world
clinical scenarios, we have also introduced a variety of visual augmentations
that mimic common imaging artifacts. The dataset is structured to support two
main evaluation tracks: one for standard VQA performance and another to test
model robustness against these visual perturbations. By providing a more
challenging and clinically relevant benchmark, Kvasir-VQA-x1 aims to accelerate
the development of more reliable and effective multimodal AI systems for use in
clinical settings. The dataset is fully accessible and adheres to FAIR data
principles, making it a valuable resource for the wider research community.
Code and data: https://github.com/Simula/Kvasir-VQA-x1 and
https://huggingface.co/datasets/SimulaMet/Kvasir-VQA-x1
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Sushant Gautam</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Michael A. Riegler</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Pål Halvorsen</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2506.09958v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2506.09958v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="68T45 (Machine learning), 92C55 (Biomedical imaging and signal&#10;  processing) 68T45 (Machine learning), 92C55 (Biomedical imaging and signal&#10;  processing)" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="I.2.10; I.2.6; J.3" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2506.09943v1</id>
    <updated>2025-06-11T17:10:36Z</updated>
    <published>2025-06-11T17:10:36Z</published>
    <title>CausalVQA: A Physically Grounded Causal Reasoning Benchmark for Video
  Models</title>
    <summary>  We introduce CausalVQA, a benchmark dataset for video question answering
(VQA) composed of question-answer pairs that probe models' understanding of
causality in the physical world. Existing VQA benchmarks either tend to focus
on surface perceptual understanding of real-world videos, or on narrow physical
reasoning questions created using simulation environments. CausalVQA fills an
important gap by presenting challenging questions that are grounded in
real-world scenarios, while focusing on models' ability to predict the likely
outcomes of different actions and events through five question types:
counterfactual, hypothetical, anticipation, planning and descriptive. We
designed quality control mechanisms that prevent models from exploiting trivial
shortcuts, requiring models to base their answers on deep visual understanding
instead of linguistic cues. We find that current frontier multimodal models
fall substantially below human performance on the benchmark, especially on
anticipation and hypothetical questions. This highlights a challenge for
current systems to leverage spatial-temporal reasoning, understanding of
physical principles, and comprehension of possible alternatives to make
accurate predictions in real-world settings.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Aaron Foss</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Chloe Evans</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sasha Mitts</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Koustuv Sinha</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ammar Rizvi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Justine T. Kao</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">35 pages, 3 figures, Submitted to NeurIPS2025 benchmark track</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2506.09943v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2506.09943v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="I.2.10; I.4.8" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2506.09928v1</id>
    <updated>2025-06-11T16:51:07Z</updated>
    <published>2025-06-11T16:51:07Z</published>
    <title>Bayesian Probabilistic Matrix Factorization</title>
    <summary>  Matrix factorization is a widely used technique in recommendation systems.
Probabilistic Matrix Factorization (PMF) [1] extends traditional matrix
factorization by incorporating probability distributions over latent factors,
allowing for uncertainty quantification. However, computing the posterior
distribution is intractable due to the high-dimensional integral. To address
this, we employ two Bayesian inference methods: Markov Chain Monte Carlo (MCMC)
[2] and Variational Inference (VI) [3] to approximate the posterior. We
evaluate their performance on MovieLens dataset and compare their convergence
speed, predictive accuracy, and computational efficiency. Experimental results
demonstrate that VI offers faster convergence, while MCMC provides more
accurate posterior estimates.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ruixuan Xu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xiangxiang Weng</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">11 pages, 4 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2506.09928v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2506.09928v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2506.09925v1</id>
    <updated>2025-06-11T16:49:15Z</updated>
    <published>2025-06-11T16:49:15Z</published>
    <title>Emergent anisotropic three-phase order in critically doped
  superconducting diamond films</title>
    <summary>  Two decades since its discovery, superconducting heavily boron-doped diamond
(HBDD) still presents unresolved fundamental questions whose resolution is
relevant to the development of this material for quantum technologies. We use
electrical magnetotransport measurements of critically-doped homoepitaxial
single crystal HBDD films to reveal signatures of intrinsic (electronic)
granular superconductivity. By studying the dependence of electrical
resistivity on temperature and magnetic field vector, we infer that this
granularity arises from electron correlations. This is revealed by a striking
three-phase anisotropy in the magnetoresistance, accompanied by a spontaneous
transverse voltage (Hall anomaly). Our findings indicate an emergent
magnetically tunable intrinsic order in an otherwise isotropic three
dimensional single crystal HBDD film, offering new insights into the mechanism
of superconductivity in this quantum material.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Jyotirmay Dwivedi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jake Morris</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Saurav Islam</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kalana D. Halanayake</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Gabriel A. Vazquez-Lizardi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>David Snyder</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Anthony Richardella</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Luke Lyle</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Danielle Reifsnyder Hickey</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Nazar Delegan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>F. Joseph Heremans</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>David D. Awschalom</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Nitin Samarth</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2506.09925v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2506.09925v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cond-mat.supr-con" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.supr-con" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2506.09923v1</id>
    <updated>2025-06-11T16:43:36Z</updated>
    <published>2025-06-11T16:43:36Z</published>
    <title>Apollo: A Posteriori Label-Only Membership Inference Attack Towards
  Machine Unlearning</title>
    <summary>  Machine Unlearning (MU) aims to update Machine Learning (ML) models following
requests to remove training samples and their influences on a trained model
efficiently without retraining the original ML model from scratch. While MU
itself has been employed to provide privacy protection and regulatory
compliance, it can also increase the attack surface of the model. Existing
privacy inference attacks towards MU that aim to infer properties of the
unlearned set rely on the weaker threat model that assumes the attacker has
access to both the unlearned model and the original model, limiting their
feasibility toward real-life scenarios. We propose a novel privacy attack, A
Posteriori Label-Only Membership Inference Attack towards MU, Apollo, that
infers whether a data sample has been unlearned, following a strict threat
model where an adversary has access to the label-output of the unlearned model
only. We demonstrate that our proposed attack, while requiring less access to
the target model compared to previous attacks, can achieve relatively high
precision on the membership status of the unlearned samples.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Liou Tang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>James Joshi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ashish Kundu</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2506.09923v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2506.09923v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2506.09916v1</id>
    <updated>2025-06-11T16:33:09Z</updated>
    <published>2025-06-11T16:33:09Z</published>
    <title>Only-Style: Stylistic Consistency in Image Generation without Content
  Leakage</title>
    <summary>  Generating images in a consistent reference visual style remains a
challenging computer vision task. State-of-the-art methods aiming for
style-consistent generation struggle to effectively separate semantic content
from stylistic elements, leading to content leakage from the image provided as
a reference to the targets. To address this challenge, we propose Only-Style: a
method designed to mitigate content leakage in a semantically coherent manner
while preserving stylistic consistency. Only-Style works by localizing content
leakage during inference, allowing the adaptive tuning of a parameter that
controls the style alignment process, specifically within the image patches
containing the subject in the reference image. This adaptive process best
balances stylistic consistency with leakage elimination. Moreover, the
localization of content leakage can function as a standalone component, given a
reference-target image pair, allowing the adaptive tuning of any
method-specific parameter that provides control over the impact of the
stylistic reference. In addition, we propose a novel evaluation framework to
quantify the success of style-consistent generations in avoiding undesired
content leakage. Our approach demonstrates a significant improvement over
state-of-the-art methods through extensive evaluation across diverse instances,
consistently achieving robust stylistic consistency without undesired content
leakage.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Tilemachos Aravanis</name>
      <arxiv:affiliation xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">School of Electrical &amp; Computer Engineering, National Technical University of Athens, Greece</arxiv:affiliation>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Panagiotis Filntisis</name>
      <arxiv:affiliation xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Robotics Institute, Athena Research Center, Maroussi, Greece</arxiv:affiliation>
      <arxiv:affiliation xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">HERON - Center of Excellence in Robotics, Athens, Greece</arxiv:affiliation>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Petros Maragos</name>
      <arxiv:affiliation xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">School of Electrical &amp; Computer Engineering, National Technical University of Athens, Greece</arxiv:affiliation>
      <arxiv:affiliation xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Robotics Institute, Athena Research Center, Maroussi, Greece</arxiv:affiliation>
      <arxiv:affiliation xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">HERON - Center of Excellence in Robotics, Athens, Greece</arxiv:affiliation>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>George Retsinas</name>
      <arxiv:affiliation xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Robotics Institute, Athena Research Center, Maroussi, Greece</arxiv:affiliation>
      <arxiv:affiliation xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">HERON - Center of Excellence in Robotics, Athens, Greece</arxiv:affiliation>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2506.09916v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2506.09916v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2506.09891v1</id>
    <updated>2025-06-11T16:00:55Z</updated>
    <published>2025-06-11T16:00:55Z</published>
    <title>Causal Climate Emulation with Bayesian Filtering</title>
    <summary>  Traditional models of climate change use complex systems of coupled equations
to simulate physical processes across the Earth system. These simulations are
highly computationally expensive, limiting our predictions of climate change
and analyses of its causes and effects. Machine learning has the potential to
quickly emulate data from climate models, but current approaches are not able
to incorporate physics-informed causal relationships. Here, we develop an
interpretable climate model emulator based on causal representation learning.
We derive a physics-informed approach including a Bayesian filter for stable
long-term autoregressive emulation. We demonstrate that our emulator learns
accurate climate dynamics, and we show the importance of each one of its
components on a realistic synthetic dataset and data from two widely deployed
climate models.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Sebastian Hickman</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ilija Trajkovic</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Julia Kaltenborn</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Francis Pelletier</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alex Archibald</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yaniv Gurwicz</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Peer Nowack</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>David Rolnick</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Julien Boussard</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">32 pages, 21 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2506.09891v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2506.09891v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.ao-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
