<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Last updated: 2025-09-23T00:52:06Z -->
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3Dall%3Acausal%20inference%26id_list%3D%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=all:causal inference&amp;id_list=&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/SsRksLzRb0LuVhSmQ+N8WbAs+f8</id>
  <updated>2025-09-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">121343</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.16202v1</id>
    <updated>2025-09-19T17:59:12Z</updated>
    <published>2025-09-19T17:59:12Z</published>
    <title>Sound-Horizon-Agnostic Inference of the Hubble Constant and Neutrino
  Mass from BAO, CMB Lensing, and Galaxy Weak Lensing and Clustering</title>
    <summary>  We present a sound-horizon-agnostic determination of the Hubble constant,
$H_0$, by combining DESI DR2 baryon acoustic oscillation (BAO) data with the
latest cosmic microwave background (CMB) lensing measurements from Planck, ACT,
and SPT-3G, the angular size of the CMB acoustic scale, Dark Energy Survey
Year-3 ($3\times2$-pt) galaxy weak lensing and clustering correlations, and the
Pantheon+ supernova sample. In this analysis, the sound horizon at the drag
epoch, $r_d$, is treated as a free parameter, avoiding assumptions about
early-Universe physics. By combining uncalibrated comoving distances from BAO
and supernovae with constraints on the matter density $\Omega_m h^2$ from CMB
and galaxy lensing/clustering, we break the $r_d$-$H_0$ degeneracy and obtain
$H_0 = 70.0 \pm 1.7$ km/s/Mpc when the sum of the neutrino masses is fixed at
$\Sigma m_\nu = 0.06$ eV. With a conservative prior on the amplitude of
primordial fluctuations, $A_s$, we find $H_0 = 70.03 \pm 0.97$ km/s/Mpc and
$r_d = 144.8 \pm 1.6$ Mpc. Allowing $\Sigma m_\nu$ to vary yields $H_0 =
75.3^{+3.3}_{-4.0}$ km/s/Mpc and $\Sigma m_\nu = 0.55^{+0.23}_{-0.37}$ ($&lt;1.11$
eV) at 68% (95%) CL, and $H_0 = 73.9 \pm 2.2$ km/s/Mpc with $\Sigma m_\nu =
0.46^{+0.21}_{-0.25}$ ($=0.46^{+0.40}_{-0.45}$ eV) at 68% (95%) CL when a prior
on $A_s$ is applied. Forecasts for the completed DESI BAO program, combined
with Simons-Observatory-like CMB lensing, next-generation $3\times2$-pt data,
and expanded supernova samples predict $\sigma(H_0) \simeq 0.67$ km/s/Mpc with
fixed $\Sigma m_\nu$, and $\sigma(H_0) \simeq 1.1$ km/s/Mpc with $\Sigma m_\nu
&lt; 0.133$ ($&lt;0.263$) eV at 68% (95%) CL when the neutrino mass is varied. As the
precision of BAO, CMB lensing, and galaxy lensing/clustering improve, this
$r_d$-agnostic framework will provide an independent test of the need for new
physics at recombination.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Helena García Escudero</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Seyed Hamidreza Mirpoorian</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Levon Pogosian</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">14 pages, 5 figures, 3 tables</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.16202v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2509.16202v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="astro-ph.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.16195v1</id>
    <updated>2025-09-19T17:57:13Z</updated>
    <published>2025-09-19T17:57:13Z</published>
    <title>FocalCodec-Stream: Streaming Low-Bitrate Speech Coding via Causal
  Distillation</title>
    <summary>  Neural audio codecs are a fundamental component of modern generative audio
pipelines. Although recent codecs achieve strong low-bitrate reconstruction and
provide powerful representations for downstream tasks, most are non-streamable,
limiting their use in real-time applications. We present FocalCodec-Stream, a
hybrid codec based on focal modulation that compresses speech into a single
binary codebook at 0.55 - 0.80 kbps with a theoretical latency of 80 ms. Our
approach combines multi-stage causal distillation of WavLM with targeted
architectural improvements, including a lightweight refiner module that
enhances quality under latency constraints. Experiments show that
FocalCodec-Stream outperforms existing streamable codecs at comparable
bitrates, while preserving both semantic and acoustic information. The result
is a favorable trade-off between reconstruction quality, downstream task
performance, latency, and efficiency. Code and checkpoints will be released at
https://github.com/lucadellalib/focalcodec.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Luca Della Libera</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Cem Subakan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mirco Ravanelli</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">5 pages, 1 figure</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.16195v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2509.16195v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.SD" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.SD" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="eess.AS" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.16191v1</id>
    <updated>2025-09-19T17:50:44Z</updated>
    <published>2025-09-19T17:50:44Z</published>
    <title>Binary-lens Microlensing Degeneracy: Impact on Planetary Sensitivity and
  Mass-ratio Function</title>
    <summary>  Gravitational microlensing is a unique method for discovering cold planets
across a broad mass range. Reliable statistics of the microlensing planets
require accurate sensitivity estimates. However, the impact of the degeneracies
in binary-lens single-source (2L1S) models that affect many actual planet
detections is often omitted in sensitivity estimates, leading to potential
self-inconsistency of the statistics studies. In this work, we evaluate the
effect of the 2L1S degeneracies on planetary sensitivity by simulating a series
of typical microlensing events and comprehensively replicating a realistic
planet detection pipeline, including the anomaly identification, global 2L1S
model search, and degenerate model comparison. We find that for a pure-survey
statistical sample, the 2L1S degeneracies reduce the overall planetary
sensitivity by $5\sim10\%$, with the effect increasing at higher planet-host
mass ratios. This bias leads to an underestimation of planet occurrence rates
and a flattening of the inferred mass-ratio function slope. This effect will be
critical for upcoming space-based microlensing surveys like the Roman or Earth
2.0 missions, which are expected to discover $\mathcal{O}(10^3)$ planets. We
also discuss the computational challenges and propose potential approaches for
future applications.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Yuxin Shang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hongjing Yang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jiyuan Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Shude Mao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Gould</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Weicheng Zang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Qiyue Qian</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jennifer C. Yee</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">submitted to AAS, 18 pages, 9 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.16191v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2509.16191v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="astro-ph.EP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.EP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.IM" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.SR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.16177v1</id>
    <updated>2025-09-19T17:39:28Z</updated>
    <published>2025-09-19T17:39:28Z</published>
    <title>Sequential analysis in a continuous spin-noise quantum sensor</title>
    <summary>  Many control and detection applications require real-time analysis of signals
from sensors, in order to quickly and accurately act upon events revealed by
the sensors. Such signal analysis benefits from statistical models of signal
and sensor behavior. This creates a need for data analysis methods that are
simultaneously model-based, computationally efficient and causal, in the sense
that they employ only sensor data available prior to a specific point in time.
In this work, we implement sequential data analysis techniques on a
spin-noise-based quantum sensor, to perform two key tasks: hypothesis testing
and quickest change-point detection. These online protocols allow us to detect
weak magnetic fields by adaptively collecting measurement data until a
predefined confidence threshold is reached. We demonstrate these methods in a
realistic experimental setting and derive performance bounds for the achievable
precision and response time. Our approach has potential utility when detecting
small perturbations to the magnetic field, in both applied and fundamental
contexts including biomagnetism, geophysical surveys, detection of concealed
materials, searches for dark matter candidates and exotic spin interactions.
Our results demonstrate that sequential techniques enable faster and more
sensitive detection, making them a powerful tool for quantum sensing.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Elisabet Roda-Salichs</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Giulio Gasbarri</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Antoni Alou</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Michalis Skotiniotis</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Aleksandra Sierant</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Diana Méndez-Avalos</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Morgan W. Mitchell</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>John Calsamiglia</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">20 + 13 pages</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.16177v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2509.16177v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.16170v1</id>
    <updated>2025-09-19T17:29:25Z</updated>
    <published>2025-09-19T17:29:25Z</published>
    <title>UniMRSeg: Unified Modality-Relax Segmentation via Hierarchical
  Self-Supervised Compensation</title>
    <summary>  Multi-modal image segmentation faces real-world deployment challenges from
incomplete/corrupted modalities degrading performance. While existing methods
address training-inference modality gaps via specialized per-combination
models, they introduce high deployment costs by requiring exhaustive model
subsets and model-modality matching. In this work, we propose a unified
modality-relax segmentation network (UniMRSeg) through hierarchical
self-supervised compensation (HSSC). Our approach hierarchically bridges
representation gaps between complete and incomplete modalities across input,
feature and output levels. % First, we adopt modality reconstruction with the
hybrid shuffled-masking augmentation, encouraging the model to learn the
intrinsic modality characteristics and generate meaningful representations for
missing modalities through cross-modal fusion. % Next, modality-invariant
contrastive learning implicitly compensates the feature space distance among
incomplete-complete modality pairs. Furthermore, the proposed lightweight
reverse attention adapter explicitly compensates for the weak perceptual
semantics in the frozen encoder. Last, UniMRSeg is fine-tuned under the hybrid
consistency constraint to ensure stable prediction under all modality
combinations without large performance fluctuations. Without bells and
whistles, UniMRSeg significantly outperforms the state-of-the-art methods under
diverse missing modality scenarios on MRI-based brain tumor segmentation, RGB-D
semantic segmentation, RGB-D/T salient object segmentation. The code will be
released at https://github.com/Xiaoqi-Zhao-DLUT/UniMRSeg.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Xiaoqi Zhao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Youwei Pang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Chenyang Yu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lihe Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Huchuan Lu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Shijian Lu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Georges El Fakhri</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xiaofeng Liu</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Accepted by NeurIPS 2025</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.16170v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2509.16170v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.16132v1</id>
    <updated>2025-09-19T16:31:05Z</updated>
    <published>2025-09-19T16:31:05Z</published>
    <title>Recovering Parametric Scenes from Very Few Time-of-Flight Pixels</title>
    <summary>  We aim to recover the geometry of 3D parametric scenes using very few depth
measurements from low-cost, commercially available time-of-flight sensors.
These sensors offer very low spatial resolution (i.e., a single pixel), but
image a wide field-of-view per pixel and capture detailed time-of-flight data
in the form of time-resolved photon counts. This time-of-flight data encodes
rich scene information and thus enables recovery of simple scenes from sparse
measurements. We investigate the feasibility of using a distributed set of few
measurements (e.g., as few as 15 pixels) to recover the geometry of simple
parametric scenes with a strong prior, such as estimating the 6D pose of a
known object. To achieve this, we design a method that utilizes both
feed-forward prediction to infer scene parameters, and differentiable rendering
within an analysis-by-synthesis framework to refine the scene parameter
estimate. We develop hardware prototypes and demonstrate that our method
effectively recovers object pose given an untextured 3D model in both
simulations and controlled real-world captures, and show promising initial
results for other parametric scenes. We additionally conduct experiments to
explore the limits and capabilities of our imaging solution.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Carter Sifferman</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yiquan Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yiming Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Fangzhou Mu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Michael Gleicher</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mohit Gupta</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yin Li</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">ICCV 2025</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.16132v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2509.16132v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.16119v1</id>
    <updated>2025-09-19T16:13:09Z</updated>
    <published>2025-09-19T16:13:09Z</published>
    <title>RadarGaussianDet3D: An Efficient and Effective Gaussian-based 3D
  Detector with 4D Automotive Radars</title>
    <summary>  4D automotive radars have gained increasing attention for autonomous driving
due to their low cost, robustness, and inherent velocity measurement
capability. However, existing 4D radar-based 3D detectors rely heavily on
pillar encoders for BEV feature extraction, where each point contributes to
only a single BEV grid, resulting in sparse feature maps and degraded
representation quality. In addition, they also optimize bounding box attributes
independently, leading to sub-optimal detection accuracy. Moreover, their
inference speed, while sufficient for high-end GPUs, may fail to meet the
real-time requirement on vehicle-mounted embedded devices. To overcome these
limitations, an efficient and effective Gaussian-based 3D detector, namely
RadarGaussianDet3D is introduced, leveraging Gaussian primitives and
distributions as intermediate representations for radar points and bounding
boxes. In RadarGaussianDet3D, a novel Point Gaussian Encoder (PGE) is designed
to transform each point into a Gaussian primitive after feature aggregation and
employs the 3D Gaussian Splatting (3DGS) technique for BEV rasterization,
yielding denser feature maps. PGE exhibits exceptionally low latency, owing to
the optimized algorithm for point feature aggregation and fast rendering of
3DGS. In addition, a new Box Gaussian Loss (BGL) is proposed, which converts
bounding boxes into 3D Gaussian distributions and measures their distance to
enable more comprehensive and consistent optimization. Extensive experiments on
TJ4DRadSet and View-of-Delft demonstrate that RadarGaussianDet3D achieves
state-of-the-art detection accuracy while delivering substantially faster
inference, highlighting its potential for real-time deployment in autonomous
driving.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Weiyi Xiong</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Bing Zhu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tao Huang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zewei Zheng</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.16119v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2509.16119v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.16111v1</id>
    <updated>2025-09-19T15:54:41Z</updated>
    <published>2025-09-19T15:54:41Z</published>
    <title>The Nature of High-Redshift Massive Quiescent Galaxies -- Searching for
  RUBIES-UDS-QG-z7 in FLARES</title>
    <summary>  RUBIES-UDS-QG-z7 (RQG) is the earliest massive quiescent galaxy identified to
date, inferred to have formed its abundant stellar mass in a single burst that
ceases rapidly before $z \sim 8$. An object of such extreme nature challenges
our understanding of galaxy formation, requiring rapid growth and quenching
mechanisms only 0.6 Gyr after the Big Bang and implying number densities 2 dex
higher than currently predicted by simulations. We use synthetic observables to
identify analogous systems within the First Light And Reionisation Epoch
Simulations (FLARES) and find two massive galaxies dominated by rapidly
quenched bursts. Beyond demonstrating that the current FLARES model is capable
of producing RQG-like systems, these analogues provide a laboratory within
which to study the underlying physics. Their active galactic nuclei (AGN) heat
and expel gas, inducing rapid quenching and preventing timely rejuvenation.
This causes above-average chemical enrichment at a given stellar mass, with
super solar levels predicted for RQG. These metallicities are underestimated by
spectral energy distribution fitting and we show that $\alpha$-enhancement
cannot be solely responsible. Degeneracies with age and dust attenuation appear
the more likely causes. Tensions between observed and simulated number
densities can be alleviated in part by considering systematics, but adjustments
to AGN feedback, such as allowing super-Eddington accretion rates, may be
required for full agreement.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Jack C. Turner</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Will J. Roper</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Aswin P. Vijayan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sophie L. Newman</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Stephen M. Wilkins</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Christopher C. Lovell</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Shihong Liao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Louise T. C. Seeyave</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">15 pages, 12 figures, submitted to MNRAS</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.16111v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2509.16111v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.16094v1</id>
    <updated>2025-09-19T15:38:13Z</updated>
    <published>2025-09-19T15:38:13Z</published>
    <title>The GUAPOS project. VI: the chemical inventory of shocked gas</title>
    <summary>  The study of the chemical composition of star-forming regions is key to
understand the chemical ingredients available during the formation of planetary
systems. Given that the chemical inventory on interstellar dust grains in the
prestellar phases might be altered due to the prostostellar warm-up, an
alternative to infer the chemical composition on the grains could be to observe
regions affected by shocks associated with molecular outflows. Such shocks can
desorb the molecules, and might produce less chemical processing due to shorter
timescales. We present here a detailed study of the chemical reservoir of a
shocked region located in the G31.41+0.31 protocluster using GUAPOS data
(G31.41+0.31 Unbiased ALMA sPectral Observational Survey). We report here the
detection of 30 molecular species (plus 18 isotopologues). We performed a
comparison of the molecular ratios in the shocked region with those derived
towards the hot core of G31.41+0.31, finding that they are poorly correlated,
excepting N-bearing species. Our results confirm observationally that a
different level of chemical alteration is present in hot cores and in shocks.
While the former likely alter the molecular ratios due to thermal processing
during longer timescales, the latter might represent freshly desorbed material
that constitutes a better proxy of the icy mantle composition. The similarity
of molecular ratios between the N-bearing species in the G31.41 shock and the
hot core suggests that these species are desorbed at early evolutionary stages.
Interestingly, we have found that the abundances in the G31.41 shock show
better correlations with other shock-dominated regions (two protostellar
outflows and a Galactic Center molecular cloud). This suggests a negligible
gas-phase chemistry after shock-induced ejection from grains, and that the
ice-mantle composition is similar regardless of the Galactic environment.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Á. López-Gallifa</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>V. M. Rivilla</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>M. T. Beltrán</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>L. Colzi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>F. Fontani</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Á. Sánchez-Monge</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>C. Mininni</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>R. Cesaroni</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>I. Jiménez-Serra</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>S. Viti</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>A. Lorenzani</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Accepted for publication in Astronomy and Astrophysics (A&amp;A)</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.16094v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2509.16094v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.16070v1</id>
    <updated>2025-09-19T15:18:41Z</updated>
    <published>2025-09-19T15:18:41Z</published>
    <title>A Hypothesis-First Framework for Mechanistic Model Evaluation and
  Selection in Neuroimaging</title>
    <summary>  Neuroimaging provides rich measurements of brain structure and neural
activity, but turning these data into mechanistic insight remains difficult.
Statistical models quantify associations without much considerations for how
they arise, whereas bio-realistic models directly embody candidate mechanisms
but remain hard to deploy rigorously without specialized training. We present a
framework that recasts modeling choices as testable mechanistic hypotheses and
supplies a simple protocol for rejecting inappropriate model specifications,
such as under-/over-parameterization or invalid simplifying assumptions, based
on predefined criteria before any parameter inference. The key idea is expected
model behavior under feature generalization constraints: instead of judging a
model solely by how well it fits a specific target feature of interest Y at an
optimal parameter set, we evaluate the model's expected Y output when the model
is constrained to reproduce a broader, or distinct, feature Z over the entire
parameter space. We then assess whether a mirror statistical model, derived
from the model's expected Y outputs, to the empirical statistical model using
standard statistics. In synthetic experiments with known ground truth (Wilson
Cowan dynamics), the framework correctly rejects mis-specified hypotheses,
penalizes unnecessary degrees of freedom, and preserves valid specifications.
This provides a practical, hypothesis-first route to using mechanistic models
for neuroimaging without requiring expert-level methodology.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Dominic Boutet</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sylvain Baillet</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">20 pages, 7 figures, 5 supplemental figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.16070v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2509.16070v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="q-bio.NC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="q-bio.NC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="q-bio.QM" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
