<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Last updated: 2025-11-19T00:56:42Z -->
<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://arxiv.org/api/p6EyKyP4fMY/66n9Ev8E79F7KlI</id>
  <title>arXiv Query: search_query=all:causal OR all:inference&amp;id_list=&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <updated>2025-11-19T00:56:43Z</updated>
  <link href="https://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query=all:causal+OR+all:inference&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10&amp;id_list=" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage>10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <opensearch:totalResults>126432</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex>0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2511.13717v1</id>
    <title>TZ-LLM: Protecting On-Device Large Language Models with Arm TrustZone</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T18:59:20Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.13717v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2511.13717v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Large Language Models (LLMs) deployed on mobile devices offer benefits like user privacy and reduced network latency, but introduce a significant security risk: the leakage of proprietary models to end users.
  To mitigate this risk, we propose a system design for protecting on-device LLMs using Arm Trusted Execution Environment (TEE), TrustZone. Our system addresses two primary challenges: (1) The dilemma between memory efficiency and fast inference (caching model parameters within TEE memory). (2) The lack of efficient and secure Neural Processing Unit (NPU) time-sharing between Rich Execution Environment (REE) and TEE.
  Our approach incorporates two key innovations. First, we employ pipelined restoration, leveraging the deterministic memory access patterns of LLM inference to prefetch parameters on demand, hiding memory allocation, I/O and decryption latency under computation time. Second, we introduce a co-driver design, creating a minimal data plane NPU driver in the TEE that collaborates with the full-fledged REE driver. This reduces the TEE TCB size and eliminates control plane reinitialization overhead during NPU world switches.
  We implemented our system on the emerging OpenHarmony OS and the llama.cpp inference framework, and evaluated it with various LLMs on an Arm Rockchip device. Compared to a strawman TEE baseline lacking our optimizations, our system reduces TTFT by up to 90.9% and increases decoding speed by up to 23.2%.</summary>
    <category term="cs.CR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T18:59:20Z</published>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="cs.CR"/>
    <author>
      <name>Xunjie Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jiacheng Shi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zihan Zhao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yang Yu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zhichao Hua</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jinyu Gu</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2511.13708v1</id>
    <title>The Scatter of the Many Outweighs the Scatter of the Few: Systematic Error Asymmetry in Steeply-Falling Mass Functions for High-Redshift JWST Galaxies</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T18:55:24Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.13708v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2511.13708v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>The discovery of massive, high redshift galaxies with JWST has been argued to challenge $Λ$CDM: such systems would require extremely rare halos and baryon-to-stellar-mass conversion efficiencies unphysically approaching--or exceeding--100%. If confirmed at galaxy formation forbidden efficiencies, these galaxies could signal new physics beyond standard cosmological structure formation. We develop a galaxy model framework that ties the linear power spectrum to the inferred efficiencies of galaxy growth in order to test the structure formation models. In addition, we incorporate multiple sources of error, including (i) observational sample variance, (ii) asymmetric scatter induced by the steepness of the high-mass halo tail, and (iii) systematic uncertainties in stellar mass estimates. We find that the inferred efficiency of star formation is dominated by systematic uncertainties on the spectral energy distribution inferred stellar mass of the JWST detected galaxies. The systematic uncertainty augments the asymmetry in scatter that largely brings the inferred efficiencies to be in line with that expected from early galaxy formation models. Our framework can be used to test $Λ$CDM as errors are reduced and further detections are made.</summary>
    <category term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="hep-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T18:55:24Z</published>
    <arxiv:comment>8 pages, 5 figures, 1 table. Code available at https://github.com/jaykrishnan9121/JWST_Early_Galaxies</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="astro-ph.GA"/>
    <author>
      <name>Jay R. Krishnan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kevork N. Abazajian</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2511.13701v1</id>
    <title>Learning stochasticity: a nonparametric framework for intrinsic noise estimation</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T18:52:05Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.13701v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2511.13701v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Understanding the principles that govern dynamical systems is a central challenge across many scientific domains, including biology and ecology. Incomplete knowledge of nonlinear interactions and stochastic effects often renders bottom-up modeling approaches ineffective, motivating the development of methods that can discover governing equations directly from data. In such contexts, parametric models often struggle without strong prior knowledge, especially when estimating intrinsic noise. Nonetheless, incorporating stochastic effects is often essential for understanding the dynamic behavior of complex systems such as gene regulatory networks and signaling pathways. To address these challenges, we introduce Trine (Three-phase Regression for INtrinsic noisE), a nonparametric, kernel-based framework that infers state-dependent intrinsic noise from time-series data. Trine features a three-stage algorithm that com- bines analytically solvable subproblems with a structured kernel architecture that captures both abrupt noise-driven fluctuations and smooth, state-dependent changes in variance. We validate Trine on biological and ecological systems, demonstrating its ability to uncover hidden dynamics without relying on predefined parametric assumptions. Across several benchmark problems, Trine achieves performance comparable to that of an oracle. Biologically, this oracle can be viewed as an idealized observer capable of directly tracking the random fluctuations in molecular concentrations or reaction events within a cell. The Trine framework thus opens new avenues for understanding how intrinsic noise affects the behavior of complex systems.</summary>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T18:52:05Z</published>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="cs.LG"/>
    <author>
      <name>Gianluigi Pillonetto</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alberto Giaretta</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mauro Bisiacco</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2511.13692v1</id>
    <title>The physical properties of post-mass-transfer binaries</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T18:46:39Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.13692v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2511.13692v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Aims. We present and analyse the detailed physical properties of six binary stellar systems, originally proposed as possible star-black hole binaries on the basis of radial velocities from Gaia's third data release, but soon recognised as likely post-mass-transfer binary systems with stripped companions. Methods. We used multi-epoch high-resolution FEROS spectra and spectral disentangling paired with stellar templates to derive effective temperatures, $T_\mathrm{eff}$; stellar radii, R*; and projected rotational velocities, v$\sin{i}$ for both components in all systems along with the mass ratio, q = $M_\mathrm{accretor}/M_\mathrm{donor}$ and the components' flux ratio as a function of wavelength. Results. Our analysis directly confirms that all systems are post-mass-transfer binaries with two luminous stars, i.e. no black hole companions. Each system contains an A-type accretor component that is rapidly rotating and a cooler very low-mass donor (~ 0.25M$\odot$) that is overluminous. Five of the systems show no trace of any emission lines, implying that there is no current mass transfer, consistent with our inferred radii, in all cases within the Roche volume. The data are generally consistent with stable case AB mass transfer with $β$ (the fraction of mass lost from the accretor) less than 0.7. While the accretor components rotate rapidly, they rotate well below the critical rotation rate, $v_\mathrm{crit}$, even though there must have been enough mass transfer to spin them up to a significant fraction of $v_\mathrm{crit}$, according to theoretical models of angular momentum transfer. As neither magnetic braking nor tidal synchronisation should have been effective in spinning down the stars, our results suggest that either mass accretion does not increase the angular momentum of the accretors to their critical values or the systems never reached these values in the first place.</summary>
    <category term="astro-ph.SR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T18:46:39Z</published>
    <arxiv:comment>Accepted for publication in Astronomy and Astrophysics</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="astro-ph.SR"/>
    <author>
      <name>Rhys Seeburger</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hans-Walter Rix</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kareem El-Badry</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Johanna Müller-Horn</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alex J. Dimoff</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jan Henneco</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jaime I. Villaseñor</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2511.13680v1</id>
    <title>Cross-Learning from Scarce Data via Multi-Task Constrained Optimization</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T18:35:59Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.13680v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2511.13680v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>A learning task, understood as the problem of fitting a parametric model from supervised data, fundamentally requires the dataset to be large enough to be representative of the underlying distribution of the source. When data is limited, the learned models fail generalize to cases not seen during training. This paper introduces a multi-task \emph{cross-learning} framework to overcome data scarcity by jointly estimating \emph{deterministic} parameters across multiple, related tasks. We formulate this joint estimation as a constrained optimization problem, where the constraints dictate the resulting similarity between the parameters of the different models, allowing the estimated parameters to differ across tasks while still combining information from multiple data sources. This framework enables knowledge transfer from tasks with abundant data to those with scarce data, leading to more accurate and reliable parameter estimates, providing a solution for scenarios where parameter inference from limited data is critical. We provide theoretical guarantees in a controlled framework with Gaussian data, and show the efficiency of our cross-learning method in applications with real data including image classification and propagation of infectious diseases.</summary>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="eess.SP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T18:35:59Z</published>
    <arxiv:comment>13 pages, 11 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="cs.LG"/>
    <author>
      <name>Leopoldo Agorio</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Cerviño</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Miguel Calvo-Fullana</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alejandro Ribeiro</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Andrés Bazerque</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2511.13676v1</id>
    <title>T-SAR: A Full-Stack Co-design for CPU-Only Ternary LLM Inference via In-Place SIMD ALU Reorganization</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T18:32:03Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.13676v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2511.13676v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Recent advances in LLMs have outpaced the computational and memory capacities of edge platforms that primarily employ CPUs, thereby challenging efficient and scalable deployment. While ternary quantization enables significant resource savings, existing CPU solutions rely heavily on memory-based lookup tables (LUTs) which limit scalability, and FPGA or GPU accelerators remain impractical for edge use. This paper presents T-SAR, the first framework to achieve scalable ternary LLM inference on CPUs by repurposing the SIMD register file for dynamic, in-register LUT generation with minimal hardware modifications. T-SAR eliminates memory bottlenecks and maximizes data-level parallelism, delivering 5.6-24.5x and 1.1-86.2x improvements in GEMM latency and GEMV throughput, respectively, with only 3.2% power and 1.4% area overheads in SIMD units. T-SAR achieves up to 2.5-4.9x the energy efficiency of an NVIDIA Jetson AGX Orin, establishing a practical approach for efficient LLM inference on edge platforms.</summary>
    <category term="cs.AR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T18:32:03Z</published>
    <arxiv:comment>Accepted to DATE 2026</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="cs.AR"/>
    <author>
      <name>Hyunwoo Oh</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>KyungIn Nam</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Rajat Bhattacharjya</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hanning Chen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tamoghno Das</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sanggeon Yun</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Suyeon Jang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Ding</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Nikil Dutt</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mohsen Imani</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2511.13669v1</id>
    <title>Investigating the Dark Energy Constraint from Strongly Lensed AGN at LSST-Scale</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T18:21:54Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.13669v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2511.13669v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Strongly lensed Active Galactic Nuclei (AGN) with an observable time delay can be used to constrain the expansion history of the Universe through time-delay cosmography (TDC). As the sample of time-delay lenses grows to statistical size, with $\mathcal{O}$(1000) lensed AGN forecast to be observed by the Vera C. Rubin Observatory Legacy Survey of Space and Time (LSST), there is an emerging opportunity to use TDC as an independent probe of dark energy. To take advantage of this statistical sample, we implement a scalable hierarchical inference tool which computes the cosmological likelihood for hundreds of strong lenses simultaneously. With this new technique, we investigate the cosmological constraining power from a simulation of the full LSST sample. We start from individual lenses, and emulate the full joint hierarchical TDC analysis, including image-based modeling, time-delay measurement, velocity dispersion measurement, and external convergence prediction. We fully account for the mass-sheet and mass-anisotropy degeneracies. We assume a sample of 800 lenses, with varying levels of follow-up fidelity based on existing campaigns. With our baseline assumptions, within a flexible $w_0w_a$CDM cosmology, we simultaneously forecast a $\sim$2.5% constraint on H0 and a dark energy figure of merit (DE FOM) of 6.7. We show that by expanding the sample from 50 lenses to include an additional 750 lenses with plausible LSST time-delay measurements, we improve the forecasted DE FOM by nearly a factor of 3, demonstrating the value of incorporating this portion of the sample. We also investigate different follow-up campaign strategies, and find significant improvements in the DE FOM with additional stellar kinematics measurements and higher-precision time-delay measurements. We also demonstrate how the redshift configuration of time-delay lenses impacts constraining power in $w_0w_a$CDM.</summary>
    <category term="astro-ph.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T18:21:54Z</published>
    <arxiv:comment>submitting to the Open Journal of Astrophysics, comments welcome</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="astro-ph.CO"/>
    <author>
      <name>Sydney Erickson</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Martin Millon</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Padmavathi Venkatraman</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tian Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Philip Holloway</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Phil Marshall</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Anowar Shajib</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Birrer</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xiang-Yu Huang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Timo Anguita</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Steven Dillmann</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Narayan Khadka</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kate Napier</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Aaron Roodman</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>The LSST Dark Energy Science Collaboration</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2511.13668v1</id>
    <title>Integrative Model for Interoception and Exteroception: predictive coding, points of modulation, and testable predictions</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T18:21:36Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.13668v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2511.13668v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Interoception and exteroception provide continuous feedback about the body and the environment, yet how they are dynamically integrated within a unified predictive coding framework has remained under-specified. This paper develops and empirically validates an integrative predictive coding model that treats interoceptive and exteroceptive inference as parallel hierarchical systems exchanging precision-weighted prediction errors. Within this framework, arbitration between the two streams is governed by relative precision weights (w) and integrated within the anterior insula (AIC) and anterior cingulate cortex (ACC). Computational simulations of the model reproduced biologically plausible dynamics: prediction errors decayed exponentially while arbitration weights self-normalized toward equilibrium (w = 0.5), demonstrating stable convergence and coherent integration. Simulated anxiety and PTSD profiles, characterized respectively by interoceptive and exteroceptive overweighting, yielded rigid, self-sustaining imbalances (w to 1 or w to 0) and slowed recalibration. Empirical application of the arbitration equation to published EEG-fMRI datasets further validated the model. The framework contributes a unifying account of how dysregulated precision weighting may underlie anxiety (overweighted interoception) and PTSD (underweighted interoception). Building on this validation, a proposed experimental paradigm is outlined to test the model's predictions in humans. It examines recalibration across anxiety, neutral, and PTSD groups following targeted interoceptive or exteroceptive therapies. Key predictions include identifiable neural markers of coherence, modulation of heartbeat-evoked potentials by vagal stimulation, and precision-sensitive behavioral signatures in interoceptive-exteroceptive congruency tasks.</summary>
    <category term="q-bio.NC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T18:21:36Z</published>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="q-bio.NC"/>
    <author>
      <name>Pranjal Balar</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sundeep Kapila</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2511.13666v1</id>
    <title>A model-independent assessment of the late-time dark energy density evolution</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T18:21:05Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.13666v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2511.13666v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Combined measurements of Baryon Acoustic Oscillations (BAO) from the Dark Energy Spectroscopic Survey (DESI), the Cosmic Microwave Background (CMB) and Type Ia Supernovae (SN Ia), have recently challenged the $Λ$-Cold Dark Matter ($Λ$CDM) paradigm, indicating potential evidence for a dynamical dark energy component. These results are usually obtained in the context of the dark energy equation-of-state (EoS) parameterizations, generally implying in phantom-crossing at intermediate redshifts. However, a general mapping between these parameterizations that yields approximately the same background observables clouds the inference of the true nature of dark energy in the context of these parametric methods. In this work, we propose a model-independent reconstruction of the dark energy density, which is more directly constrained than its EoS, based on the Gaussian Process (GP) regression method with the use of DESI DR2 BAO data and the Pantheon+, Union3 and DESY5 SN Ia samples. In addition, we perform a statistical comparison between the energy densities of $Λ$, a non-phantom thawing quintessence-type dark energy, and the Chevallier-Polarski-Linder parameterization with the reconstructed function. We find that all models agree with the GP reconstruction at 95\% C.L., with the largest discrepancy coming from $Λ$CDM with DESY5 at low redshifts. Even in this case, our findings suggest that it may be premature to claim statistically significant evidence for evolving or phantom dark energy with current DESI and SN Ia measurements.</summary>
    <category term="astro-ph.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="gr-qc" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="hep-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="hep-th" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T18:21:05Z</published>
    <arxiv:comment>13 pages, 5 figures, 3 tables</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="astro-ph.CO"/>
    <author>
      <name>Rayff de Souza</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Agripino Sousa-Neto</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Javier E. González</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jailson Alcaniz</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2511.13655v1</id>
    <title>OlmoEarth: Stable Latent Image Modeling for Multimodal Earth Observation</title>
    <updated>2025-11-17T18:06:26Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.13655v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2511.13655v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Earth observation data presents a unique challenge: it is spatial like images, sequential like video or text, and highly multimodal. We present OlmoEarth: a multimodal, spatio-temporal foundation model that employs a novel self-supervised learning formulation, masking strategy, and loss all designed for the Earth observation domain. OlmoEarth achieves state-of-the-art performance compared to 12 other foundation models across a variety of research benchmarks and real-world tasks from external partners. When evaluating embeddings OlmoEarth achieves the best performance on 15 out of 24 tasks, and with full fine-tuning it is the best on 19 of 29 tasks. We deploy OlmoEarth as the backbone of an end-to-end platform for data collection, labeling, training, and inference of Earth observation models. The OlmoEarth Platform puts frontier foundation models and powerful data management tools into the hands of non-profits and NGOs working to solve the world's biggest problems. OlmoEarth source code, training data, and pre-trained weights are available at $\href{https://github.com/allenai/olmoearth_pretrain}{\text{https://github.com/allenai/olmoearth_pretrain}}$.</summary>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2025-11-17T18:06:26Z</published>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="cs.CV"/>
    <author>
      <name>Henry Herzog</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Favyen Bastani</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yawen Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Gabriel Tseng</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Joseph Redmon</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hadrien Sablon</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ryan Park</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Morrison</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alexandra Buraczynski</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Karen Farley</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Joshua Hansen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Howe</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Patrick Alan Johnson</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mark Otterlee</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ted Schmitt</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hunter Pitelka</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Stephen Daspit</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Rachel Ratner</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Christopher Wilhelm</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sebastian Wood</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mike Jacobi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hannah Kerner</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Evan Shelhamer</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ali Farhadi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ranjay Krishna</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Patrick Beukema</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
