<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Last updated: 2025-03-25T00:52:56Z -->
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3Dall%3Acausal%20inference%26id_list%3D%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=all:causal inference&amp;id_list=&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/SsRksLzRb0LuVhSmQ+N8WbAs+f8</id>
  <updated>2025-03-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">109315</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.17363v1</id>
    <updated>2025-03-21T17:59:55Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-21T17:59:55Z</published>
    <title>Dancing with Critiques: Enhancing LLM Reasoning with Stepwise Natural
  Language Self-Critique</title>
    <summary>  Enhancing the reasoning capabilities of large language models (LLMs),
particularly for complex tasks requiring multi-step logical deductions, remains
a significant challenge. Traditional inference time scaling methods utilize
scalar reward signals from process reward models to evaluate candidate
reasoning steps, but these scalar rewards lack the nuanced qualitative
information essential for understanding and justifying each step. In this
paper, we propose a novel inference-time scaling approach -- stepwise natural
language self-critique (PANEL), which employs self-generated natural language
critiques as feedback to guide the step-level search process. By generating
rich, human-readable critiques for each candidate reasoning step, PANEL retains
essential qualitative information, facilitating better-informed decision-making
during inference. This approach bypasses the need for task-specific verifiers
and the associated training overhead, making it broadly applicable across
diverse tasks. Experimental results on challenging reasoning benchmarks,
including AIME and GPQA, demonstrate that PANEL significantly enhances
reasoning performance, outperforming traditional scalar reward-based methods.
Our code is available at https://github.com/puddingyeah/PANEL to support and
encourage future research in this promising field.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Yansi Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jiahao Xu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tian Liang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xingyu Chen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zhiwei He</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Qiuzhi Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Rui Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zhuosheng Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zhaopeng Tu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Haitao Mi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Dong Yu</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:doi xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">10.13140/RG.2.2.27912.33289</arxiv:doi>
    <link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.13140/RG.2.2.27912.33289" rel="related"/>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.17363v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2503.17363v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.17361v1</id>
    <updated>2025-03-21T17:59:43Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-21T17:59:43Z</published>
    <title>Gumbel-Softmax Flow Matching with Straight-Through Guidance for
  Controllable Biological Sequence Generation</title>
    <summary>  Flow matching in the continuous simplex has emerged as a promising strategy
for DNA sequence design, but struggles to scale to higher simplex dimensions
required for peptide and protein generation. We introduce Gumbel-Softmax Flow
and Score Matching, a generative framework on the simplex based on a novel
Gumbel-Softmax interpolant with a time-dependent temperature. Using this
interpolant, we introduce Gumbel-Softmax Flow Matching by deriving a
parameterized velocity field that transports from smooth categorical
distributions to distributions concentrated at a single vertex of the simplex.
We alternatively present Gumbel-Softmax Score Matching which learns to regress
the gradient of the probability density. Our framework enables high-quality,
diverse generation and scales efficiently to higher-dimensional simplices. To
enable training-free guidance, we propose Straight-Through Guided Flows
(STGFlow), a classifier-based guidance method that leverages straight-through
estimators to steer the unconditional velocity field toward optimal vertices of
the simplex. STGFlow enables efficient inference-time guidance using
classifiers pre-trained on clean sequences, and can be used with any discrete
flow method. Together, these components form a robust framework for
controllable de novo sequence generation. We demonstrate state-of-the-art
performance in conditional DNA promoter design, sequence-only protein
generation, and target-binding peptide design for rare disease treatment.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Sophia Tang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yinuo Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alexander Tong</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Pranam Chatterjee</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.17361v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2503.17361v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="q-bio.BM" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.17359v1</id>
    <updated>2025-03-21T17:59:22Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-21T17:59:22Z</published>
    <title>Position: Interactive Generative Video as Next-Generation Game Engine</title>
    <summary>  Modern game development faces significant challenges in creativity and cost
due to predetermined content in traditional game engines. Recent breakthroughs
in video generation models, capable of synthesizing realistic and interactive
virtual environments, present an opportunity to revolutionize game creation. In
this position paper, we propose Interactive Generative Video (IGV) as the
foundation for Generative Game Engines (GGE), enabling unlimited novel content
generation in next-generation gaming. GGE leverages IGV's unique strengths in
unlimited high-quality content synthesis, physics-aware world modeling,
user-controlled interactivity, long-term memory capabilities, and causal
reasoning. We present a comprehensive framework detailing GGE's core modules
and a hierarchical maturity roadmap (L0-L4) to guide its evolution. Our work
charts a new course for game development in the AI era, envisioning a future
where AI-powered generative systems fundamentally reshape how games are created
and experienced.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Jiwen Yu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yiran Qin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Haoxuan Che</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Quande Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xintao Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Pengfei Wan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Di Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xihui Liu</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.17359v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2503.17359v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.17347v1</id>
    <updated>2025-03-21T17:48:14Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-21T17:48:14Z</published>
    <title>Dereflection Any Image with Diffusion Priors and Diversified Data</title>
    <summary>  Reflection removal of a single image remains a highly challenging task due to
the complex entanglement between target scenes and unwanted reflections.
Despite significant progress, existing methods are hindered by the scarcity of
high-quality, diverse data and insufficient restoration priors, resulting in
limited generalization across various real-world scenarios. In this paper, we
propose Dereflection Any Image, a comprehensive solution with an efficient data
preparation pipeline and a generalizable model for robust reflection removal.
First, we introduce a dataset named Diverse Reflection Removal (DRR) created by
randomly rotating reflective mediums in target scenes, enabling variation of
reflection angles and intensities, and setting a new benchmark in scale,
quality, and diversity. Second, we propose a diffusion-based framework with
one-step diffusion for deterministic outputs and fast inference. To ensure
stable learning, we design a three-stage progressive training strategy,
including reflection-invariant finetuning to encourage consistent outputs
across varying reflection patterns that characterize our dataset. Extensive
experiments show that our method achieves SOTA performance on both common
benchmarks and challenging in-the-wild images, showing superior generalization
across diverse real-world scenes.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Jichen Hu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Chen Yang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zanwei Zhou</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jiemin Fang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xiaokang Yang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Qi Tian</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Wei Shen</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.17347v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2503.17347v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.17340v1</id>
    <updated>2025-03-21T17:42:50Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-21T17:42:50Z</published>
    <title>Align Your Rhythm: Generating Highly Aligned Dance Poses with
  Gating-Enhanced Rhythm-Aware Feature Representation</title>
    <summary>  Automatically generating natural, diverse and rhythmic human dance movements
driven by music is vital for virtual reality and film industries. However,
generating dance that naturally follows music remains a challenge, as existing
methods lack proper beat alignment and exhibit unnatural motion dynamics. In
this paper, we propose Danceba, a novel framework that leverages gating
mechanism to enhance rhythm-aware feature representation for music-driven dance
generation, which achieves highly aligned dance poses with enhanced rhythmic
sensitivity. Specifically, we introduce Phase-Based Rhythm Extraction (PRE) to
precisely extract rhythmic information from musical phase data, capitalizing on
the intrinsic periodicity and temporal structures of music. Additionally, we
propose Temporal-Gated Causal Attention (TGCA) to focus on global rhythmic
features, ensuring that dance movements closely follow the musical rhythm. We
also introduce Parallel Mamba Motion Modeling (PMMM) architecture to separately
model upper and lower body motions along with musical features, thereby
improving the naturalness and diversity of generated dance movements. Extensive
experiments confirm that Danceba outperforms state-of-the-art methods,
achieving significantly better rhythmic alignment and motion diversity. Project
page: https://danceba.github.io/ .
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Congyi Fan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jian Guan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xuanjia Zhao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Dongli Xu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Youtian Lin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tong Ye</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Pengming Feng</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Haiwei Pan</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">10 pages, 6 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.17340v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2503.17340v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.MM" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.MM" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.SD" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="eess.AS" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.17316v1</id>
    <updated>2025-03-21T17:12:30Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-21T17:12:30Z</published>
    <title>Pow3R: Empowering Unconstrained 3D Reconstruction with Camera and Scene
  Priors</title>
    <summary>  We present Pow3r, a novel large 3D vision regression model that is highly
versatile in the input modalities it accepts. Unlike previous feed-forward
models that lack any mechanism to exploit known camera or scene priors at test
time, Pow3r incorporates any combination of auxiliary information such as
intrinsics, relative pose, dense or sparse depth, alongside input images,
within a single network. Building upon the recent DUSt3R paradigm, a
transformer-based architecture that leverages powerful pre-training, our
lightweight and versatile conditioning acts as additional guidance for the
network to predict more accurate estimates when auxiliary information is
available. During training we feed the model with random subsets of modalities
at each iteration, which enables the model to operate under different levels of
known priors at test time. This in turn opens up new capabilities, such as
performing inference in native image resolution, or point-cloud completion. Our
experiments on 3D reconstruction, depth completion, multi-view depth
prediction, multi-view stereo, and multi-view pose estimation tasks yield
state-of-the-art results and confirm the effectiveness of Pow3r at exploiting
all available information. The project webpage is
https://europe.naverlabs.com/pow3r.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Wonbong Jang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Philippe Weinzaepfel</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Vincent Leroy</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lourdes Agapito</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jerome Revaud</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">CVPR 2025</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.17316v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2503.17316v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.17314v1</id>
    <updated>2025-03-21T17:10:32Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-21T17:10:32Z</published>
    <title>Numerical Investigation of Preferential Flow Paths in Enzymatically
  Induced Calcite Precipitation supported by Bayesian Model Analysis</title>
    <summary>  The usability of enzymatically induced calcium carbonate precipitation (EICP)
as a method for altering porous-media properties, soil stabilization, or
biocementation depends on our ability to predict the spatial distribution of
the precipitated calcium carbonate in porous media. While current REV-scale
models are able to reproduce the main features of laboratory experiments, they
neglect effects like the formation of preferential flow paths and the
appearance of multiple polymorphs of calcium carbonate with differing
properties. We show that extending an existing EICP model by the conceptual
assumption of a mobile precipitate, amorphous calcium carbonate (ACC), allows
for the formation of preferential flow paths when the initial porosity is
heterogeneous. We apply sensitivity analysis and Bayesian inference to gain an
understanding of the influence of characteristic parameters of ACC that are
uncertain or unknown and compare two variations of the model based on different
formulations of the ACC detachment term to analyse the plausibility of our
hypothesis. An arbitrary Polynomial Chaos (aPC) surrogate model is trained
based on the full model and used to reduce the computational cost of this
study.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Rebecca Kohlhaas</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Johannes Hommel</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Felix Weinhardt</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Holger Class</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sergey Oladyshkin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Bernd Flemisch</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.17314v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2503.17314v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="physics.comp-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.comp-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.data-an" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.17291v1</id>
    <updated>2025-03-21T16:42:45Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-21T16:42:45Z</published>
    <title>Linear sigma model with quarks and Polyakov loop in rotation: phase
  diagrams, Tolman-Ehrenfest law and mechanical properties</title>
    <summary>  We study the effect of rotation on the confining and chiral properties of QCD
using the Polyakov-enhanced linear sigma model coupled to quarks. Working in
the homogeneous approximation, we obtain the phase diagram at finite
temperature, baryon density and angular frequency, taking into account the
causality constraint enforced by the spectral boundary conditions at a
cylindrical surface. We explicitly address various limits with respect to
system size, angular frequency and chemical potential. We demonstrate that, in
this model, the critical temperatures of both transitions diminish in response
to the increasing rotation, being in contradiction with the first-principle
lattice results. In the limit of large volume, the thermodynamics of the model
is consistent with the Tolman-Ehrenfest law. We also compute the mechanical
characteristics of rotating plasma such as the moment of inertia and the $K_4$
shape coefficient.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Pracheta Singha</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sergiu Busuioc</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Victor E. Ambrus</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Maxim N. Chernodub</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">62 pages, 26 figures, 2 tables, insane numerics</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.17291v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2503.17291v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="nucl-th" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="nucl-th" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="hep-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="hep-th" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.17290v1</id>
    <updated>2025-03-21T16:41:10Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-21T16:41:10Z</published>
    <title>Calibration Strategies for Robust Causal Estimation: Theoretical and
  Empirical Insights on Propensity Score Based Estimators</title>
    <summary>  The partitioning of data for estimation and calibration critically impacts
the performance of propensity score based estimators like inverse probability
weighting (IPW) and double/debiased machine learning (DML) frameworks. We
extend recent advances in calibration techniques for propensity score
estimation, improving the robustness of propensity scores in challenging
settings such as limited overlap, small sample sizes, or unbalanced data. Our
contributions are twofold: First, we provide a theoretical analysis of the
properties of calibrated estimators in the context of DML. To this end, we
refine existing calibration frameworks for propensity score models, with a
particular emphasis on the role of sample-splitting schemes in ensuring valid
causal inference. Second, through extensive simulations, we show that
calibration reduces variance of inverse-based propensity score estimators while
also mitigating bias in IPW, even in small-sample regimes. Notably, calibration
improves stability for flexible learners (e.g., gradient boosting) while
preserving the doubly robust properties of DML. A key insight is that, even
when methods perform well without calibration, incorporating a calibration step
does not degrade performance, provided that an appropriate sample-splitting
approach is chosen.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Jan Rabenseifner</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sven Klaassen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jannis Kueck</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Philipp Bach</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.17290v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2503.17290v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="econ.EM" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ME" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.17269v1</id>
    <updated>2025-03-21T16:11:21Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-21T16:11:21Z</published>
    <title>Recovering Pulse Waves from Video Using Deep Unrolling and Deep
  Equilibrium Models</title>
    <summary>  Camera-based monitoring of vital signs, also known as imaging
photoplethysmography (iPPG), has seen applications in driver-monitoring,
perfusion assessment in surgical settings, affective computing, and more. iPPG
involves sensing the underlying cardiac pulse from video of the skin and
estimating vital signs such as the heart rate or a full pulse waveform. Some
previous iPPG methods impose model-based sparse priors on the pulse signals and
use iterative optimization for pulse wave recovery, while others use end-to-end
black-box deep learning methods. In contrast, we introduce methods that combine
signal processing and deep learning methods in an inverse problem framework.
Our methods estimate the underlying pulse signal and heart rate from facial
video by learning deep-network-based denoising operators that leverage deep
algorithm unfolding and deep equilibrium models. Experiments show that our
methods can denoise an acquired signal from the face and infer the correct
underlying pulse rate, achieving state-of-the-art heart rate estimation
performance on well-known benchmarks, all with less than one-fifth the number
of learnable parameters as the closest competing method.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Vineet R Shenoy</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Suhas Lohit</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hassan Mansour</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Rama Chellappa</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tim K. Marks</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">13 pages, 9 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.17269v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2503.17269v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="eess.IV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
