<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Last updated: 2025-04-29T00:54:57Z -->
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3Dall%3Acausal%20inference%26id_list%3D%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=all:causal inference&amp;id_list=&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/SsRksLzRb0LuVhSmQ+N8WbAs+f8</id>
  <updated>2025-04-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">111275</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.18536v1</id>
    <updated>2025-04-25T17:59:14Z</updated>
    <published>2025-04-25T17:59:14Z</published>
    <title>Adapting Probabilistic Risk Assessment for AI</title>
    <summary>  Modern general-purpose artificial intelligence (AI) systems present an urgent
risk management challenge, as their rapidly evolving capabilities and potential
for catastrophic harm outpace our ability to reliably assess their risks.
Current methods often rely on selective testing and undocumented assumptions
about risk priorities, frequently failing to make a serious attempt at
assessing the set of pathways through which Al systems pose direct or indirect
risks to society and the biosphere. This paper introduces the probabilistic
risk assessment (PRA) for AI framework, adapting established PRA techniques
from high-reliability industries (e.g., nuclear power, aerospace) for the new
challenges of advanced AI. The framework guides assessors in identifying
potential risks, estimating likelihood and severity, and explicitly documenting
evidence, underlying assumptions, and analyses at appropriate granularities.
The framework's implementation tool synthesizes the results into a risk report
card with aggregated risk estimates from all assessed risks. This systematic
approach integrates three advances: (1) Aspect-oriented hazard analysis
provides systematic hazard coverage guided by a first-principles taxonomy of AI
system aspects (e.g. capabilities, domain knowledge, affordances); (2) Risk
pathway modeling analyzes causal chains from system aspects to societal impacts
using bidirectional analysis and incorporating prospective techniques; and (3)
Uncertainty management employs scenario decomposition, reference scales, and
explicit tracing protocols to structure credible projections with novelty or
limited data. Additionally, the framework harmonizes diverse assessment methods
by integrating evidence into comparable, quantified absolute risk estimates for
critical decisions. We have implemented this as a workbook tool for AI
developers, evaluators, and regulators, available on the project website.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Anna Katariina Wisakanto</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Joe Rogero</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Avyay M. Casheekar</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Mallah</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">for project website, see https://pra-for-ai.github.io/pra/</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.18536v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2504.18536v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CY" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.SY" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="eess.SY" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.AP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.18529v1</id>
    <updated>2025-04-25T17:53:52Z</updated>
    <published>2025-04-25T17:53:52Z</published>
    <title>Practical Type-Based Taint Checking and Inference (Extended Version)</title>
    <summary>  Many important security properties can be formulated in terms of flows of
tainted data, and improved taint analysis tools to prevent such flows are of
critical need. Most existing taint analyses use whole-program static analysis,
leading to scalability challenges. Type-based checking is a promising
alternative, as it enables modular and incremental checking for fast
performance. However, type-based approaches have not been widely adopted in
practice, due to challenges with false positives and annotating existing
codebases. In this paper, we present a new approach to type-based checking of
taint properties that addresses these challenges, based on two key techniques.
First, we present a new type-based tainting checker with significantly reduced
false positives, via more practical handling of third-party libraries and other
language constructs. Second, we present a novel technique to automatically
infer tainting type qualifiers for existing code. Our technique supports
inference of generic type argument annotations, crucial for tainting
properties. We implemented our techniques in a tool TaintTyper and evaluated it
on real-world benchmarks. TaintTyper exceeds the recall of a state-of-the-art
whole-program taint analyzer, with comparable precision, and 2.93X-22.9X faster
checking time. Further, TaintTyper infers annotations comparable to those
written by hand, suitable for insertion into source code. TaintTyper is a
promising new approach to efficient and practical taint checking.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Nima Karimipour</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kanak Das</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Manu Sridharan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Behnaz Hassanshahi</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Extended version of ECOOP 2025 paper</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.18529v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2504.18529v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.PL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.PL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.18510v1</id>
    <updated>2025-04-25T17:23:47Z</updated>
    <published>2025-04-25T17:23:47Z</published>
    <title>Examining the Impact of Optical Aberrations to Image Classification and
  Object Detection Models</title>
    <summary>  Deep neural networks (DNNs) have proven to be successful in various computer
vision applications such that models even infer in safety-critical situations.
Therefore, vision models have to behave in a robust way to disturbances such as
noise or blur. While seminal benchmarks exist to evaluate model robustness to
diverse corruptions, blur is often approximated in an overly simplistic way to
model defocus, while ignoring the different blur kernel shapes that result from
optical systems. To study model robustness against realistic optical blur
effects, this paper proposes two datasets of blur corruptions, which we denote
OpticsBench and LensCorruptions. OpticsBench examines primary aberrations such
as coma, defocus, and astigmatism, i.e. aberrations that can be represented by
varying a single parameter of Zernike polynomials. To go beyond the principled
but synthetic setting of primary aberrations, LensCorruptions samples linear
combinations in the vector space spanned by Zernike polynomials, corresponding
to 100 real lenses. Evaluations for image classification and object detection
on ImageNet and MSCOCO show that for a variety of different pre-trained models,
the performance on OpticsBench and LensCorruptions varies significantly,
indicating the need to consider realistic image corruptions to evaluate a
model's robustness against blur.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Patrick Müller</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alexander Braun</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Margret Keuper</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">v1.0</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.18510v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2504.18510v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.18497v1</id>
    <updated>2025-04-25T17:10:33Z</updated>
    <published>2025-04-25T17:10:33Z</published>
    <title>DeSIA: Attribute Inference Attacks Against Limited Fixed Aggregate
  Statistics</title>
    <summary>  Empirical inference attacks are a popular approach for evaluating the privacy
risk of data release mechanisms in practice. While an active attack literature
exists to evaluate machine learning models or synthetic data release, we
currently lack comparable methods for fixed aggregate statistics, in particular
when only a limited number of statistics are released. We here propose an
inference attack framework against fixed aggregate statistics and an attribute
inference attack called DeSIA. We instantiate DeSIA against the U.S. Census
PPMF dataset and show it to strongly outperform reconstruction-based attacks.
In particular, we show DeSIA to be highly effective at identifying vulnerable
users, achieving a true positive rate of 0.14 at a false positive rate of
$10^{-3}$. We then show DeSIA to perform well against users whose attributes
cannot be verified and when varying the number of aggregate statistics and
level of noise addition. We also perform an extensive ablation study of DeSIA
and show how DeSIA can be successfully adapted to the membership inference
task. Overall, our results show that aggregation alone is not sufficient to
protect privacy, even when a relatively small number of aggregates are being
released, and emphasize the need for formal privacy mechanisms and testing
before aggregate statistics are released.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Yifeng Mao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Bozhidar Stevanoski</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yves-Alexandre de Montjoye</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.18497v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2504.18497v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.18478v1</id>
    <updated>2025-04-25T16:36:27Z</updated>
    <published>2025-04-25T16:36:27Z</published>
    <title>Magnetic field orientation dependence of continuous-wave optically
  detected magnetic resonance with nitrogen-vacancy ensembles</title>
    <summary>  Continuous-wave optically detected magnetic resonance (CW-ODMR) measurements
with nitrogen-vacancy (NV) spins in diamond are used for sensing DC magnetic
fields from nearby magnetic targets. However, this technique suffers from
ambiguities in the extraction of the magnetic field components when resonances
due to different NV orientation classes overlap with each other. Here, we
perform detailed experimental and theoretical studies of such effects on NV
ensembles experiencing low bias magnetic fields. In particular, through
symmetry considerations, we systematically examine the ODMR response of
different NV orientation classes as a function of the orientation of the
magnetic field vector. Our studies are of importance for performing a careful
and detailed analysis of the ODMR spectra in order to infer the vector magnetic
field information. Our results find application in the studies of magnetic
samples that require a low applied bias field and also can be potentially
adapted to defect spins in other solid-state systems.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Pralekh Dubey</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Shashank Kumar</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Chinmaya Singh</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jemish Naliyapara</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Monish A Poojar</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Harikrishnan K B</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Anshul Poonia</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Phani Peddibhotla</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.18478v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2504.18478v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.18452v1</id>
    <updated>2025-04-25T16:03:34Z</updated>
    <published>2025-04-25T16:03:34Z</published>
    <title>Structured Bayesian Regression Tree Models for Estimating Distributed
  Lag Effects: The R Package dlmtree</title>
    <summary>  When examining the relationship between an exposure and an outcome, there is
often a time lag between exposure and the observed effect on the outcome. A
common statistical approach for estimating the relationship between the outcome
and lagged measurements of exposure is a distributed lag model (DLM). Because
repeated measurements are often autocorrelated, the lagged effects are
typically constrained to vary smoothly over time. A recent statistical
development on the smoothing constraint is a tree structured DLM framework. We
present an R package dlmtree, available on CRAN, that integrates tree
structured DLM and extensions into a comprehensive software package with
user-friendly implementation. A conceptual background on tree structured DLMs
and demonstration of the fitting process of each model using simulated data are
provided. We also demonstrate inference and interpretation using the fitted
models, including summary and visualization. Additionally, a built-in shiny app
for heterogeneity analysis is included.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Seongwon Im</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ander Wilson</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Daniel Mork</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">22 pages, 11 figures, 2 tables</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.18452v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2504.18452v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="stat.ME" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ME" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.18443v1</id>
    <updated>2025-04-25T15:54:09Z</updated>
    <published>2025-04-25T15:54:09Z</published>
    <title>Pseudo-Boolean Proof Logging for Optimal Classical Planning</title>
    <summary>  We introduce lower-bound certificates for classical planning tasks, which can
be used to prove the unsolvability of a task or the optimality of a plan in a
way that can be verified by an independent third party. We describe a general
framework for generating lower-bound certificates based on pseudo-Boolean
constraints, which is agnostic to the planning algorithm used.
  As a case study, we show how to modify the $A^{*}$ algorithm to produce
proofs of optimality with modest overhead, using pattern database heuristics
and $h^\textit{max}$ as concrete examples. The same proof logging approach
works for any heuristic whose inferences can be efficiently expressed as
reasoning over pseudo-Boolean constraints.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Dold</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Malte Helmert</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jakob Nordström</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Gabriele Röger</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tanja Schindler</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">35th International Conference on Automated Planning and Scheduling
  (ICAPS'2025)</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.18443v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2504.18443v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.18435v1</id>
    <updated>2025-04-25T15:45:54Z</updated>
    <published>2025-04-25T15:45:54Z</published>
    <title>Robust Binding Energy Distribution Sampling on Amorphous Solid Water
  Models. Method testing and validation with NH3, CO and CH4</title>
    <summary>  This work aims to develop a method based on a structurally reliable ice model
and a statistically and physico-chemically robust approach for BE distribution
inference, with the aim to be applicable to various relevant interstellar
species. A multiscale computational approach is presented, with a Molecular
Dynamics (MD) Heat &amp; Quench protocol for the amorphous water ice model, and an
ONIOM(B3LYP-D3(BJ)/6-311+G**:GFN2-xtb) scheme for the BE inference, with a
prime emphasis onto the BE/real system size convergence. The sampling of the
binding configurations is twofold, exploring both regularly spaced binding
sites, as well as various adsorbate-to-substrate orientations on each locally
distinct site. This second source of BE diversity accounts for the local
roughness of the potential energy landscape of the substrate. Three different
adsorbate test cases are considered, i.e. NH3, CO and CH4, owing to their
significance in dust icy mantles, and their distinct binding behavior with
water ices. The BE distributions for NH3, CO and CH4 have been inferred, with
converged statistics. The distribution for NH3 is better represented by a
double Gaussian component profile. Three starting adsorbate orientations per
site are required to reach convergence for both Gaussian components of NH3,
while 2 orientations are sufficient for CO, and one unique for CH4 (symmetric).
Further geometrical and molecular surrounding insights have been provided.
These results encompass previously reported results.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Maria Groyne</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Benoît Champagne</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Cedric Baijot</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Michaël De Becker</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Accepted for publication in A&amp;A 22 pages, 27 Figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.18435v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2504.18435v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="astro-ph.IM" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.IM" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.18425v1</id>
    <updated>2025-04-25T15:31:46Z</updated>
    <published>2025-04-25T15:31:46Z</published>
    <title>Kimi-Audio Technical Report</title>
    <summary>  We present Kimi-Audio, an open-source audio foundation model that excels in
audio understanding, generation, and conversation. We detail the practices in
building Kimi-Audio, including model architecture, data curation, training
recipe, inference deployment, and evaluation. Specifically, we leverage a
12.5Hz audio tokenizer, design a novel LLM-based architecture with continuous
features as input and discrete tokens as output, and develop a chunk-wise
streaming detokenizer based on flow matching. We curate a pre-training dataset
that consists of more than 13 million hours of audio data covering a wide range
of modalities including speech, sound, and music, and build a pipeline to
construct high-quality and diverse post-training data. Initialized from a
pre-trained LLM, Kimi-Audio is continual pre-trained on both audio and text
data with several carefully designed tasks, and then fine-tuned to support a
diverse of audio-related tasks. Extensive evaluation shows that Kimi-Audio
achieves state-of-the-art performance on a range of audio benchmarks including
speech recognition, audio understanding, audio question answering, and speech
conversation. We release the codes, model checkpoints, as well as the
evaluation toolkits in https://github.com/MoonshotAI/Kimi-Audio.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name> KimiTeam</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ding Ding</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zeqian Ju</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yichong Leng</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Songxiang Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tong Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zeyu Shang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kai Shen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Wei Song</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xu Tan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Heyi Tang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zhengtao Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Chu Wei</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yifei Xin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xinran Xu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jianwei Yu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yutao Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xinyu Zhou</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Y. Charles</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jun Chen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yanru Chen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yulun Du</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Weiran He</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zhenxing Hu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Guokun Lai</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Qingcheng Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yangyang Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Weidong Sun</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jianzhou Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yuzhi Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yuefeng Wu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yuxin Wu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Dongchao Yang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hao Yang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ying Yang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zhilin Yang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Aoxiong Yin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ruibin Yuan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yutong Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zaida Zhou</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.18425v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2504.18425v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="eess.AS" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="eess.AS" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.MM" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.SD" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.18415v1</id>
    <updated>2025-04-25T15:17:52Z</updated>
    <published>2025-04-25T15:17:52Z</published>
    <title>BitNet v2: Native 4-bit Activations with Hadamard Transformation for
  1-bit LLMs</title>
    <summary>  Efficient deployment of 1-bit Large Language Models (LLMs) is hindered by
activation outliers, which complicate quantization to low bit-widths. We
introduce BitNet v2, a novel framework enabling native 4-bit activation
quantization for 1-bit LLMs. To tackle outliers in attention and feed-forward
network activations, we propose H-BitLinear, a module applying an online
Hadamard transformation prior to activation quantization. This transformation
smooths sharp activation distributions into more Gaussian-like forms, suitable
for low-bit representation. Experiments show BitNet v2 trained from scratch
with 8-bit activations matches BitNet b1.58 performance. Crucially, BitNet v2
achieves minimal performance degradation when trained with native 4-bit
activations, significantly reducing memory footprint and computational cost for
batched inference.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Hongyu Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Shuming Ma</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Furu Wei</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Work in progress</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.18415v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2504.18415v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
