<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Last updated: 2026-02-11T01:24:13Z -->
<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://arxiv.org/api/p6EyKyP4fMY/66n9Ev8E79F7KlI</id>
  <title>arXiv Query: search_query=all:causal OR all:inference&amp;id_list=&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <updated>2026-02-11T01:24:14Z</updated>
  <link href="https://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query=all:causal+OR+all:inference&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10&amp;id_list=" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage>10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <opensearch:totalResults>133596</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex>0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09019v1</id>
    <title>The seismic diversity of four successive solar cycle minima as observed by the Birmingham Solar-Oscillations Network (BiSON)</title>
    <updated>2026-02-09T18:59:26Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09019v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2602.09019v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>We have used data collected by the Birmingham Solar-Oscillations Network (BiSON) to perform a helioseismic diagnosis of changes to the Sun's internal structure between four successive solar cycle minima, beginning with the minimum at the end of cycle 21 and ending with the recent minimum at the beginning of cycle 25. The unique duration of the BiSON database makes such a study possible. We used the low-degree BiSON p-mode frequencies to constrain structural changes between minima in the layers above $\approx 0.9 R_{\odot}$. We accomplished this by examining variations in the HeII ionisation zone signature; and by inverting the frequency differences to infer changes in the sound speed. Additionally, we employed frequency differences between various solar models that had subtle modifications to their internal structures to facilitate analysis of the observations. We find evidence for small, but marginally significant, changes in structure between different minima. The HeII signature was larger, and the sound speed in the range $\approx 0.93$ to $0.97 R_{\odot}$ was slightly higher, during the cycle 23/24 minimum, than during the other minima. The cycle 23/24 minimum was the deepest, as measured by proxies of global solar activity. These findings are consistent with magnetic flux levels having been lower in this minimum than the others, resulting in a higher gas pressure, higher temperatures, and higher sound speed. Our results demonstrate the potential of using asteroseismic data to perform similar analyses on other solar-type stars.</summary>
    <category term="astro-ph.SR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-02-09T18:59:26Z</published>
    <arxiv:comment>Accepted for publication in MNRAS</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="astro-ph.SR"/>
    <author>
      <name>Sarbani Basu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>William J. Chaplin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Rachel Howe</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yvonne Elsworth</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Steven J. Hale</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Eleanor Murray</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09014v1</id>
    <title>ArcFlow: Unleashing 2-Step Text-to-Image Generation via High-Precision Non-Linear Flow Distillation</title>
    <updated>2026-02-09T18:56:14Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.09014v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2602.09014v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Diffusion models have achieved remarkable generation quality, but they suffer from significant inference cost due to their reliance on multiple sequential denoising steps, motivating recent efforts to distill this inference process into a few-step regime. However, existing distillation methods typically approximate the teacher trajectory by using linear shortcuts, which makes it difficult to match its constantly changing tangent directions as velocities evolve across timesteps, thereby leading to quality degradation. To address this limitation, we propose ArcFlow, a few-step distillation framework that explicitly employs non-linear flow trajectories to approximate pre-trained teacher trajectories. Concretely, ArcFlow parameterizes the velocity field underlying the inference trajectory as a mixture of continuous momentum processes. This enables ArcFlow to capture velocity evolution and extrapolate coherent velocities to form a continuous non-linear trajectory within each denoising step. Importantly, this parameterization admits an analytical integration of this non-linear trajectory, which circumvents numerical discretization errors and results in high-precision approximation of the teacher trajectory. To train this parameterization into a few-step generator, we implement ArcFlow via trajectory distillation on pre-trained teacher models using lightweight adapters. This strategy ensures fast, stable convergence while preserving generative diversity and quality. Built on large-scale models (Qwen-Image-20B and FLUX.1-dev), ArcFlow only fine-tunes on less than 5% of original parameters and achieves a 40x speedup with 2 NFEs over the original multi-step teachers without significant quality degradation. Experiments on benchmarks show the effectiveness of ArcFlow both qualitatively and quantitatively.</summary>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-02-09T18:56:14Z</published>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="cs.CV"/>
    <author>
      <name>Zihan Yang</name>
      <arxiv:affiliation>Fudan University</arxiv:affiliation>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Shuyuan Tu</name>
      <arxiv:affiliation>Fudan University</arxiv:affiliation>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Licheng Zhang</name>
      <arxiv:affiliation>Fudan University</arxiv:affiliation>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Qi Dai</name>
      <arxiv:affiliation>Microsoft Research Asia</arxiv:affiliation>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yu-Gang Jiang</name>
      <arxiv:affiliation>Fudan University</arxiv:affiliation>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zuxuan Wu</name>
      <arxiv:affiliation>Fudan University</arxiv:affiliation>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2602.08997v1</id>
    <title>Paradox of De-identification: A Critique of HIPAA Safe Harbour in the Age of LLMs</title>
    <updated>2026-02-09T18:43:19Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.08997v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2602.08997v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Privacy is a human right that sustains patient-provider trust. Clinical notes capture a patient's private vulnerability and individuality, which are used for care coordination and research. Under HIPAA Safe Harbor, these notes are de-identified to protect patient privacy. However, Safe Harbor was designed for an era of categorical tabular data, focusing on the removal of explicit identifiers while ignoring the latent information found in correlations between identity and quasi-identifiers, which can be captured by modern LLMs. We first formalize these correlations using a causal graph, then validate it empirically through individual re-identification of patients from scrubbed notes. The paradox of de-identification is further shown through a diagnosis ablation: even when all other information is removed, the model can predict the patient's neighborhood based on diagnosis alone. This position paper raises the question of how we can act as a community to uphold patient-provider trust when de-identification is inherently imperfect. We aim to raise awareness and discuss actionable recommendations.</summary>
    <category term="cs.CY" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-02-09T18:43:19Z</published>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="cs.CY"/>
    <author>
      <name>Lavender Y. Jiang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xujin Chris Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kyunghyun Cho</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Eric K. Oermann</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2602.08959v1</id>
    <title>Is the nitrogen-rich source PN K4-47 a true planetary nebula?</title>
    <updated>2026-02-09T17:56:45Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.08959v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2602.08959v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>PN K4-47 is a young planetary nebula that exhibits shock-excited bipolar lobes and a complex molecular environment, with the highest number of molecules detected within a planetary nebula. It has been questioned whether K4-47 is indeed a `typical' planetary nebula, or may be more exotic in nature. We examine this question using optical imaging and spectroscopy, and sub-millimetre and radio interferometry. Our observations spatially resolve the sub-millimetre environment of K4-47 for the first time. We find elongated CO (2-1) emission along a similar PA to the optical bipolar outflow. We derive a distance upper limit of 6 kpc to the source. The source hosts a fast ($\sim$350 km s$^{-1}$) bipolar optical outflow, and a slow (~50-60 km s$^{-1}$) molecular outflow along a similar PA. The outflow velocity indicates an age of 336 $\pm$ 119 yr. We also find that the excitation temperature and density of the atomic gas is~20 kK and 2800 cm$^{-3}$, respectively. The elemental and isotopic enrichment of K4-47 infers an AGB progenitor mass of 4-6 M$_{\odot}$, which corresponds to a white dwarf mass of ~1 M$_{\odot}$, following the initial-final mass relation for white dwarfs. We find that the core of K4-47 must contain 10$^{-2}$ M$_{\odot}$ of dust to explain the extinction, and that photoionisation alone cannot explain the excitation of the atomic gas. We instead require an additional heating mechanism, with shocks a likely scenario. It is likely that the progenitor star of K4-47 was a J-type carbon AGB star, which formed the molecular and dusty circumstellar environment. The bipolar outflow is later triggered, punching through the circumstellar environment, producing shocks, and shaping the environment into the elongated structure seen in the sub-millimetre. We therefore classify K4-47 as a genuine, if unusual, planetary nebula.</summary>
    <category term="astro-ph.SR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-02-09T17:56:45Z</published>
    <arxiv:comment>21 pages, 19 figures. Submitted to A&amp;A. Comments welcome</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="astro-ph.SR"/>
    <author>
      <name>Thomas Steinmetz</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tomasz Kaminski</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>David Jones</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Marcin Hajduk</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Denise R. Goncalves</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Stavros Akras</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2602.08955v1</id>
    <title>Platform Design, Earnings Transparency and Minimum Wage Policies: Evidence from A Natural Experiment on Lyft</title>
    <updated>2026-02-09T17:51:57Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.08955v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2602.08955v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>We study the impact of a major policy and design change at Lyft that altered both driver earnings and platform transparency, offering insights into how such changes affect stakeholders and platform outcomes. In February 2024, Lyft began a staggered rollout of a new policy that guaranteed drivers a minimum share of rider payments and increased transparency by displaying estimated earnings per ride upfront. This policy was first introduced in major urban markets, creating a natural experiment to evaluate its effects. Using data from over 47 million rides across urban and neighboring suburban markets, we apply dynamic staggered difference-in-differences and geographic border strategies to measure causal effects on driver behavior, rider experience, and platform performance. We find the policy significantly increased driver engagement-particularly among those with lower pre-policy earnings or higher income uncertainty-leading to more hours worked, higher utilization, and greater trip volume. These supply-side changes also generated positive spillovers on rider demand. We disentangle the separate effects of earnings guarantees and transparency and show that while both were beneficial, transparency may have also triggered strategic driver behaviors. In ongoing work, we develop a counterfactual simulation framework linking driver supply and rider intents to ride production, showing how small behavioral shifts could further amplify platform outcomes. We also train a self-supervised model on driver trajectories to detect multihoming, examining whether the observed supply increase reflects net expansion or substitution from other platforms. Together, our findings highlight the potential for platform-led policies to serve as alternatives to regulation and offer design insights for managing platform change.</summary>
    <category term="econ.GN" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-02-09T17:51:57Z</published>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="econ.GN"/>
    <author>
      <name>Rubing Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xiao Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Arun Sundararajan</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2602.08939v1</id>
    <title>CausalT5K: Diagnosing and Informing Refusal for Trustworthy Causal Reasoning of Skepticism, Sycophancy, Detection-Correction, and Rung Collapse</title>
    <updated>2026-02-09T17:36:56Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.08939v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2602.08939v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>LLM failures in causal reasoning, including sycophancy, rung collapse, and miscalibrated refusal, are well-documented, yet progress on remediation is slow because no benchmark enables systematic diagnosis. We introduce CausalT5K, a diagnostic benchmark of over 5,000 cases across 10 domains that tests three critical capabilities: (1) detecting rung collapse, where models answer interventional queries with associational evidence; (2) resisting sycophantic drift under adversarial pressure; and (3) generating Wise Refusals that specify missing information when evidence is underdetermined. Unlike synthetic benchmarks, CausalT5K embeds causal traps in realistic narratives and decomposes performance into Utility (sensitivity) and Safety (specificity), revealing failure modes invisible to aggregate accuracy. Developed through a rigorous human-machine collaborative pipeline involving 40 domain experts, iterative cross-validation cycles, and composite verification via rule-based, LLM, and human scoring, CausalT5K implements Pearl's Ladder of Causation as research infrastructure. Preliminary experiments reveal a Four-Quadrant Control Landscape where static audit policies universally fail, a finding that demonstrates CausalT5K's value for advancing trustworthy reasoning systems. Repository: https://github.com/genglongling/CausalT5kBench</summary>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-02-09T17:36:56Z</published>
    <arxiv:comment>17 pages, 20 tables, figures</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="cs.AI"/>
    <author>
      <name>Longling Geng</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Andy Ouyang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Theodore Wu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Daphne Barretto</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Matthew John Hayes</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Rachael Cooper</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yuqiao Zeng</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sameer Vijay</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Gia Ancone</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ankit Rai</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Matthew Wolfman</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Patrick Flanagan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Edward Y. Chang</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2602.08928v1</id>
    <title>Hints of sign-changing scalar field energy density and a transient acceleration phase at $z\sim 2$ from model-agnostic reconstructions</title>
    <updated>2026-02-09T17:29:55Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.08928v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2602.08928v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>We present a data-driven reconstruction of the late-time expansion history and its implications for dark-energy dynamics. Modeling the reduced Hubble rate with a node-based Gaussian-process-kernel interpolant, we constrain the reconstruction using CC, Pantheon+ SNIa, BAO data from SDSS and DESI, transversal BAO data, and external $H_0$ priors (SH0ES and H0DN). Assuming GR at the background level, we map the reconstructed kinematics onto a dark-energy fluid and a scalar-field description, yielding the total potential and kinetic contributions that reproduce the inferred $H(z)$. To interpret the reconstruction, we consider both a minimal single-field model (canonical or phantom) and a two-field (quintom) system consisting of one canonical and one phantom scalar field (or families). Within the GR-based effective-fluid mapping, the inferred dark-energy density changes sign for all dataset combinations explored, transitioning from $ρ_{\rm DE}&lt;0$ at higher redshift to $ρ_{\rm DE}&gt;0$ toward the present, and defining a transition redshift $z_\dagger$ by $ρ_{\rm DE}(z_\dagger)=0$. A single canonical scalar cannot realize such a smooth evolution during expansion, whereas a phantom field or a two-field quintom framework can accommodate the required behavior; in particular, the two-field system permits smooth phantom-divide crossings at finite $ρ_{\rm DE}&gt;0$ and distinguishes them from the separate notion of a density zero crossing. The reconstructed kinematics admit intermediate-redshift structure in some combinations, including hints of an additional accelerated-expansion interval around $z\sim 1.7$--$2.3$. The present-day equation of state remains close to a cosmological constant: combinations including supernovae give $w_0\simeq -1$, while combinations without supernovae but with an external $H_0$ prior show only a mild preference for $w_0&lt;-1$ at the $\sim1.5$--$1.7σ$ level.</summary>
    <category term="astro-ph.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="gr-qc" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-02-09T17:29:55Z</published>
    <arxiv:comment>42 pages total (24 pages main text; remainder appendices), 32 figures (4 in main text, 28 in appendices), 2 tables</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="astro-ph.CO"/>
    <author>
      <name>Özgür Akarsu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Maria Caruana</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Konstantinos F. Dialektopoulos</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Luis A. Escamilla</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Emre O. Kahya</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jackson Levi Said</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2602.08926v1</id>
    <title>The Reawakening of 4U 1755-338 after 25 Years of Quiescence: Spectro-temporal Analysis Using Multi-instrument X-ray Data</title>
    <updated>2026-02-09T17:28:59Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.08926v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2602.08926v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>The black hole X-ray binary 4U 1755$-$338 underwent an outburst in 2020 after 25 years of quiescence. The comprehensive spectral analysis revealed that the system has a low interstellar neutral hydrogen column density of $0.34\pm0.01 \times$10$^{22}$ cm$^{-2}$. The outburst began with a low mass-accretion rate and was characterized as a low-luminosity outburst. The radius of the inner accretion disc remained constant throughout the outburst. Additionally, a growing neutral medium with constant density was detected in the local environment of 4U 1755$-$338.The hardness-intensity diagram (HID) did not follow the standard q-shaped pattern, indicating a non-canonical outburst. Instead, the HID showed a correlated evolution of hardness and source flux, suggesting a thermal disc origin of the flux. A wideband spectral analysis was performed using simultaneous NICER-NuSTAR data in two frameworks, based on kerrbb and bhspec. The results of bhspec (kerrbb) based modeling indicate that 4U 1755$-$338 is a high-inclination system, $67.44_{-3.03}^{+9.75}$ ($75.25_{-4.68}^{+5.59}$) degrees, and harbors a moderately spinning black hole with a spin parameter of $0.78_{-0.14}^{+0.02}$ ($0.50_{-0.43}^{+0.19}$) and a mass of $3.37_{-1.04}^{+0.45} (3.28_{-1.1}^{+1.7})M_{\odot}$ respectively. The inferred key parameters: black hole mass, spin, and system inclination are consistent across both modeling approaches. No reflection features were detected in the spectra of 4U 1755$-$338. The high spectral index, the blackbody nature ($L\propto T^4$) of the hardness ratio, the absence of reflection signatures, and the weak variability in the power density spectra indicate that the source remained in the high/soft state throughout the outburst.</summary>
    <category term="astro-ph.HE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-02-09T17:28:59Z</published>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="astro-ph.HE"/>
    <author>
      <name>Geethu Prabhakar</name>
      <arxiv:affiliation>Department of Earth and Space Sciences, Indian Institute of Space Science and Technology</arxiv:affiliation>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Samir Mandal</name>
      <arxiv:affiliation>Department of Earth and Space Sciences, Indian Institute of Space Science and Technology</arxiv:affiliation>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2602.08897v1</id>
    <title>A Mathematical Theory of Redox Biology</title>
    <updated>2026-02-09T16:58:26Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.08897v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2602.08897v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Redox biology underpins signalling, metabolism, immunity, and adaptation, yet lacks a unifying theoretical framework capable of formalising structure, function, and dynamics. Current interpretations rely on descriptive catalogues of molecules and reactions, obscuring how redox behaviour emerges from constrained biochemical organisation. Here, we present a mathematical theory of redox biology that resolves this gap by treating redox systems as finite, compositional, dynamical, and spatially embedded objects. We define a structured redox state space in which admissible molecular transformations form a neutral algebra of possibilities. Biological function emerges when this structure is embedded within a wider molecular network and interpreted through weighted flux distributions. Time-dependent reweighting of these transformations generates redox dynamics, while spatial embedding enforces locality and causality, yielding a distributed redox field. Within this framework, context dependence, nonlinearity, hysteresis, and memory arise naturally from bounded state spaces and irreversible transformations, without requiring ad hoc assumptions. This theory provides a working, predictive interpretative basis for redox biology: it constrains admissible states and trajectories, clarifies the meaning of redox measurements, and links chemical transformation to biological behaviour. Redox biology emerges as a geometric, dynamical process governed by lawful organisation.</summary>
    <category term="q-bio.BM" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-02-09T16:58:26Z</published>
    <arxiv:comment>41 pages, 4 figures, 2 boxes</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="q-bio.BM"/>
    <author>
      <name>James N. Cobley</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Michalis G. Nikolaidis</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2602.08892v1</id>
    <title>Winner's Curse Drives False Promises in Data-Driven Decisions: A Case Study in Refugee Matching</title>
    <updated>2026-02-09T16:54:05Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.08892v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2602.08892v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>A major challenge in data-driven decision-making is accurate policy evaluation-i.e., guaranteeing that a learned decision-making policy achieves the promised benefits. A popular strategy is model-based policy evaluation, which estimates a model from data to infer counterfactual outcomes. This strategy is known to produce unwarrantedly optimistic estimates of the true benefit due to the winner's curse. We searched the recent literature on data-driven decision-making, identifying a sample of 55 papers published in the Management Science in the past decade; all but two relied on this flawed methodology. Several common justifications are provided: (1) the estimated models are accurate, stable, and well-calibrated, (2) the historical data uses random treatment assignment, (3) the model family is well-specified, and (4) the evaluation methodology uses sample splitting. Unfortunately, we show that no combination of these justifications avoids the winner's curse. First, we provide a theoretical analysis demonstrating that the winner's curse can cause large, spurious reported benefits even when all these justifications hold. Second, we perform a simulation study based on the recent and consequential data-driven refugee matching problem. We construct a synthetic refugee matching environment (calibrated to closely match the real setting) but designed so that no assignment policy can improve expected employment compared to random assignment. Model-based methods report large, stable gains of around 60% even when the true effect is zero; these gains are on par with improvements of 22-75% reported in the literature. Our results provide strong evidence against model-based evaluation.</summary>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="econ.EM" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-02-09T16:54:05Z</published>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="stat.ML"/>
    <author>
      <name>Hamsa Bastani</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Osbert Bastani</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Bryce McLaughlin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
