<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Last updated: 2025-07-09T01:00:01Z -->
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3Dall%3Acausal%20inference%26id_list%3D%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=all:causal inference&amp;id_list=&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/SsRksLzRb0LuVhSmQ+N8WbAs+f8</id>
  <updated>2025-07-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">116481</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2507.05254v1</id>
    <updated>2025-07-07T17:58:53Z</updated>
    <published>2025-07-07T17:58:53Z</published>
    <title>From Marginal to Joint Predictions: Evaluating Scene-Consistent
  Trajectory Prediction Approaches for Automated Driving</title>
    <summary>  Accurate motion prediction of surrounding traffic participants is crucial for
the safe and efficient operation of automated vehicles in dynamic environments.
Marginal prediction models commonly forecast each agent's future trajectories
independently, often leading to sub-optimal planning decisions for an automated
vehicle. In contrast, joint prediction models explicitly account for the
interactions between agents, yielding socially and physically consistent
predictions on a scene level. However, existing approaches differ not only in
their problem formulation but also in the model architectures and
implementation details used, making it difficult to compare them. In this work,
we systematically investigate different approaches to joint motion prediction,
including post-processing of the marginal predictions, explicitly training the
model for joint predictions, and framing the problem as a generative task. We
evaluate each approach in terms of prediction accuracy, multi-modality, and
inference efficiency, offering a comprehensive analysis of the strengths and
limitations of each approach. Several prediction examples are available at
https://frommarginaltojointpred.github.io/.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Fabian Konstantinidis</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ariel Dallari Guerreiro</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Raphael Trumpp</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Moritz Sackmann</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ulrich Hofmann</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Marco Caccamo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Christoph Stiller</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Accepted at International Conference on Intelligent Transportation
  Systems 2025 (ITSC 2025)</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2507.05254v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2507.05254v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.MA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2507.05244v1</id>
    <updated>2025-07-07T17:53:13Z</updated>
    <published>2025-07-07T17:53:13Z</published>
    <title>Modeling Latent Partner Strategies for Adaptive Zero-Shot Human-Agent
  Collaboration</title>
    <summary>  In collaborative tasks, being able to adapt to your teammates is a necessary
requirement for success. When teammates are heterogeneous, such as in
human-agent teams, agents need to be able to observe, recognize, and adapt to
their human partners in real time. This becomes particularly challenging in
tasks with time pressure and complex strategic spaces where the dynamics can
change rapidly. In this work, we introduce TALENTS, a strategy-conditioned
cooperator framework that learns to represent, categorize, and adapt to a range
of partner strategies, enabling ad-hoc teamwork. Our approach utilizes a
variational autoencoder to learn a latent strategy space from trajectory data.
This latent space represents the underlying strategies that agents employ.
Subsequently, the system identifies different types of strategy by clustering
the data. Finally, a cooperator agent is trained to generate partners for each
type of strategy, conditioned on these clusters. In order to adapt to
previously unseen partners, we leverage a fixed-share regret minimization
algorithm that infers and adjusts the estimated partner strategy dynamically.
We assess our approach in a customized version of the Overcooked environment,
posing a challenging cooperative cooking task that demands strong coordination
across a wide range of possible strategies. Using an online user study, we show
that our agent outperforms current baselines when working with unfamiliar human
partners.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Benjamin Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Shuyang Shi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lucia Romero</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Huao Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yaqi Xie</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Woojun Kim</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Stefanos Nikolaidis</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Michael Lewis</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Katia Sycara</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Stepputtis</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Best Paper Award at the RSS 2025 Generative Models x HRI (GenAI-HRI)
  Workshop</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2507.05244v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2507.05244v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.MA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2507.05240v1</id>
    <updated>2025-07-07T17:49:41Z</updated>
    <published>2025-07-07T17:49:41Z</published>
    <title>StreamVLN: Streaming Vision-and-Language Navigation via SlowFast Context
  Modeling</title>
    <summary>  Vision-and-Language Navigation (VLN) in real-world settings requires agents
to process continuous visual streams and generate actions with low latency
grounded in language instructions. While Video-based Large Language Models
(Video-LLMs) have driven recent progress, current VLN methods based on
Video-LLM often face trade-offs among fine-grained visual understanding,
long-term context modeling and computational efficiency. We introduce
StreamVLN, a streaming VLN framework that employs a hybrid slow-fast context
modeling strategy to support multi-modal reasoning over interleaved vision,
language and action inputs. The fast-streaming dialogue context facilitates
responsive action generation through a sliding-window of active dialogues,
while the slow-updating memory context compresses historical visual states
using a 3D-aware token pruning strategy. With this slow-fast design, StreamVLN
achieves coherent multi-turn dialogue through efficient KV cache reuse,
supporting long video streams with bounded context size and inference cost.
Experiments on VLN-CE benchmarks demonstrate state-of-the-art performance with
stable low latency, ensuring robustness and efficiency in real-world
deployment. The project page is:
\href{https://streamvln.github.io/}{https://streamvln.github.io/}.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Meng Wei</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Chenyang Wan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xiqian Yu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tai Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yuqiang Yang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xiaohan Mao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Chenming Zhu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Wenzhe Cai</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hanqing Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yilun Chen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xihui Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jiangmiao Pang</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2507.05240v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2507.05240v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2507.05229v1</id>
    <updated>2025-07-07T17:39:11Z</updated>
    <published>2025-07-07T17:39:11Z</published>
    <title>Self-Supervised Real-Time Tracking of Military Vehicles in Low-FPS UAV
  Footage</title>
    <summary>  Multi-object tracking (MOT) aims to maintain consistent identities of objects
across video frames. Associating objects in low-frame-rate videos captured by
moving unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs) in actual combat scenarios is complex
due to rapid changes in object appearance and position within the frame. The
task becomes even more challenging due to image degradation caused by cloud
video streaming and compression algorithms. We present how instance association
learning from single-frame annotations can overcome these challenges. We show
that global features of the scene provide crucial context for low-FPS instance
association, allowing our solution to be robust to distractors and gaps in
detections. We also demonstrate that such a tracking approach maintains high
association quality even when reducing the input image resolution and latent
representation size for faster inference. Finally, we present a benchmark
dataset of annotated military vehicles collected from publicly available data
sources. This paper was initially presented at the NATO Science and Technology
Organization Symposium (ICMCIS) organized by the Information Systems Technology
(IST)Scientific and Technical Committee, IST-209-RSY - the ICMCIS, held in
Oeiras, Portugal, 13-14 May 2025.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Markiyan Kostiv</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Anatolii Adamovskyi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yevhen Cherniavskyi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mykyta Varenyk</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ostap Viniavskyi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Igor Krashenyi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Oles Dobosevych</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:doi xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">10.1109/ICMCIS64378.2025.11047873</arxiv:doi>
    <link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/ICMCIS64378.2025.11047873" rel="related"/>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2507.05229v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2507.05229v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2507.05228v1</id>
    <updated>2025-07-07T17:37:16Z</updated>
    <published>2025-07-07T17:37:16Z</published>
    <title>Cascade: Token-Sharded Private LLM Inference</title>
    <summary>  As LLMs continue to increase in parameter size, the computational resources
required to run them are available to fewer parties. Therefore, third-party
inference services -- where LLMs are hosted by third parties with significant
computational resources -- are becoming increasingly popular. However, third
party inference raises critical concerns about user data privacy. To mitigate
these risks, privacy researchers have developed provably secure schemes for
third-party inference, such as Secure Multi-Party Computation (SMPC). However,
SMPC protocols have significant computational and communication overhead, and
do not scale to large models. In this work, we propose a new multi-party
inference protocol, Cascade, that avoids these punitive costs by leveraging
sharding in the sequence dimension to maintain privacy, trading off
cryptographic privacy guarantees for increased performance and scalability. We
demonstrate that Cascade is resistant to a generalization of a recent attack
that is highly effective against other statistical privacy schemes, and that it
is further resistant to learning-based attacks. As Cascade is orders of
magnitude faster than existing schemes, our findings offer practical solutions
for secure deployment of modern state-of-the-art LLMs.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Rahul Thomas</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Louai Zahran</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Erica Choi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Akilesh Potti</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Micah Goldblum</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Arka Pal</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">To be published in ICML 2025 Main Proceedings as "Hidden No More:
  Attacking and Defending Private Third-Party LLM Inference", together with
  arXiv:2505.18332</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2507.05228v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2507.05228v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2507.05220v1</id>
    <updated>2025-07-07T17:33:18Z</updated>
    <published>2025-07-07T17:33:18Z</published>
    <title>QuEst: Enhancing Estimates of Quantile-Based Distributional Measures
  Using Model Predictions</title>
    <summary>  As machine learning models grow increasingly competent, their predictions can
supplement scarce or expensive data in various important domains. In support of
this paradigm, algorithms have emerged to combine a small amount of
high-fidelity observed data with a much larger set of imputed model outputs to
estimate some quantity of interest. Yet current hybrid-inference tools target
only means or single quantiles, limiting their applicability for many critical
domains and use cases. We present QuEst, a principled framework to merge
observed and imputed data to deliver point estimates and rigorous confidence
intervals for a wide family of quantile-based distributional measures. QuEst
covers a range of measures, from tail risk (CVaR) to population segments such
as quartiles, that are central to fields such as economics, sociology,
education, medicine, and more. We extend QuEst to multidimensional metrics, and
introduce an additional optimization technique to further reduce variance in
this and other hybrid estimators. We demonstrate the utility of our framework
through experiments in economic modeling, opinion polling, and language model
auto-evaluation.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Zhun Deng</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Thomas P Zollo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Benjamin Eyre</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Amogh Inamdar</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>David Madras</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Zemel</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Published as a conference paper at ICML 2025</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2507.05220v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2507.05220v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2507.05215v1</id>
    <updated>2025-07-07T17:29:08Z</updated>
    <published>2025-07-07T17:29:08Z</published>
    <title>Testing the ubiquitous presence of very high energy emission in
  gamma-ray bursts with the MAGIC telescopes</title>
    <summary>  Gamma-ray bursts (GRBs) are the most powerful transient objects in the
Universe, and they are a primary target for the MAGIC Collaboration.
Recognizing the challenges of observing these elusive objects with Imaging
Atmospheric Cherenkov Telescopes (IACTs), we implemented a dedicated
observational strategy that included an automated procedure for rapid
re-pointing to transient sources. Since 2013, this automated procedure has
enabled MAGIC to observe GRBs at a rate of approximately ten per year, which
led to the successful detection of two GRBs at very high energies (VHE; E &gt; 100
GeV). We present a comprehensive analysis of 42 non-detected GRBs (4 short
GRBs) observed by MAGIC from 2013 to 2019. We derived upper limits (ULs) on the
observed energy flux as well as on the intrinsic energy flux corrected for
absorption by the extragalactic background light (EBL) from the MAGIC
observations in selected energy and time intervals. We conducted a
comprehensive study of their properties to investigate the reasons for these
non-detections, including the possible peculiar properties of TeV-detected
GRBs. We find that strong EBL absorption significantly hinders TeV detection
for the majority of GRBs in our sample. For a subset of 6 GRBs with redshift z
&lt; 2, we compared the UL on the intrinsic flux in the VHE domain with the
simultaneous X-ray flux, which is observed to be at the same level in the
current population of TeV-detected GRBs. Based on these inferred MAGIC ULs, we
conclude that a VHE component with a luminosity comparable to the
simultaneously observed X-ray luminosity cannot be ruled out for this sample.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>S. Abe</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>J. Abhir</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>A. Abhishek</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>V. A. Acciari</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>A. Aguasca-Cabot</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>I. Agudo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>T. Aniello</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>S. Ansoldi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>L. A. Antonelli</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>A. Arbet Engels</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>C. Arcaro</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>T. T. H. Arnesen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>K. Asano</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>A. Babic</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>C. Bakshi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>U. Barres de Almeida</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>J. A. Barrio</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>L. Barrios-Jimenez</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>I. Batkovic</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>J. Baxter</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>J. Becerra Gonzalez</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>W. Bednarek</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>E. Bernardini</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>J. Bernete</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>A. Berti</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>J. Besenrieder</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>C. Bigongiari</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>A. Biland</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>O. Blanch</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>G. Bonnoli</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ž. Bošnjak</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>E. Bronzini</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>I. Burelli</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>A. Campoy-Ordaz</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>A. Carosi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>R. Carosi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>M. Carretero-Castrillo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>A. J. Castro-Tirado</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>D. Cerasole</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>G. Ceribella</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Y. Chai</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>A. Cifuentes</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>J. L. Contreras</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>J. Cortina</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>S. Covino</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>G. D'Amico</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>P. Da Vela</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>F. Dazzi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>A. De Angelis</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>B. De Lotto</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>R. de Menezes</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>M. Delfino</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>J. Delgado</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>C. Delgado Mendez</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>F. Di Pierro</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>R. Di Tria</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>L. Di Venere</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>A. Dinesh</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>D. Dominis Prester</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>A. Donini</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>D. Dorner</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>M. Doro</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>L. Eisenberger</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>D. Elsaesser</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>J. Escudero</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>L. Fariña</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>A. Fattorini</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>L. Foffano</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>L. Font</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>S. Fröse</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>S. Fukami</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Y. Fukazawa</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>R. J. García López</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>S. García Soto</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>M. Garczarczyk</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>S. Gasparyan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>M. Gaug</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>J. G. Giesbrecht Paiva</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>N. Giglietto</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>F. Giordano</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>P. Gliwny</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>N. Godinovic</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>T. Gradetzke</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>R. Grau</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>D. Green</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>J. G. Green</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>P. Günther</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>D. Hadasch</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>A. Hahn</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>T. Hassan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>L. Heckmann</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>J. Herrera Llorente</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>D. Hrupec</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>R. Imazawa</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>S. Inoue</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>D. Israyelyan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>J. Jahanvi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>I. Jiménez Martínez</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>J. Jiménez Quiles</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>J. Jormanainen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>S. Kankkunen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>T. Kayanoki</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>J. Konrad</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>P. M. Kouch</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>H. Kubo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>J. Kushida</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>M. Láinez</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>A. Lamastra</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>E. Lindfors</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>S. Lombardi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>F. Longo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>R. López-Coto</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>M. López-Moya</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>A. López-Oramas</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>S. Loporchio</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>L. Lulic</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>E. Lyard</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>P. Majumdar</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>M. Makariev</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>M. Mallamaci</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>G. Maneva</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>M. Manganaro</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>S. Mangano</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>K. Mannheim</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>S. Marchesi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>M. Mariotti</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>M. Martínez</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>P. Maruševec</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>A. Mas-Aguilar</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>D. Mazin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>S. Menchiari</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>J. Méndez Gallego</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>S. Menon</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>D. Miceli</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>J. M. Miranda</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>R. Mirzoyan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>M. Molero González</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>E. Molina</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>H. A. Mondal</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>A. Moralejo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>E. Moretti</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>T. Nakamori</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>C. Nanci</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>L. Nava</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>V. Neustroev</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>L. Nickel</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>M. Nievas Rosillo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>C. Nigro</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>L. Nikolic</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>K. Nilsson</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>K. Nishijima</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>K. Noda</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>S. Nozaki</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>A. Okumura</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>J. Otero-Santos</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>S. Paiano</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>D. Paneque</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>R. Paoletti</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>J. M. Paredes</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>M. Peresano</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>M. Persic</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>M. Pihet</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>G. Pirola</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>F. Podobnik</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>P. G. Prada Moroni</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>E. Prandini</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>M. Ribó</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>J. Rico</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>C. Righi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>N. Sahakyan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>T. Saito</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>F. G. Saturni</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>K. Schmitz</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>F. Schmuckermaier</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>A. Sciaccaluga</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>G. Silvestri</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>A. Simongini</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>J. Sitarek</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>V. Sliusar</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>D. Sobczynska</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>A. Stamerra</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>J. Striškovic</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>D. Strom</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>M. Strzys</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Y. Suda</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>H. Tajima</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>M. Takahashi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>R. Takeishi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>P. Temnikov</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>K. Terauchi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>T. Terzic</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>M. Teshima</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>A. Tutone</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>S. Ubach</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>J. van Scherpenberg</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>M. Vazquez Acosta</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>S. Ventura</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>G. Verna</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>I. Viale</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>A. Vigliano</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>C. F. Vigorito</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>E. Visentin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>V. Vitale</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>I. Vovk</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>R. Walter</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>F. Wersig</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>M. Will</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>T. Yamamoto</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>P. K. H. Yeung</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Accepted for publication in A&amp;A</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2507.05215v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2507.05215v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="astro-ph.HE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.HE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2507.05210v1</id>
    <updated>2025-07-07T17:20:34Z</updated>
    <published>2025-07-07T17:20:34Z</published>
    <title>Identification of Causal Effects with a Bunching Design</title>
    <summary>  We show that causal effects can be identified when there is bunching in the
distribution of a continuous treatment variable, without imposing any
parametric assumptions. This yields a new nonparametric method for overcoming
selection bias in the absence of instrumental variables, panel data, or other
popular research designs for causal inference. The method leverages the change
of variables theorem from integration theory, relating the selection bias to
the ratio of the density of the treatment and the density of the part of the
outcome that varies with confounders. At the bunching point, the treatment
level is constant, so the variation in the outcomes is due entirely to
unobservables, allowing us to identify the denominator. Our main result
identifies the average causal response to the treatment among individuals who
marginally select into the bunching point. We further show that under
additional smoothness assumptions on the selection bias, treatment effects away
from the bunching point may also be identified. We propose estimators based on
standard software packages and apply the method to estimate the effect of
maternal smoking during pregnancy on birth weight.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Carolina Caetano</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Gregorio Caetano</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Leonard Goff</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Eric Nielsen</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2507.05210v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2507.05210v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="econ.EM" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="econ.EM" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2507.05209v1</id>
    <updated>2025-07-07T17:19:21Z</updated>
    <published>2025-07-07T17:19:21Z</published>
    <title>Hierarchical Subtraction with Neural Density Estimators as a General
  Solution to Overlapping Gravitational Wave Signals</title>
    <summary>  Overlapping gravitational wave (GW) signals are expected in the
third-generation (3G) GW detectors, leading to one of the major challenges in
GW data analysis. Inference of overlapping GW sources is complicated - it has
been reported that hierarchical inference with signal subtraction may amplify
errors, while joint estimation, though more accurate, is computationally
expensive. However, in this work, we show that hierarchical subtraction can
achieve accurate results with a sufficient number of iterations, and on the
other hand, neural density estimators, being able to generate posterior samples
rapidly, make it possible to perform signal subtraction and inference
repeatedly. We further develop likelihood-based resampling to accelerate the
convergence of the iterative subtraction. Our method provides fast and accurate
inference for overlapping GW signals and is highly adaptable to various source
types and time separations, offering a potential general solution for
overlapping GW signal analysis.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Qian Hu</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">11 pages, 4 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2507.05209v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2507.05209v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="gr-qc" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="gr-qc" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.HE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.IM" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2507.05176v1</id>
    <updated>2025-07-07T16:31:07Z</updated>
    <published>2025-07-07T16:31:07Z</published>
    <title>Mass Proxy Quality of Massive Halo Properties in the IllustrisTNG and
  FLAMINGO Simulations: I. Hot Gas</title>
    <summary>  We examine scale and redshift dependence of mass-property relations (MPRs)
for five hot gas properties of two large group- and cluster-scale halo samples
realized by the IllustrisTNG, TNG-Cluster and FLAMINGO cosmological
hydrodynamical simulations. For intrinsic properties of i) hot gas mass
($M_{\rm gas}$), ii) spectroscopic-like temperature ($T_{\rm sl}$), iii)
soft-band X-ray luminosity ($L_{\rm X}$), and iv) X-ray ($Y_{\rm X}$) and v)
Sunyaev-Zel'dovich ($Y_{\rm SZ}$) thermal energies, we use MPR parameters to
infer mass proxy quality (MPQ) -- the implied scatter in total halo mass
conditioned on a property -- for halos with $M_{\rm 500c} \geq 10^{13}{\, {\rm
M}_\odot}$ at redshifts, $z \in \{0, 0.5, 1, 2\}$. We find: (1) in general,
scaling relation slopes and covariance display moderate to strong dependence on
halo mass, with redshift dependence secondary, (2) for halos with $M_{\rm 500c}
&gt; 10^{14}{\, {\rm M}_\odot}$, scalings of $M_{\rm gas}$ and $Y_{\rm SZ}$
simplify toward self-similar slope and constant intrinsic scatter (5 and 10%,
respectively) nearly independent of scale, making both measures ideal for
cluster finding and characterization to $z=2$, (3) halo mass-conditioned
likelihoods of hot gas mass and thermal energy at fixed halo mass closely
follow a log-normal form, (4) despite normalization differences ranging up to
$0.4$ dex, there is good qualitative, and often quantitative, agreement between
the scale-dependent slopes and property covariance of the two simulations.
Slopes show appreciable redshift dependence at the group scale, while redshift
dependence of the scatter is exhibited by low mass FLAMINGO halos only, (5)
property correlations are largely consistent between the simulations, with
values that mainly agree with existing empirical measurements. We close with a
literature survey placing our MPR slopes and intrinsic scatter estimates into
context.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Eddie Aljamal</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>August E. Evrard</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Arya Farahi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Annalisa Pillepich</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Dylan Nelson</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Joop Schaye</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Matthieu Schaller</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Joey Braspenning</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">23 pages, 14 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2507.05176v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2507.05176v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
