<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Last updated: 2025-08-06T01:03:19Z -->
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3Dall%3Acausal%20inference%26id_list%3D%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=all:causal inference&amp;id_list=&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/SsRksLzRb0LuVhSmQ+N8WbAs+f8</id>
  <updated>2025-08-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">118243</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.02666v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-04T17:55:49Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-04T17:55:49Z</published>
    <title>Testing Dark Matter with Generative Models for Extragalactic Stellar
  Streams</title>
    <summary>  Upcoming ground and space-based surveys are poised to illuminate low surface
brightness tidal features, providing a new observable connection to dark matter
physics. From imaging of tidal debris, the morphology of stellar streams can be
used to infer the geometry of dark matter halos. In this paper, we develop a
generative approach, X-Stream, which translates stream imaging into constraints
on the radial density profile of dark matter halos--from the inner region out
to the virial radius. Using the GPU-accelerated code streamsculptor, we
generate thousands of stream realizations in trial gravitational potentials and
apply nested sampling with a custom objective function to explore viable
regions of parameter space. We find that multiple stellar streams can be used
to constrain the entire radial density profile of a halo, including both its
inner and outer density slopes. These constraints provide a test for
alternatives to cold dark matter, such as self-interacting dark matter, which
predicts cored density profiles. From cosmological simulations, the outer
density slope is expected to correlate with merger histories though remains
underexplored observationally. With ongoing and upcoming missions such as
Euclid, the Rubin Observatory, ARRAKIHS, and the Nancy Grace Roman Space
Telescope, X-Stream will enable detailed mapping of dark matter for thousands
of galaxies across a wide range of redshifts and halo masses.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Nibauer</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sarah Pearson</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">24 pages, 12 figures, 2 tables. Submitted to AAS Journals. Comments
  welcome</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.02666v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.02666v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.02647v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-04T17:38:12Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-04T17:38:12Z</published>
    <title>Optimal Adjustment and Combination of Independent Discrete $p$-Values</title>
    <summary>  Combining p-values from multiple independent tests is a fundamental task in
statistical inference, but presents unique challenges when the p-values are
discrete. We extend a recent optimal transport-based framework for combining
discrete p-values, which constructs a continuous surrogate distribution by
minimizing the Wasserstein distance between the transformed discrete null and
its continuous analogue. We provide a unified approach for several classical
combination methods, including Fisher's, Pearson's, George's, Stouffer's, and
Edgington's statistics. Our theoretical analysis and extensive simulations show
that accurate Type I error control is achieved when the variance of the
adjusted discrete statistic closely matches that of the continuous case. We
further demonstrate that, when the likelihood ratio test is a monotonic
function of a combination statistic, the proposed approximation achieves power
comparable to the uniformly most powerful (UMP) test. The methodology is
illustrated with a genetic association study of rare variants using
case-control data, and is implemented in the R package DPComb.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Gonzalo Contador</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zheyang Wu</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.02647v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.02647v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="stat.ME" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ME" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.ST" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.TH" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.02630v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-04T17:19:36Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-04T17:19:36Z</published>
    <title>What Is Your AI Agent Buying? Evaluation, Implications and Emerging
  Questions for Agentic E-Commerce</title>
    <summary>  Online marketplaces will be transformed by autonomous AI agents acting on
behalf of consumers. Rather than humans browsing and clicking,
vision-language-model (VLM) agents can parse webpages, evaluate products, and
transact. This raises a fundamental question: what do AI agents buy, and why?
We develop ACES, a sandbox environment that pairs a platform-agnostic VLM agent
with a fully programmable mock marketplace to study this question. We first
conduct basic rationality checks in the context of simple tasks, and then, by
randomizing product positions, prices, ratings, reviews, sponsored tags, and
platform endorsements, we obtain causal estimates of how frontier VLMs actually
shop. Models show strong but heterogeneous position effects: all favor the top
row, yet different models prefer different columns, undermining the assumption
of a universal "top" rank. They penalize sponsored tags and reward
endorsements. Sensitivities to price, ratings, and reviews are directionally
human-like but vary sharply in magnitude across models. Motivated by scenarios
where sellers use AI agents to optimize product listings, we show that a
seller-side agent that makes minor tweaks to product descriptions, targeting AI
buyer preferences, can deliver substantial market-share gains if AI-mediated
shopping dominates. We also find that modal product choices can differ across
models and, in some cases, demand may concentrate on a few select products,
raising competition questions. Together, our results illuminate how AI agents
may behave in e-commerce settings and surface concrete seller strategy,
platform design, and regulatory questions in an AI-mediated ecosystem.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Amine Allouah</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Omar Besbes</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Josué D Figueroa</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yash Kanoria</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Akshit Kumar</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.02630v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.02630v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CY" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.HC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.MA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="econ.GN" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="q-fin.EC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.02629v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-04T17:18:14Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-04T17:18:14Z</published>
    <title>HyCodePolicy: Hybrid Language Controllers for Multimodal Monitoring and
  Decision in Embodied Agents</title>
    <summary>  Recent advances in multimodal large language models (MLLMs) have enabled
richer perceptual grounding for code policy generation in embodied agents.
However, most existing systems lack effective mechanisms to adaptively monitor
policy execution and repair codes during task completion. In this work, we
introduce HyCodePolicy, a hybrid language-based control framework that
systematically integrates code synthesis, geometric grounding, perceptual
monitoring, and iterative repair into a closed-loop programming cycle for
embodied agents. Technically, given a natural language instruction, our system
first decomposes it into subgoals and generates an initial executable program
grounded in object-centric geometric primitives. The program is then executed
in simulation, while a vision-language model (VLM) observes selected
checkpoints to detect and localize execution failures and infer failure
reasons. By fusing structured execution traces capturing program-level events
with VLM-based perceptual feedback, HyCodePolicy infers failure causes and
repairs programs. This hybrid dual feedback mechanism enables self-correcting
program synthesis with minimal human supervision. Our results demonstrate that
HyCodePolicy significantly improves the robustness and sample efficiency of
robot manipulation policies, offering a scalable strategy for integrating
multimodal reasoning into autonomous decision-making pipelines.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Yibin Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zhixuan Liang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zanxin Chen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tianxing Chen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mengkang Hu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Wanxi Dong</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Congsheng Xu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zhaoming Han</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yusen Qin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yao Mu</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Accepted to ICCV 2025 Workshop on Multi-Modal Reasoning for Agentic
  Intelligence</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.02629v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.02629v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.02618v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-04T17:06:23Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-04T17:06:23Z</published>
    <title>Mitigating Attention Hacking in Preference-Based Reward Modeling via
  Interaction Distillation</title>
    <summary>  The reward model (RM), as the core component of reinforcement learning from
human feedback (RLHF) for large language models (LLMs), responsible for
providing reward signals to generated responses. However, mainstream preference
modeling in RM is inadequate in terms of token-level interaction, making its
judgment signals vulnerable to being hacked by misallocated attention to
context. This stems from two fundamental limitations: (1) Current preference
modeling employs decoder-only architectures, where the unidirectional causal
attention mechanism leads to forward-decaying intra-sequence attention within
the prompt-response sequence. (2) The independent Siamese-encoding paradigm
induces the absence of token-level inter-sequence attention between chosen and
rejected sequences. To address this "attention hacking", we propose
"Interaction Distillation", a novel training framework for more adequate
preference modeling through attention-level optimization. The method introduces
an interaction-based natural language understanding model as the teacher to
provide sophisticated token interaction patterns via comprehensive attention,
and guides the preference modeling to simulate teacher model's interaction
pattern through an attentional alignment objective. Through extensive
experiments, interaction distillation has demonstrated its ability to provide
more stable and generalizable reward signals compared to state-of-the-art RM
optimization methods that target data noise, highlighting the attention hacking
constitute a more fundamental limitation in RM.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Jianxiang Zang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Meiling Ning</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Shihan Dou</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jiazheng Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tao Gui</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Qi Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xuanjing Huang</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.02618v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.02618v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.02602v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-04T16:56:11Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-04T16:56:11Z</published>
    <title>Trustworthy scientific inference for inverse problems with generative
  models</title>
    <summary>  Generative artificial intelligence (AI) excels at producing complex data
structures (text, images, videos) by learning patterns from training examples.
Across scientific disciplines, researchers are now applying generative models
to ``inverse problems'' to infer hidden parameters from observed data. While
these methods can handle intractable models and large-scale studies, they can
also produce biased or overconfident conclusions. We present a solution with
Frequentist-Bayes (FreB), a mathematically rigorous protocol that reshapes
AI-generated probability distributions into confidence regions that
consistently include true parameters with the expected probability, while
achieving minimum size when training and target data align. We demonstrate
FreB's effectiveness by tackling diverse case studies in the physical sciences:
identifying unknown sources under dataset shift, reconciling competing
theoretical models, and mitigating selection bias and systematics in
observational studies. By providing validity guarantees with interpretable
diagnostics, FreB enables trustworthy scientific inference across fields where
direct likelihood evaluation remains impossible or prohibitively expensive.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>James Carzon</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Luca Masserano</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Joshua D. Ingram</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alex Shen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Antonio Carlos Herling Ribeiro Junior</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tommaso Dorigo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Michele Doro</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Joshua S. Speagle</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Rafael Izbicki</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ann B. Lee</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.02602v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.02602v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.IM" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.AP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ME" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.02585v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-04T16:40:33Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-04T16:40:33Z</published>
    <title>Variational Bernstein-von Mises theorem with increasing parameter
  dimension</title>
    <summary>  Variational Bayes (VB) provides a computationally efficient alternative to
Markov Chain Monte Carlo, especially for high-dimensional and large-scale
inference. However, existing theory on VB primarily focuses on
fixed-dimensional settings or specific models. To address this limitation, this
paper develops a finite-sample theory for VB in a broad class of parametric
models with latent variables. We establish theoretical properties of the VB
posterior, including a non-asymptotic variational Bernstein--von Mises theorem.
Furthermore, we derive consistency and asymptotic normality of the VB
estimator. An application to multivariate Gaussian mixture models is presented
for illustration.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Jiawei Yan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Peirong Xu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tao Wang</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.02585v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.02585v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="math.ST" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.ST" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.TH" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.02583v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-04T16:39:24Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-04T16:39:24Z</published>
    <title>CAMA: Enhancing Mathematical Reasoning in Large Language Models with
  Causal Knowledge</title>
    <summary>  Large Language Models (LLMs) have demonstrated strong performance across a
wide range of tasks, yet they still struggle with complex mathematical
reasoning, a challenge fundamentally rooted in deep structural dependencies. To
address this challenge, we propose \textbf{CA}usal \textbf{MA}thematician
(\textbf{CAMA}), a two-stage causal framework that equips LLMs with explicit,
reusable mathematical structure. In the learning stage, CAMA first constructs
the \textbf{M}athematical \textbf{C}ausal \textbf{G}raph (\textbf{MCG}), a
high-level representation of solution strategies, by combining LLM priors with
causal discovery algorithms applied to a corpus of question-solution pairs. The
resulting MCG encodes essential knowledge points and their causal dependencies.
To better align the graph with downstream reasoning tasks, CAMA further refines
the MCG through iterative feedback derived from a selected subset of the
question-solution pairs. In the reasoning stage, given a new question, CAMA
dynamically extracts a task-relevant subgraph from the MCG, conditioned on both
the question content and the LLM's intermediate reasoning trace. This subgraph,
which encodes the most pertinent knowledge points and their causal
dependencies, is then injected back into the LLM to guide its reasoning
process. Empirical results on real-world datasets show that CAMA significantly
improves LLM performance on challenging mathematical problems. Furthermore, our
experiments demonstrate that structured guidance consistently outperforms
unstructured alternatives, and that incorporating asymmetric causal
relationships yields greater improvements than using symmetric associations
alone.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Lei Zan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Keli Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ruichu Cai</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lujia Pan</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.02583v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.02583v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.02571v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-04T16:26:17Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-04T16:26:17Z</published>
    <title>ASINT: Learning AS-to-Organization Mapping from Internet Metadata</title>
    <summary>  Accurately mapping Autonomous Systems (ASNs) to their owning or operating
organizations underpins Internet measurement research and security
applications. Yet existing approaches commonly rely solely on WHOIS or
PeeringDB, missing important relationships (e.g., cross-regional aliases,
parent-child ownership) and failing to unify organizations scattered across
different RIR identifiers. We introduce ASINT, an end-to-end pipeline that
fuses bulk registry data with unstructured Web sources, then employs
retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) to guide large language model (LLM)
inference. Through a multi-stage procedure, ASINT merges ASNs into
"organization families," capturing nuanced ties beyond the scope of simpler
heuristics.
  ASINT maps 111,470 ASNs to 81,233 organization families; compared to both
AS2ORG+ and AS-Sibling, ASINT identifies more cross-regional groupings (e.g.,
operator aliases, rebrands) that other datasets overlook. Moreover, our refined
mappings enhance multiple security and measurement tasks: ASINT exposes 27.5%
more intra-organizational RPKI misconfigurations, cuts false-positive hijack
alarms by 9.4%, and lowers erroneous IP leasing inferences by 5.9%.
  Finally, ASINT supports periodic updates and cost-sensitive LLM selection,
demonstrating that broader Web evidence can provide a more accurate, evolving
view of the Internet's organizational structure.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Yongzhe Xu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Weitong Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Eeshan Umrani</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Taejoong Chung</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.02571v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.02571v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.NI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.NI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.02558v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-04T16:14:03Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-04T16:14:03Z</published>
    <title>Sparse-dLLM: Accelerating Diffusion LLMs with Dynamic Cache Eviction</title>
    <summary>  Diffusion Large Language Models (dLLMs) enable breakthroughs in reasoning and
parallel decoding but suffer from prohibitive quadratic computational
complexity and memory overhead during inference. Current caching techniques
accelerate decoding by storing full-layer states, yet impose substantial memory
usage that limit long-context applications. Our analysis of attention patterns
in dLLMs reveals persistent cross-layer sparsity, with pivotal tokens remaining
salient across decoding steps and low-relevance tokens staying unimportant,
motivating selective cache eviction. We propose Sparse-dLLM, the first
training-free framework integrating dynamic cache eviction with sparse
attention via delayed bidirectional sparse caching. By leveraging the stability
of token saliency over steps, it retains critical tokens and dynamically evicts
unimportant prefix/suffix entries using an attention-guided strategy. Extensive
experiments on LLaDA and Dream series demonstrate Sparse-dLLM achieves up to
10$\times$ higher throughput than vanilla dLLMs, with comparable performance
and similar peak memory costs, outperforming previous methods in efficiency and
effectiveness.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Yuerong Song</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xiaoran Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ruixiao Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zhigeng Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zengfeng Huang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Qipeng Guo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ziwei He</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xipeng Qiu</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">11 pages, 6 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.02558v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.02558v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
