<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Last updated: 2025-05-08T00:56:28Z -->
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3Dall%3Acausal%20inference%26id_list%3D%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=all:causal inference&amp;id_list=&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/SsRksLzRb0LuVhSmQ+N8WbAs+f8</id>
  <updated>2025-05-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">111796</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.03739v1</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T17:59:53Z</updated>
    <published>2025-05-06T17:59:53Z</published>
    <title>VITA-Audio: Fast Interleaved Cross-Modal Token Generation for Efficient
  Large Speech-Language Model</title>
    <summary>  With the growing requirement for natural human-computer interaction,
speech-based systems receive increasing attention as speech is one of the most
common forms of daily communication. However, the existing speech models still
experience high latency when generating the first audio token during streaming,
which poses a significant bottleneck for deployment. To address this issue, we
propose VITA-Audio, an end-to-end large speech model with fast audio-text token
generation. Specifically, we introduce a lightweight Multiple Cross-modal Token
Prediction (MCTP) module that efficiently generates multiple audio tokens
within a single model forward pass, which not only accelerates the inference
but also significantly reduces the latency for generating the first audio in
streaming scenarios. In addition, a four-stage progressive training strategy is
explored to achieve model acceleration with minimal loss of speech quality. To
our knowledge, VITA-Audio is the first multi-modal large language model capable
of generating audio output during the first forward pass, enabling real-time
conversational capabilities with minimal latency. VITA-Audio is fully
reproducible and is trained on open-source data only. Experimental results
demonstrate that our model achieves an inference speedup of 3~5x at the 7B
parameter scale, but also significantly outperforms open-source models of
similar model size on multiple benchmarks for automatic speech recognition
(ASR), text-to-speech (TTS), and spoken question answering (SQA) tasks.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Zuwei Long</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yunhang Shen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Chaoyou Fu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Heting Gao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lijiang Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Peixian Chen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mengdan Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hang Shao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jian Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jinlong Peng</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Haoyu Cao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ke Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Rongrong Ji</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xing Sun</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Training and Inference Codes: https://github.com/VITA-MLLM/VITA-Audio</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.03739v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2505.03739v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.03737v1</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T17:59:45Z</updated>
    <published>2025-05-06T17:59:45Z</published>
    <title>Impact of Galactic non-Gaussian foregrounds on CMB lensing measurements</title>
    <summary>  Weak gravitational lensing of the CMB has been established as a robust and
powerful observable for precision cosmology. However, the impact of Galactic
foregrounds, which has been studied less extensively than many other potential
systematics, could in principle pose a problem for CMB lensing measurements.
These foregrounds are inherently non-Gaussian and hence might mimic the
characteristic signal that lensing estimators are designed to measure. We
present an analysis that quantifies the level of contamination from Galactic
dust in lensing measurements, focusing particularly on measurements with the
Atacama Cosmology Telescope and the Simons Observatory. We employ a whole suite
of foreground models and study the contamination of lensing measurements with
both individual frequency channels and multifrequency combinations. We test the
sensitivity of different estimators to the level of foreground non-Gaussianity,
and the dependence on sky fraction and multipole range used. We find that
Galactic foregrounds do not present a problem for the Atacama Cosmology
Telescope experiment (the bias in the inferred CMB lensing power spectrum
amplitude remains below $0.3\sigma$). For Simons Observatory, not all
foreground models remain below this threshold. Although our results are
conservative upper limits, they suggest that further work on characterizing
dust biases and determining the impact of mitigation methods is well motivated,
especially for the largest sky fractions.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Irene Abril-Cabezas</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Frank J. Qu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Blake D. Sherwin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alexander van Engelen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Niall MacCrann</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Carlos Hervías-Caimapo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Omar Darwish</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>J. Colin Hill</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mathew S. Madhavacheril</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Neelima Sehgal</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">24 pages, 16 figures, prepared for submission to PRD, comments
  welcome</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.03737v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2505.03737v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="astro-ph.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.03732v1</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T17:59:10Z</updated>
    <published>2025-05-06T17:59:10Z</published>
    <title>A Communication-First Account of Explanation</title>
    <summary>  This paper develops a formal account of causal explanation, grounded in a
theory of conversational pragmatics, and inspired by the interventionist idea
that explanation is about asking and answering
what-if-things-had-been-different questions. We illustrate the fruitfulness of
the account, relative to previous accounts, by showing that widely recognised
explanatory virtues emerge naturally, as do subtle empirical patterns
concerning the impact of norms on causal judgments. This shows the value of a
communication-first approach to explanation: getting clear on explanation's
communicative dimension is an important prerequisite for philosophical work on
explanation. The result is a simple but powerful framework for incorporating
insights from the cognitive sciences into philosophical work on explanation,
which will be useful for philosophers or cognitive scientists interested in
explanation.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Jacqueline Harding</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tobias Gerstenberg</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Thomas Icard</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.03732v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2505.03732v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.MA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.MA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.03708v1</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T17:27:54Z</updated>
    <published>2025-05-06T17:27:54Z</published>
    <title>CHEX-MATE: exploring the kinematical properties of Planck galaxy
  clusters</title>
    <summary>  We analyse the kinematical properties of the CHEX-MATE (Cluster HEritage
project with XMM-Newton - Mass Assembly and Thermodynamics at the Endpoint of
structure formation) galaxy cluster sample. [...] We derive cluster mass
profiles for 75 clusters using the \textsc{MG-MAMPOSSt} procedure, which
recovers the gravitational potential and the anisotropy profiles from
line-of-sight velocities and projected positions of galaxy members. The
standard NFW and the Burkert models with flatter cores than NFW both adequately
fit the kinematic data, with only marginal statistical preference for one model
over the other. An estimation of the mass bias $(1-B_1) =
M^{SZ}_{500}/M^{M}_{500} $ is performed from the comparison with
SZ-X-ray-calibrated mass estimates, resulting in a value of $ 0.54 \pm 0.11$
when four evidently disturbed clusters are removed from the sample. We assess
the dynamical state of the clusters by inferring the Anderson-Darling
coefficient $(A^2)$ and the fraction of galaxies in substructures
($f_\text{sub}$). Except for a few cases, we found relatively low values for
$A^2$, suggesting that CHEX-MATE clusters are not too far from relaxation.
Moreover, no significant trends emerge among $A^2,\,f_\text{sub}$ and the
difference between the log-masses estimated by \textsc{MG-MAMPOSSt} and by
SZ-X-ray.
  We study the concentration-mass relation for the sample; despite the large
scatter, we observe signs of an increasing trend for large-mass clusters, in
agreement with recent theoretical expectations.
  Finally, the analysis of radial anisotropy profiles of member galaxies -
stacked in five bins of mass and redshift - reveals that orbits tend to be
isotropic at the center and more radial towards the edge, as already found in
previous studies. A slight trend of increasing radial orbits at $r_{200}$ is
observed in clusters with larger velocity dispersion
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Lorenzo Pizzuti</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Rafael Barrena</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mauro Sereno</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alina Streblyanska</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Antonio Ferragamo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sophie Maurogordato</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alberto Cappi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Stefano Ettori</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Gabriel W. Pratt</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Gianluca Castignani</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Megan Donahue</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Dominique Eckert</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Fabio Gastaldello</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Raphael Gavazzi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Christopher P. Haines</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Scott T. Kay</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lorenzo Lovisari</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ben J. Maughan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Etienne Pointecouteau</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Elena Rasia</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mario Radovich</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jack Sayers</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">12 pages (plus appendices), 14 Figures. To be submitted to A&amp;A</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.03708v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2505.03708v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="astro-ph.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.03674v1</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T16:15:24Z</updated>
    <published>2025-05-06T16:15:24Z</published>
    <title>Gap the (Theory of) Mind: Sharing Beliefs About Teammates' Goals Boosts
  Collaboration Perception, Not Performance</title>
    <summary>  In human-agent teams, openly sharing goals is often assumed to enhance
planning, collaboration, and effectiveness. However, direct communication of
these goals is not always feasible, requiring teammates to infer their
partner's intentions through actions. Building on this, we investigate whether
an AI agent's ability to share its inferred understanding of a human teammate's
goals can improve task performance and perceived collaboration. Through an
experiment comparing three conditions-no recognition (NR), viable goals (VG),
and viable goals on-demand (VGod) - we find that while goal-sharing information
did not yield significant improvements in task performance or overall
satisfaction scores, thematic analysis suggests that it supported strategic
adaptations and subjective perceptions of collaboration. Cognitive load
assessments revealed no additional burden across conditions, highlighting the
challenge of balancing informativeness and simplicity in human-agent
interactions. These findings highlight the nuanced trade-off of goal-sharing:
while it fosters trust and enhances perceived collaboration, it can
occasionally hinder objective performance gains.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Yotam Amitai</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Reuth Mirsky</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ofra Amir</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.03674v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2505.03674v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.03673v1</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T16:11:49Z</updated>
    <published>2025-05-06T16:11:49Z</published>
    <title>RoboOS: A Hierarchical Embodied Framework for Cross-Embodiment and
  Multi-Agent Collaboration</title>
    <summary>  The dawn of embodied intelligence has ushered in an unprecedented imperative
for resilient, cognition-enabled multi-agent collaboration across
next-generation ecosystems, revolutionizing paradigms in autonomous
manufacturing, adaptive service robotics, and cyber-physical production
architectures. However, current robotic systems face significant limitations,
such as limited cross-embodiment adaptability, inefficient task scheduling, and
insufficient dynamic error correction. While End-to-end VLA models demonstrate
inadequate long-horizon planning and task generalization, hierarchical VLA
models suffer from a lack of cross-embodiment and multi-agent coordination
capabilities. To address these challenges, we introduce RoboOS, the first
open-source embodied system built on a Brain-Cerebellum hierarchical
architecture, enabling a paradigm shift from single-agent to multi-agent
intelligence. Specifically, RoboOS consists of three key components: (1)
Embodied Brain Model (RoboBrain), a MLLM designed for global perception and
high-level decision-making; (2) Cerebellum Skill Library, a modular,
plug-and-play toolkit that facilitates seamless execution of multiple skills;
and (3) Real-Time Shared Memory, a spatiotemporal synchronization mechanism for
coordinating multi-agent states. By integrating hierarchical information flow,
RoboOS bridges Embodied Brain and Cerebellum Skill Library, facilitating robust
planning, scheduling, and error correction for long-horizon tasks, while
ensuring efficient multi-agent collaboration through Real-Time Shared Memory.
Furthermore, we enhance edge-cloud communication and cloud-based distributed
inference to facilitate high-frequency interactions and enable scalable
deployment. Extensive real-world experiments across various scenarios,
demonstrate RoboOS's versatility in supporting heterogeneous embodiments.
Project website: https://github.com/FlagOpen/RoboOS
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Huajie Tan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xiaoshuai Hao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Minglan Lin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Pengwei Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yaoxu Lyu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mingyu Cao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zhongyuan Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Shanghang Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">22 pages, 10 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.03673v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2505.03673v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.03668v1</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T16:08:55Z</updated>
    <published>2025-05-06T16:08:55Z</published>
    <title>Learning Symbolic Persistent Macro-Actions for POMDP Solving Over Time</title>
    <summary>  This paper proposes an integration of temporal logical reasoning and
Partially Observable Markov Decision Processes (POMDPs) to achieve
interpretable decision-making under uncertainty with macro-actions. Our method
leverages a fragment of Linear Temporal Logic (LTL) based on Event Calculus
(EC) to generate \emph{persistent} (i.e., constant) macro-actions, which guide
Monte Carlo Tree Search (MCTS)-based POMDP solvers over a time horizon,
significantly reducing inference time while ensuring robust performance. Such
macro-actions are learnt via Inductive Logic Programming (ILP) from a few
traces of execution (belief-action pairs), thus eliminating the need for
manually designed heuristics and requiring only the specification of the POMDP
transition model. In the Pocman and Rocksample benchmark scenarios, our learned
macro-actions demonstrate increased expressiveness and generality when compared
to time-independent heuristics, indeed offering substantial computational
efficiency improvements.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Celeste Veronese</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Daniele Meli</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alessandro Farinelli</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Accepted at 9th Conference on Neurosymbolic Learning and Reasoning</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.03668v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2505.03668v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.03666v1</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T16:06:44Z</updated>
    <published>2025-05-06T16:06:44Z</published>
    <title>A Centrality-independent Framework for Revealing Genuine Higher-Order
  Cumulants in Heavy-Ion Collisions</title>
    <summary>  We propose a novel centrality definition-independent method for analyzing
higher-order proton cumulants, specifically addressing the challenge of volume
fluctuations that dominate in low-energy heavy-ion collisions. This method
reconstructs particle number distributions using the Edgeworth expansion, with
parameters optimized via a combination of differential evolution algorithm and
Bayesian inference. Its effectiveness is validated using UrQMD model
simulations and benchmarked against traditional approaches, including
centrality definitions based on particle multiplicity. Our results show that
the proposed framework yields cumulant patterns consistent with those obtained
using number of participant nucleon ($N_{\text{part}}$) based centrality
observables, while eliminating the conventional reliance on centrality
determination. This consistency confirms the method's ability to extract
genuine physical signals, thereby paving the way for probing the intrinsic
thermodynamic properties of the produced medium through event-by-event
fluctuations.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Zhaohui Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xiaofeng Luo</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">14 pages, 11 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.03666v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2505.03666v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="physics.data-an" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.data-an" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="hep-ex" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="hep-th" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="nucl-ex" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="nucl-th" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.03655v1</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T16:00:41Z</updated>
    <published>2025-05-06T16:00:41Z</published>
    <title>Counterfactual Inference for Eliminating Sentiment Bias in Recommender
  Systems</title>
    <summary>  Recommender Systems (RSs) aim to provide personalized recommendations for
users. A newly discovered bias, known as sentiment bias, uncovers a common
phenomenon within Review-based RSs (RRSs): the recommendation accuracy of users
or items with negative reviews deteriorates compared with users or items with
positive reviews. Critical users and niche items are disadvantaged by such
unfair recommendations. We study this problem from the perspective of
counterfactual inference with two stages. At the model training stage, we build
a causal graph and model how sentiment influences the final rating score.
During the inference stage, we decouple the direct and indirect effects to
mitigate the impact of sentiment bias and remove the indirect effect using
counterfactual inference. We have conducted extensive experiments, and the
results validate that our model can achieve comparable performance on rating
prediction for better recommendations and effective mitigation of sentiment
bias. To the best of our knowledge, this is the first work to employ
counterfactual inference on sentiment bias mitigation in RSs.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Le Pan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yuanjiang Cao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Chengkai Huang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Wenjie Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lina Yao</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.03655v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2505.03655v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.IR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.IR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.03646v1</id>
    <updated>2025-05-06T15:52:14Z</updated>
    <published>2025-05-06T15:52:14Z</published>
    <title>ALMA: Aggregated Lipschitz Maximization Attack on Auto-encoders</title>
    <summary>  Despite the extensive use of deep autoencoders (AEs) in critical
applications, their adversarial robustness remains relatively underexplored
compared to classification models. AE robustness is characterized by the
Lipschitz bounds of its components. Existing robustness evaluation frameworks
based on white-box attacks do not fully exploit the vulnerabilities of
intermediate ill-conditioned layers in AEs. In the context of optimizing
imperceptible norm-bounded additive perturbations to maximize output damage,
existing methods struggle to effectively propagate adversarial loss gradients
throughout the network, often converging to less effective perturbations. To
address this, we propose a novel layer-conditioning-based adversarial
optimization objective that effectively guides the adversarial map toward
regions of local Lipschitz bounds by enhancing loss gradient information
propagation during attack optimization. We demonstrate through extensive
experiments on state-of-the-art AEs that our adversarial objective results in
stronger attacks, outperforming existing methods in both universal and
sample-specific scenarios. As a defense method against this attack, we
introduce an inference-time adversarially trained defense plugin that mitigates
the effects of adversarial examples.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chethan Krishnamurthy Ramanaik</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Arjun Roy</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Eirini Ntoutsi</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.03646v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2505.03646v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
