<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Last updated: 2025-11-07T00:56:32Z -->
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3Dall%3Acausal%20inference%26id_list%3D%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=all:causal inference&amp;id_list=&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/SsRksLzRb0LuVhSmQ+N8WbAs+f8</id>
  <updated>2025-11-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">125474</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2511.03720v1</id>
    <updated>2025-11-05T18:53:57Z</updated>
    <published>2025-11-05T18:53:57Z</published>
    <title>Observation of phase memory and dynamical phase transitions in spinor
  gases</title>
    <summary>  Utilizing ultracold spinor gases as large-scale, many-body quantum simulation
platforms, we establish a toolbox for the precise control, characterization,
and detection of nonequilibrium dynamics via internal spinor phases. We develop
a method to extract the phase evolution from the observed spin population
dynamics, allowing us to define an order parameter that sharply identifies
dynamical phase transitions over a wide range of conditions. This work also
demonstrates a technique for inferring spin-dependent interactions from a
single experimental time trace, in contrast to the standard approach that
requires mapping a cross section of the phase diagram, with immediate
applications to systems experiencing complex time-dependent interactions.
Additionally, we demonstrate experimental access to and control over
non-ergodic relaxation dynamics, where states in the (nominally) thermal region
of the energy spectrum retain memory of the initial state, via the manipulation
of spinor phases, enabling the study of non-ergodic thermalization dynamics
connected to quantum scarring.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>J. O. Austin-Harris</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>P. Sigdel</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>C. Binegar</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>S. E. Begg</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>T. Bilitewski</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Y. Liu</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2511.03720v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2511.03720v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cond-mat.quant-gas" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.quant-gas" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2511.03692v1</id>
    <updated>2025-11-05T18:18:06Z</updated>
    <published>2025-11-05T18:18:06Z</published>
    <title>Improving Gene Trees without more data</title>
    <summary>  Estimating species and gene trees from sequence data is challenging. Gene
tree estimation is often hampered by low phylogenetic signal in alignments,
leading to inaccurate trees. Species tree estimation is complicated by
incomplete lineage sorting (ILS), where gene histories differ from the species'
history. Summary methods like MP-EST, ASTRAL2, and ASTRID infer species trees
from gene trees but suffer when gene tree accuracy is low. To address this, the
Statistical Binning (SB) and Weighted Statistical Binning (WSB) pipelines were
developed to improve gene tree estimation. However, previous studies only
tested these pipelines using multi-locus bootstrapping (MLBS), not the BestML
approach.
  This thesis proposes a novel pipeline, WSB+WQMC, which shares design features
with the existing WSB+CAML pipeline but has other desirable properties and is
statistically consistent under the GTR+MSC model. This study evaluated WSB+WQMC
against WSB+CAML using BestML analysis on various simulated datasets. The
results confirmed many trends seen in prior MLBS analyses. WSB+WQMC
substantially improved gene tree and species tree accuracy (using ASTRAL2 and
ASTRID) on most datasets with low, medium, and moderately high ILS levels. In a
direct comparison, WSB+WQMC computed less accurate trees than WSB+CAML under
certain low and medium ILS conditions. However, WSB+WQMC performed better or at
least as accurately as WSB+CAML on all datasets with moderately high and high
ILS. It also proved better for estimating gene trees on some medium and low ILS
datasets. Thus, WSB+WQMC is a promising alternative to WSB+CAML for
phylogenetic estimation, especially in the presence of low phylogenetic signal.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ashu Gupta</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Master's thesis, Adviser: Dr Tandy Warnow</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2511.03692v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2511.03692v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="q-bio.PE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="q-bio.PE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2511.03675v1</id>
    <updated>2025-11-05T17:47:46Z</updated>
    <published>2025-11-05T17:47:46Z</published>
    <title>Whisper Leak: a side-channel attack on Large Language Models</title>
    <summary>  Large Language Models (LLMs) are increasingly deployed in sensitive domains
including healthcare, legal services, and confidential communications, where
privacy is paramount. This paper introduces Whisper Leak, a side-channel attack
that infers user prompt topics from encrypted LLM traffic by analyzing packet
size and timing patterns in streaming responses. Despite TLS encryption
protecting content, these metadata patterns leak sufficient information to
enable topic classification. We demonstrate the attack across 28 popular LLMs
from major providers, achieving near-perfect classification (often &gt;98% AUPRC)
and high precision even at extreme class imbalance (10,000:1 noise-to-target
ratio). For many models, we achieve 100% precision in identifying sensitive
topics like "money laundering" while recovering 5-20% of target conversations.
This industry-wide vulnerability poses significant risks for users under
network surveillance by ISPs, governments, or local adversaries. We evaluate
three mitigation strategies - random padding, token batching, and packet
injection - finding that while each reduces attack effectiveness, none provides
complete protection. Through responsible disclosure, we have collaborated with
providers to implement initial countermeasures. Our findings underscore the
need for LLM providers to address metadata leakage as AI systems handle
increasingly sensitive information.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Geoff McDonald</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jonathan Bar Or</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">14 pages, 7 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2511.03675v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2511.03675v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="K.4.1; C.2.0; K.6.5; I.2.7" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2511.03667v1</id>
    <updated>2025-11-05T17:33:44Z</updated>
    <published>2025-11-05T17:33:44Z</published>
    <title>Addressing prior dependence in hierarchical Bayesian modeling for PTA
  data analysis I: Methodology and implementation</title>
    <summary>  Complex inference tasks, such as those encountered in Pulsar Timing Array
(PTA) data analysis, rely on Bayesian frameworks. The high-dimensional
parameter space and the strong interdependencies among astrophysical, pulsar
noise, and nuisance parameters introduce significant challenges for efficient
learning and robust inference. These challenges are emblematic of broader
issues in decision science, where model over-parameterization and prior
sensitivity can compromise both computational tractability and the reliability
of the results. We address these issues in the framework of hierarchical
Bayesian modeling by introducing a reparameterization strategy. Our approach
employs Normalizing Flows (NFs) to decorrelate the parameters governing
hierarchical priors from those of astrophysical interest. The use of NF-based
mappings provides both the flexibility to realize the reparametrization and the
tractability to preserve proper probability densities. We further adopt
i-nessai, a flow-guided nested sampler, to accelerate exploration of complex
posteriors. This unified use of NFs improves statistical robustness and
computational efficiency, providing a principled methodology for addressing
hierarchical Bayesian inference in PTA analysis.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Luigi D'amico</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Eleonora Villa</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Fatima Modica Bittordo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Aldo Barca</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Francesco Alì</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Massimo Meneghetti</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Luca Naso</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">15 pages, 7 figures. Under review for Proceedings of International
  Summer Conference 2025: Intelligent Systems &amp; Decision Making: Human Insights
  in the Era of A.I - Lecture Notes in Computer Science, Springer Nature</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2511.03667v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2511.03667v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="astro-ph.IM" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.IM" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.HE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2511.03666v1</id>
    <updated>2025-11-05T17:33:03Z</updated>
    <published>2025-11-05T17:33:03Z</published>
    <title>Part-Aware Bottom-Up Group Reasoning for Fine-Grained Social Interaction
  Detection</title>
    <summary>  Social interactions often emerge from subtle, fine-grained cues such as
facial expressions, gaze, and gestures. However, existing methods for social
interaction detection overlook such nuanced cues and primarily rely on holistic
representations of individuals. Moreover, they directly detect social groups
without explicitly modeling the underlying interactions between individuals.
These drawbacks limit their ability to capture localized social signals and
introduce ambiguity when group configurations should be inferred from social
interactions grounded in nuanced cues. In this work, we propose a part-aware
bottom-up group reasoning framework for fine-grained social interaction
detection. The proposed method infers social groups and their interactions
using body part features and their interpersonal relations. Our model first
detects individuals and enhances their features using part-aware cues, and then
infers group configuration by associating individuals via similarity-based
reasoning, which considers not only spatial relations but also subtle social
cues that signal interactions, leading to more accurate group inference.
Experiments on the NVI dataset demonstrate that our method outperforms prior
methods, achieving the new state of the art.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Dongkeun Kim</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Minsu Cho</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Suha Kwak</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Accepted to NeurIPS 2025</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2511.03666v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2511.03666v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2511.03663v1</id>
    <updated>2025-11-05T17:26:05Z</updated>
    <published>2025-11-05T17:26:05Z</published>
    <title>3D Full Spectrum Fitting: Algorithm Comparison</title>
    <summary>  Full spectrum fitting is the prevailing method for extracting stellar
kinematic and population measurements from 1D galaxy spectra. 3D methods refer
to analysis of Integral Field Spectroscopy (IFS) data where spatial and
spectral dimensions are modelled simultaneously. While several 3D methods exist
for modelling gas structures there has been less investigation into the more
computationally demanding problem of 3D full spectrum fitting for stellar
recoveries. This work introduces and compares two algorithms for this task: the
Projected Nesterov Kaczmarz Reconstruction method (PNKR) and a version of the
Bayes-LOSVD software which has been modified to account for spatial
correlations. We aim to understand strengths and weaknesses of both algorithms
and assess the impact of 3D methods for stellar inferences. We apply both
recovery algorithms to a mock IFS data over a signal-to-noise ratio (SNR) range
from 20-200 and evaluate the quality of the recoveries compared to the known
ground truth. Accounting for spatial correlations in Bayes-LOSVD significantly
improved the accuracy and precision of kinematic recoveries. 3D modelling with
PNKR did not provide any significant improvement over 1D fits however, for
SNR&gt;40, PNKR did recover the most accurate kinematics overall. Additionally, by
modelling the joint distribution over kinematics and populations, PNKR could
successfully infer trends between these quantities e.g. inferring local
metallicity-velocity trends, albeit with a significant bias on the absolute
metallicity. Having demonstrated advantages of (i) 3D modelling with
Bayes-LOSVD, and (ii) joint kinematic-population analyses with PNKR, we
conclude that both methodological advances will prove useful for detecting and
characterising stellar structures from IFS data.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Prashin Jethwa</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Hubmer</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ronny Ramlau</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Glenn Van de Ven</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Submitted to A&amp;A</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2511.03663v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2511.03663v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.IM" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2511.03636v1</id>
    <updated>2025-11-05T16:54:17Z</updated>
    <published>2025-11-05T16:54:17Z</published>
    <title>Quantifying Weighted Morphological Content of Large-Scale Structures via
  Simulation-Based Inference</title>
    <summary>  In this work, we perform a simulation-based forecasting analysis to compare
the constraining power of two higher-order summary statistics of the
large-scale structure (LSS), the Minkowski Functionals (MFs) and the
Conditional Moments of Derivative (CMD), with a particular focus on their
sensitivity to nonlinear and anisotropic features in redshift-space. Our
analysis relies on halo catalogs from the Big Sobol Sequence(BSQ) simulations
at redshift $z=0.5$, employing a likelihood-free inference framework
implemented via neural posterior estimation. At the fiducial cosmology of the
Quijote simulations $(\Omega_{m}=0.3175,\,\sigma_{8}=0.834)$, and for the
smoothing scale $R=15\,h^{-1}$Mpc, we find that the CMD yields tighter
forecasts for $(\Omega_{m}},\,\sigma_{8})$ than the zeroth- to third-order MFs
components, improving the constraint precision by ${\sim}(44\%,\,52\%)$,
${\sim}(30\%,\,45\%)$, ${\sim}(27\%,\,17\%)$, and ${\sim}(26\%,\,17\%)$,
respectively. A joint configuration combining the MFs and CMD further enhances
the precision by approximately ${\sim}27\%$ compared to the standard MFs alone,
highlighting the complementary anisotropy-sensitive information captured by the
CMD in contrast to the scalar morphological content encapsulated by the MFs. We
further extend the forecasting analysis to a continuous range of cosmological
parameter values and multiple smoothing scales. Our results show that, although
the absolute forecast uncertainty for each component of summary statistics
depends on the underlying parameter values and the adopted smoothing scale, the
relative constraining power among the summary statistics remains nearly
constant throughout.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>M. H. Jalali Kanafi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>S. M. S. Movahed</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">19 pages, 9 figures and 3 tables. Comments are welcome</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2511.03636v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2511.03636v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="astro-ph.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.comp-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2511.03616v1</id>
    <updated>2025-11-05T16:33:39Z</updated>
    <published>2025-11-05T16:33:39Z</published>
    <title>Going Beyond Expert Performance via Deep Implicit Imitation
  Reinforcement Learning</title>
    <summary>  Imitation learning traditionally requires complete state-action
demonstrations from optimal or near-optimal experts. These requirements
severely limit practical applicability, as many real-world scenarios provide
only state observations without corresponding actions and expert performance is
often suboptimal. In this paper we introduce a deep implicit imitation
reinforcement learning framework that addresses both limitations by combining
deep reinforcement learning with implicit imitation learning from
observation-only datasets. Our main algorithm, Deep Implicit Imitation
Q-Network (DIIQN), employs an action inference mechanism that reconstructs
expert actions through online exploration and integrates a dynamic confidence
mechanism that adaptively balances expert-guided and self-directed learning.
This enables the agent to leverage expert guidance for accelerated training
while maintaining capacity to surpass suboptimal expert performance. We further
extend our framework with a Heterogeneous Actions DIIQN (HA-DIIQN) algorithm to
tackle scenarios where expert and agent possess different action sets, a
challenge previously unaddressed in the implicit imitation learning literature.
HA-DIIQN introduces an infeasibility detection mechanism and a bridging
procedure identifying alternative pathways connecting agent capabilities to
expert guidance when direct action replication is impossible. Our experimental
results demonstrate that DIIQN achieves up to 130% higher episodic returns
compared to standard DQN, while consistently outperforming existing implicit
imitation methods that cannot exceed expert performance. In heterogeneous
action settings, HA-DIIQN learns up to 64% faster than baselines, leveraging
expert datasets unusable by conventional approaches. Extensive parameter
sensitivity analysis reveals the framework's robustness across varying dataset
sizes and hyperparameter configurations.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Iason Chrysomallis</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Georgios Chalkiadakis</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2511.03616v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2511.03616v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2511.03608v1</id>
    <updated>2025-11-05T16:27:20Z</updated>
    <published>2025-11-05T16:27:20Z</published>
    <title>A local eigenvector centrality</title>
    <summary>  Eigenvector centrality is an established measure of global connectivity, from
which the importance and influence of nodes can be inferred. We introduce a
local eigenvector centrality that incorporates both local and global
connectivity. This new measure references prominent eigengaps and combines
their associated eigenspectrum, via the Euclidean norm, to detect centrality
that reflects the influence of prominent community structures. In contact
networks, with clearly defined community structures, local eigenvector
centrality is shown to identify similar but distinct distributions to
eigenvector centrality applied on each community in isolation and PageRank.
Discrepancies between the two eigenvector measures highlight nodes and
communities that do not conform to their defined local structures, e.g. nodes
with more connections outside of their defined community than within it. While
reference to PageRank's centrality assessment enables a mitigation strategy for
localisation effects inherent in eigenvector-based measures. In networks
without clearly defined communities, such as city road networks, local
eigenvector centrality is shown to identify both locally prominent and globally
connected hubs.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ruaridh A. Clark</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Francesca Arrigo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Agathe Bouis</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Malcolm Macdonald</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">17 pages, 9 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2511.03608v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2511.03608v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.SI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.SI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2511.03605v1</id>
    <updated>2025-11-05T16:25:22Z</updated>
    <published>2025-11-05T16:25:22Z</published>
    <title>Bayesian Topological Analysis of Functional Brain Networks</title>
    <summary>  Subtle alterations in brain network topology often evade detection by
traditional statistical methods. To address this limitation, we introduce a
Bayesian inference framework for topological comparison of brain networks that
probabilistically models within- and between-group dissimilarities. The
framework employs Markov chain Monte Carlo sampling to estimate posterior
distributions of test statistics and Bayes factors, enabling graded evidence
assessment beyond binary significance testing. Simulations confirmed
statistical consistency to permutation testing. Applied to fMRI data from the
Duke-UNC Alzheimer's Disease Research Center, the framework detected
topology-based network differences that conventional permutation tests failed
to reveal, highlighting its enhanced sensitivity to early or subtle brain
network alterations in clinical neuroimaging.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Xukun Zhu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Michael W Lutz</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tananun Songdechakraiwut</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2511.03605v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2511.03605v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="stat.ME" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ME" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
