<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Last updated: 2025-05-01T01:00:45Z -->
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3Dall%3Acausal%20inference%26id_list%3D%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=all:causal inference&amp;id_list=&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/SsRksLzRb0LuVhSmQ+N8WbAs+f8</id>
  <updated>2025-04-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">111430</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20922v1</id>
    <updated>2025-04-29T16:38:15Z</updated>
    <published>2025-04-29T16:38:15Z</published>
    <title>DYNAMAX: Dynamic computing for Transformers and Mamba based
  architectures</title>
    <summary>  Early exits (EEs) offer a promising approach to reducing computational costs
and latency by dynamically terminating inference once a satisfactory prediction
confidence on a data sample is achieved. Although many works integrate EEs into
encoder-only Transformers, their application to decoder-only architectures and,
more importantly, Mamba models, a novel family of state-space architectures in
the LLM realm, remains insufficiently explored. This work introduces DYNAMAX,
the first framework to exploit the unique properties of Mamba architectures for
early exit mechanisms. We not only integrate EEs into Mamba but also repurpose
Mamba as an efficient EE classifier for both Mamba-based and transformer-based
LLMs, showcasing its versatility. Our experiments employ the Mistral 7B
transformer compared to the Codestral 7B Mamba model, using data sets such as
TruthfulQA, CoQA, and TriviaQA to evaluate computational savings, accuracy, and
consistency. The results highlight the adaptability of Mamba as a powerful EE
classifier and its efficiency in balancing computational cost and performance
quality across NLP tasks. By leveraging Mamba's inherent design for dynamic
processing, we open pathways for scalable and efficient inference in embedded
applications and resource-constrained environments. This study underscores the
transformative potential of Mamba in redefining dynamic computing paradigms for
LLMs.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Miguel Nogales</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Matteo Gambella</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Manuel Roveri</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Accepted to IJCNN 2025</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20922v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2504.20922v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="68T50 (Primary), 68T07 (Secondary)" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20914v1</id>
    <updated>2025-04-29T16:33:54Z</updated>
    <published>2025-04-29T16:33:54Z</published>
    <title>Relativistic ejecta from stellar mass black holes: insights from
  simulations and synthetic radio images</title>
    <summary>  We present numerical simulations of discrete relativistic ejecta from an
X-ray binary (XRB) with initial conditions directly informed by observations.
XRBs have been observed to launch powerful discrete plasma ejecta during state
transitions, which can propagate up to parsec distances. Understanding these
ejection events unveils new understanding of jet-launching, jet power, and
jet-ISM interaction among other implications. Multi-frequency
quasi-simultaneous radio observations of ejecta from the black hole XRB MAXI
J1820+070 produced both size and calorimetry constraints, which we use as
initial conditions of a relativistic hydrodynamic simulation. We qualitatively
reproduce the observed deceleration of the ejecta in a homogeneous interstellar
medium (ISM). Our simulations demonstrate that the ejecta must be denser than
the ISM, the ISM be significantly low-density, and the launch be extremely
powerful, in order to propagate to the observed distances. The blob propagates
and clears out a high-pressure low-density cavity in its wake, providing an
explanation for this pre-existing low-density environment, as well as
'bubble-like' environments in the vicinity of XRBs inferred from other studies.
As the blob decelerates, we observe the onset of instabilities and a long-lived
reverse shock -- these mechanisms convert kinetic to internal energy in the
blob, responsible for in-situ particle acceleration. We transform the outputs
of our simulation into pseudo-radio images, incorporating the u,v coverage of
the MeerKAT and e-MERLIN telescopes from the original observations with
real-sky background. Through this, we maximize the interpretability of the
results and provide direct comparison to current data, as well as provide
prediction capabilities.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Katie Savard</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>James H. Matthews</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Rob Fender</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Heywood</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Accepted for publication in MNRAS</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20914v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2504.20914v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="astro-ph.HE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.HE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20863v1</id>
    <updated>2025-04-29T15:39:10Z</updated>
    <published>2025-04-29T15:39:10Z</published>
    <title>Bayesian Optimization-based Tire Parameter and Uncertainty Estimation
  for Real-World Data</title>
    <summary>  This work presents a methodology to estimate tire parameters and their
uncertainty using a Bayesian optimization approach. The literature mainly
considers the estimation of tire parameters but lacks an evaluation of the
parameter identification quality and the required slip ratios for an adequate
model fit. Therefore, we examine the use of Stochastical Variational Inference
as a methodology to estimate both - the parameters and their uncertainties. We
evaluate the method compared to a state-of-the-art Nelder-Mead algorithm for
theoretical and real-world application. The theoretical study considers
parameter fitting at different slip ratios to evaluate the required excitation
for an adequate fitting of each parameter. The results are compared to a
sensitivity analysis for a Pacejka Magic Formula tire model. We show the
application of the algorithm on real-world data acquired during the Abu Dhabi
Autonomous Racing League and highlight the uncertainties in identifying the
curvature and shape parameters due to insufficient excitation. The gathered
insights can help assess the acquired data's limitations and instead utilize
standardized parameters until higher slip ratios are captured. We show that our
proposed method can be used to assess the mean values and the uncertainties of
tire model parameters in real-world conditions and derive actions for the tire
modeling based on our simulative study.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Sven Goblirsch</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Benedikt Ruhland</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Johannes Betz</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Markus Lienkamp</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">This paper has been accepted at IV 2025</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20863v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2504.20863v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20837v1</id>
    <updated>2025-04-29T15:00:25Z</updated>
    <published>2025-04-29T15:00:25Z</published>
    <title>RadSAM: Segmenting 3D radiological images with a 2D promptable model</title>
    <summary>  Medical image segmentation is a crucial and time-consuming task in clinical
care, where mask precision is extremely important. The Segment Anything Model
(SAM) offers a promising approach, as it provides an interactive interface
based on visual prompting and edition to refine an initial segmentation. This
model has strong generalization capabilities, does not rely on predefined
classes, and adapts to diverse objects; however, it is pre-trained on natural
images and lacks the ability to process medical data effectively. In addition,
this model is built for 2D images, whereas a whole medical domain is based on
3D images, such as CT and MRI. Recent adaptations of SAM for medical imaging
are based on 2D models, thus requiring one prompt per slice to segment 3D
objects, making the segmentation process tedious. They also lack important
features such as editing. To bridge this gap, we propose RadSAM, a novel method
for segmenting 3D objects with a 2D model from a single prompt. In practice, we
train a 2D model using noisy masks as initial prompts, in addition to bounding
boxes and points. We then use this novel prompt type with an iterative
inference pipeline to reconstruct the 3D mask slice-by-slice. We introduce a
benchmark to evaluate the model's ability to segment 3D objects in CT images
from a single prompt and evaluate the models' out-of-domain transfer and
edition capabilities. We demonstrate the effectiveness of our approach against
state-of-the-art models on this benchmark using the AMOS abdominal organ
segmentation dataset.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Julien Khlaut</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Elodie Ferreres</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Daniel Tordjman</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hélène Philippe</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Boeken</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Pierre Manceron</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Corentin Dancette</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20837v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2504.20837v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20835v1</id>
    <updated>2025-04-29T14:59:42Z</updated>
    <published>2025-04-29T14:59:42Z</published>
    <title>Enhancing Non-Core Language Instruction-Following in Speech LLMs via
  Semi-Implicit Cross-Lingual CoT Reasoning</title>
    <summary>  Large language models have been extended to the speech domain, leading to the
development of speech large language models (SLLMs). While existing SLLMs
demonstrate strong performance in speech instruction-following for core
languages (e.g., English), they often struggle with non-core languages due to
the scarcity of paired speech-text data and limited multilingual semantic
reasoning capabilities. To address this, we propose the semi-implicit
Cross-lingual Speech Chain-of-Thought (XS-CoT) framework, which integrates
speech-to-text translation into the reasoning process of SLLMs. The XS-CoT
generates four types of tokens: instruction and response tokens in both core
and non-core languages, enabling cross-lingual transfer of reasoning
capabilities. To mitigate inference latency in generating target non-core
response tokens, we incorporate a semi-implicit CoT scheme into XS-CoT, which
progressively compresses the first three types of intermediate reasoning tokens
while retaining global reasoning logic during training. By leveraging the
robust reasoning capabilities of the core language, XS-CoT improves responses
for non-core languages by up to 45\% in GPT-4 score when compared to direct
supervised fine-tuning on two representative SLLMs, Qwen2-Audio and SALMONN.
Moreover, the semi-implicit XS-CoT reduces token delay by more than 50\% with a
slight drop in GPT-4 scores. Importantly, XS-CoT requires only a small amount
of high-quality training data for non-core languages by leveraging the
reasoning capabilities of core languages. To support training, we also develop
a data pipeline and open-source speech instruction-following datasets in
Japanese, German, and French.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Hongfei Xue</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yufeng Tang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hexin Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jun Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xuelong Geng</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lei Xie</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">10 pages, 6 figures, Submitted to ACM MM 2025</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20835v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2504.20835v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.SD" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.SD" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="eess.AS" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20829v1</id>
    <updated>2025-04-29T14:52:14Z</updated>
    <published>2025-04-29T14:52:14Z</published>
    <title>GaussTrap: Stealthy Poisoning Attacks on 3D Gaussian Splatting for
  Targeted Scene Confusion</title>
    <summary>  As 3D Gaussian Splatting (3DGS) emerges as a breakthrough in scene
representation and novel view synthesis, its rapid adoption in safety-critical
domains (e.g., autonomous systems, AR/VR) urgently demands scrutiny of
potential security vulnerabilities. This paper presents the first systematic
study of backdoor threats in 3DGS pipelines. We identify that adversaries may
implant backdoor views to induce malicious scene confusion during inference,
potentially leading to environmental misperception in autonomous navigation or
spatial distortion in immersive environments. To uncover this risk, we propose
GuassTrap, a novel poisoning attack method targeting 3DGS models. GuassTrap
injects malicious views at specific attack viewpoints while preserving
high-quality rendering in non-target views, ensuring minimal detectability and
maximizing potential harm. Specifically, the proposed method consists of a
three-stage pipeline (attack, stabilization, and normal training) to implant
stealthy, viewpoint-consistent poisoned renderings in 3DGS, jointly optimizing
attack efficacy and perceptual realism to expose security risks in 3D
rendering. Extensive experiments on both synthetic and real-world datasets
demonstrate that GuassTrap can effectively embed imperceptible yet harmful
backdoor views while maintaining high-quality rendering in normal views,
validating its robustness, adaptability, and practical applicability.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Jiaxin Hong</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sixu Chen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Shuoyang Sun</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hongyao Yu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hao Fang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yuqi Tan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Bin Chen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Shuhan Qi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jiawei Li</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20829v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2504.20829v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20808v1</id>
    <updated>2025-04-29T14:21:08Z</updated>
    <published>2025-04-29T14:21:08Z</published>
    <title>SoccerDiffusion: Toward Learning End-to-End Humanoid Robot Soccer from
  Gameplay Recordings</title>
    <summary>  This paper introduces SoccerDiffusion, a transformer-based diffusion model
designed to learn end-to-end control policies for humanoid robot soccer
directly from real-world gameplay recordings. Using data collected from RoboCup
competitions, the model predicts joint command trajectories from multi-modal
sensor inputs, including vision, proprioception, and game state. We employ a
distillation technique to enable real-time inference on embedded platforms that
reduces the multi-step diffusion process to a single step. Our results
demonstrate the model's ability to replicate complex motion behaviors such as
walking, kicking, and fall recovery both in simulation and on physical robots.
Although high-level tactical behavior remains limited, this work provides a
robust foundation for subsequent reinforcement learning or preference
optimization methods. We release the dataset, pretrained models, and code
under: https://bit-bots.github.io/SoccerDiffusion
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Florian Vahl</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jörn Griepenburg</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jan Gutsche</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jasper Güldenstein</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jianwei Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20808v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2504.20808v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20784v1</id>
    <updated>2025-04-29T14:01:10Z</updated>
    <published>2025-04-29T14:01:10Z</published>
    <title>Approximate Lifted Model Construction</title>
    <summary>  Probabilistic relational models such as parametric factor graphs enable
efficient (lifted) inference by exploiting the indistinguishability of objects.
In lifted inference, a representative of indistinguishable objects is used for
computations. To obtain a relational (i.e., lifted) representation, the
Advanced Colour Passing (ACP) algorithm is the state of the art. The ACP
algorithm, however, requires underlying distributions, encoded as
potential-based factorisations, to exactly match to identify and exploit
indistinguishabilities. Hence, ACP is unsuitable for practical applications
where potentials learned from data inevitably deviate even if associated
objects are indistinguishable. To mitigate this problem, we introduce the
$\varepsilon$-Advanced Colour Passing ($\varepsilon$-ACP) algorithm, which
allows for a deviation of potentials depending on a hyperparameter
$\varepsilon$. $\varepsilon$-ACP efficiently uncovers and exploits
indistinguishabilities that are not exact. We prove that the approximation
error induced by $\varepsilon$-ACP is strictly bounded and our experiments show
that the approximation error is close to zero in practice.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Malte Luttermann</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jan Speller</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Marcel Gehrke</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tanya Braun</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ralf Möller</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mattis Hartwig</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Extended version of paper accepted to the Proceedings of the 34th
  International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI-2025)</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20784v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2504.20784v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.DS" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20776v1</id>
    <updated>2025-04-29T13:53:33Z</updated>
    <published>2025-04-29T13:53:33Z</published>
    <title>ECOSoundSet: a finely annotated dataset for the automated acoustic
  identification of Orthoptera and Cicadidae in North, Central and temperate
  Western Europe</title>
    <summary>  Currently available tools for the automated acoustic recognition of European
insects in natural soundscapes are limited in scope. Large and ecologically
heterogeneous acoustic datasets are currently needed for these algorithms to
cross-contextually recognize the subtle and complex acoustic signatures
produced by each species, thus making the availability of such datasets a key
requisite for their development. Here we present ECOSoundSet (European
Cicadidae and Orthoptera Sound dataSet), a dataset containing 10,653 recordings
of 200 orthopteran and 24 cicada species (217 and 26 respective taxa when
including subspecies) present in North, Central, and temperate Western Europe
(Andorra, Belgium, Denmark, mainland France and Corsica, Germany, Ireland,
Luxembourg, Monaco, Netherlands, United Kingdom, Switzerland), collected partly
through targeted fieldwork in South France and Catalonia and partly through
contributions from various European entomologists. The dataset is composed of a
combination of coarsely labeled recordings, for which we can only infer the
presence, at some point, of their target species (weak labeling), and finely
annotated recordings, for which we know the specific time and frequency range
of each insect sound present in the recording (strong labeling). We also
provide a train/validation/test split of the strongly labeled recordings, with
respective approximate proportions of 0.8, 0.1 and 0.1, in order to facilitate
their incorporation in the training and evaluation of deep learning algorithms.
This dataset could serve as a meaningful complement to recordings already
available online for the training of deep learning algorithms for the acoustic
classification of orthopterans and cicadas in North, Central, and temperate
Western Europe.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>David Funosas</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Elodie Massol</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yves Bas</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Svenja Schmidt</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Dominik Arend</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alexander Gebhard</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Luc Barbaro</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sebastian König</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Rafael Carbonell Font</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>David Sannier</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Fernand Deroussen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jérôme Sueur</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Christian Roesti</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tomi Trilar</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Wolfgang Forstmeier</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lucas Roger</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Eloïsa Matheu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Piotr Guzik</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Julien Barataud</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Laurent Pelozuelo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Stéphane Puissant</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sandra Mueller</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Björn Schuller</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jose M. Montoya</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Andreas Triantafyllopoulos</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Maxime Cauchoix</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">3 Figures + 2 Supplementary Figures, 2 Tables + 3 Supplementary
  Tables</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20776v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2504.20776v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.SD" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.SD" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="eess.AS" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20758v1</id>
    <updated>2025-04-29T13:37:36Z</updated>
    <published>2025-04-29T13:37:36Z</published>
    <title>Influence network reconstruction from discrete time-series of count data
  modelled by multidimensional Hawkes processes</title>
    <summary>  Identifying key influencers from time series data without a known prior
network structure is a challenging problem in various applications, from crime
analysis to social media. While much work has focused on event-based time
series (timestamp) data, fewer methods address count data, where event counts
are recorded in fixed intervals. We develop network inference methods for both
batched and sequential count data. Here the strong network connection
represents the key influences among the nodes. We introduce an ensemble-based
algorithm, rooted in the expectation-maximization (EM) framework, and
demonstrate its utility to identify node dynamics and connections through a
discrete-time Cox or Hawkes process. For the linear multidimensional Hawkes
model, we employ a minimization-majorization (MM) approach, allowing for
parallelized inference of networks. For sequential inference, we use a
second-order approximation of the Bayesian inference problem. Under certain
assumptions, a rank-1 update for the covariance matrix reduces computational
costs. We validate our methods on synthetic data and real-world datasets,
including email communications within European academic communities. Our
approach effectively reconstructs underlying networks, accounting for both
excitation and diffusion influences. This work advances network reconstruction
from count data in real-world scenarios.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Naratip Santitissadeekorn</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Martin Short</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>David J. B. Lloyd</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">28 pages, 18 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.20758v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2504.20758v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="math.DS" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.DS" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="62F15, 62F30, 62M20" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
