<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Last updated: 2025-10-15T00:54:40Z -->
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3Dall%3Acausal%20inference%26id_list%3D%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=all:causal inference&amp;id_list=&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/SsRksLzRb0LuVhSmQ+N8WbAs+f8</id>
  <updated>2025-10-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">123578</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2510.11719v1</id>
    <updated>2025-10-13T17:59:59Z</updated>
    <published>2025-10-13T17:59:59Z</published>
    <title>BayeSN-TD: Time Delay and $H_0$ Estimation for Lensed SN H0pe</title>
    <summary>  We present BayeSN-TD, an enhanced implementation of the probabilistic type Ia
supernova (SN Ia) BayeSN SED model, designed for fitting multiply-imaged,
gravitationally lensed type Ia supernovae (glSNe Ia). BayeSN-TD fits for
magnifications and time-delays across multiple images while marginalising over
an achromatic, Gaussian process-based treatment of microlensing, to allow for
time-dependent deviations from a typical SN Ia SED caused by gravitational
lensing by stars in the lensing system. BayeSN-TD is able to robustly infer
time delays and produce well-calibrated uncertainties, even when applied to
simulations based on a different SED model and incorporating chromatic
microlensing, strongly validating its suitability for time-delay cosmography.
We then apply BayeSN-TD to publicly available photometry of the glSN Ia SN
H0pe, inferring time delays between images BA and BC of $\Delta
T_{BA}=121.9^{+9.5}_{-7.5}$ days and $\Delta T_{BC}=63.2^{+3.2}_{-3.3}$ days
along with absolute magnifications $\beta$ for each image, $\beta_A =
2.38^{+0.72}_{-0.54}$, $\beta_B=5.27^{+1.25}_{-1.02}$ and
$\beta_C=3.93^{+1.00}_{-0.75}$. Combining our constraints on time-delays and
magnifications with existing lens models of this system, we infer
$H_0=69.3^{+12.6}_{-7.8}$ km s$^{-1}$ Mpc$^{-1}$, consistent with previous
analysis of this system; incorporating additional constraints based on
spectroscopy yields $H_0=66.8^{+13.4}_{-5.4}$ km s$^{-1}$ Mpc$^{-1}$. While
this is not yet precise enough to draw a meaningful conclusion with regard to
the `Hubble tension', upcoming analysis of SN H0pe with more accurate
photometry enabled by template images, and other glSNe, will provide stronger
constraints on $H_0$; BayeSN-TD will be a valuable tool for these analyses.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>M. Grayling</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>S. Thorp</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>K. S. Mandel</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>M. Pascale</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>J. D. R</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name> Pierel</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>E. E. Hayes</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>C. Larison</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>A. Agrawal</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>G. Narayan</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">20 pages, 11 figures, 4 tables. Submitted to MNRAS. BayeSN-TD code
  will be made public upon acceptance of the paper</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2510.11719v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2510.11719v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="astro-ph.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2510.11689v1</id>
    <updated>2025-10-13T17:51:23Z</updated>
    <published>2025-10-13T17:51:23Z</published>
    <title>Phys2Real: Fusing VLM Priors with Interactive Online Adaptation for
  Uncertainty-Aware Sim-to-Real Manipulation</title>
    <summary>  Learning robotic manipulation policies directly in the real world can be
expensive and time-consuming. While reinforcement learning (RL) policies
trained in simulation present a scalable alternative, effective sim-to-real
transfer remains challenging, particularly for tasks that require precise
dynamics. To address this, we propose Phys2Real, a real-to-sim-to-real RL
pipeline that combines vision-language model (VLM)-inferred physical parameter
estimates with interactive adaptation through uncertainty-aware fusion. Our
approach consists of three core components: (1) high-fidelity geometric
reconstruction with 3D Gaussian splatting, (2) VLM-inferred prior distributions
over physical parameters, and (3) online physical parameter estimation from
interaction data. Phys2Real conditions policies on interpretable physical
parameters, refining VLM predictions with online estimates via ensemble-based
uncertainty quantification. On planar pushing tasks of a T-block with varying
center of mass (CoM) and a hammer with an off-center mass distribution,
Phys2Real achieves substantial improvements over a domain randomization
baseline: 100% vs 79% success rate for the bottom-weighted T-block, 57% vs 23%
in the challenging top-weighted T-block, and 15% faster average task completion
for hammer pushing. Ablation studies indicate that the combination of VLM and
interaction information is essential for success. Project website:
https://phys2real.github.io/ .
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Maggie Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Stephen Tian</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Aiden Swann</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ola Shorinwa</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jiajun Wu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mac Schwager</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2510.11689v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2510.11689v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2510.11687v1</id>
    <updated>2025-10-13T17:49:15Z</updated>
    <published>2025-10-13T17:49:15Z</published>
    <title>Beyond 'Templates': Category-Agnostic Object Pose, Size, and Shape
  Estimation from a Single View</title>
    <summary>  Estimating an object's 6D pose, size, and shape from visual input is a
fundamental problem in computer vision, with critical applications in robotic
grasping and manipulation. Existing methods either rely on object-specific
priors such as CAD models or templates, or suffer from limited generalization
across categories due to pose-shape entanglement and multi-stage pipelines. In
this work, we propose a unified, category-agnostic framework that
simultaneously predicts 6D pose, size, and dense shape from a single RGB-D
image, without requiring templates, CAD models, or category labels at test
time. Our model fuses dense 2D features from vision foundation models with
partial 3D point clouds using a Transformer encoder enhanced by a
Mixture-of-Experts, and employs parallel decoders for pose-size estimation and
shape reconstruction, achieving real-time inference at 28 FPS. Trained solely
on synthetic data from 149 categories in the SOPE dataset, our framework is
evaluated on four diverse benchmarks SOPE, ROPE, ObjaversePose, and HANDAL,
spanning over 300 categories. It achieves state-of-the-art accuracy on seen
categories while demonstrating remarkably strong zero-shot generalization to
unseen real-world objects, establishing a new standard for open-set 6D
understanding in robotics and embodied AI.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Jinyu Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Haitao Lin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jiashu Hou</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xiangyang Xue</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yanwei Fu</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2510.11687v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2510.11687v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2510.11686v1</id>
    <updated>2025-10-13T17:49:05Z</updated>
    <published>2025-10-13T17:49:05Z</published>
    <title>Representation-Based Exploration for Language Models: From Test-Time to
  Post-Training</title>
    <summary>  Reinforcement learning (RL) promises to expand the capabilities of language
models, but it is unclear if current RL techniques promote the discovery of
novel behaviors, or simply sharpen those already present in the base model. In
this paper, we investigate the value of deliberate exploration -- explicitly
incentivizing the model to discover novel and diverse behaviors -- and aim to
understand how the knowledge in pre-trained models can guide this search. Our
main finding is that exploration with a simple, principled,
representation-based bonus derived from the pre-trained language model's hidden
states significantly improves diversity and pass@k rates -- both for
post-training, and in a novel inference-time scaling setting we introduce. For
inference-time, exploration with representation-based diversity improves
efficiency, consistently improving pass@k rates across a variety of models and
reasoning tasks. For example, for Qwen-2.5-14b-Instruct we obtain over 50%
improvement in verifier efficiency on almost all tasks. For post-training, we
show that integrating this exploration strategy into an RL pipeline improves
reasoning performance over that of the initial model and over standard RL
post-training. For example, on AIME 2024, our post-trained
Qwen-2.5-7b-Instruct's pass@80 matches the pass@256 of GRPO on the same model,
demonstrating a 3x improvement in test-time sample efficiency. Overall, our
findings suggest that deliberate exploration -- with the right notion of
diversity -- is a practical path toward discovery of new behaviors beyond
sharpening.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Jens Tuyls</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Dylan J. Foster</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Akshay Krishnamurthy</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jordan T. Ash</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Website and code: https://rep-exp.github.io</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2510.11686v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2510.11686v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2510.11671v1</id>
    <updated>2025-10-13T17:43:24Z</updated>
    <published>2025-10-13T17:43:24Z</published>
    <title>Finite-temperature phase diagram and collective modes of coherently
  coupled Bose mixtures</title>
    <summary>  We investigate the ferromagnetic-paramagnetic phase transition in coherently
(Rabi) coupled Bose-Einstein condensates at zero and finite temperatures,
exploring different routes to the transition by tuning the Rabi coupling or
increasing the temperature at a fixed coupling. Using the
Hartree-Fock-Bogoliubov theory within the Popov approximation, we map out the
finite-temperature phase diagram of a three-dimensional homogeneous condensate
and identify the critical line through the softening of the spin gap.
Magnetization and the spin dispersion branch reveal the progressive suppression
of the ferromagnetic order with increasing temperature. In
quasi-one-dimensional harmonic traps, the transition, driven by Rabi coupling,
is inferred through the softening of the spin breathing mode with its minimum
shifting to lower coupling values with increasing temperature. Notably, the
thermally driven transition causes monotonic hardening of all the spin modes.
For both coupling and temperature-driven transition, the hybridized density
modes in the ferromagnetic phase acquire more density character while
approaching the critical point.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Sunilkumar V</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name> Rajat</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sandeep Gautam</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Arko Roy</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">11 pages, 8 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2510.11671v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2510.11671v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cond-mat.quant-gas" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.quant-gas" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2510.11664v1</id>
    <updated>2025-10-13T17:38:02Z</updated>
    <published>2025-10-13T17:38:02Z</published>
    <title>Proprioceptive Misestimation of Hand Speed</title>
    <summary>  The accuracy with which the human proprioceptive system estimates hand speed
is not well understood. To investigate this, we designed an experiment using
hobby-grade mechatronics parts and integrated it as a laboratory exercise in a
large remote laboratory course. In a simple joint position reproduction task,
participants (N = 191) grasped a servomotor-driven shaft with one hand as it
followed a randomized trajectory composed of sinusoidal submovements. They
simultaneously attempted to reproduce the movement by turning the shaft of a
potentiometer with the other hand. Focusing on the first movement of the
trajectory, we found that participants consistently overestimated the speed of
the slowest rotations by ~45% and underestimated the speed of the fastest
rotations also by ~30%. Speed estimation errors were near zero for trajectories
with peak velocities ~63 deg/s. Participants' movements also overshot slow
trajectories and undershot fast trajectories. We show that these trajectory
errors can be explained by a model in which the proprioceptive system
integrates velocity misestimates to infer position.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Caitlin Callaghan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>David J Reinkensmeyer</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">7 pages, 6 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2510.11664v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2510.11664v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="q-bio.NC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="q-bio.NC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2510.11633v1</id>
    <updated>2025-10-13T17:14:14Z</updated>
    <published>2025-10-13T17:14:14Z</published>
    <title>The Role of Congeniality in Multiple Imputation for Doubly Robust Causal
  Estimation</title>
    <summary>  This paper provides clear and practical guidance on the specification of
imputation models when multiple imputation is used in conjunction with doubly
robust estimation methods for causal inference. Through theoretical arguments
and targeted simulations, we show that when a confounder has missing data the
corresponding imputation model must include all variables used in either the
propensity score model or the outcome model, and that these variables must
appear in the same functional form as in the final analysis. Violating these
conditions can lead to biased treatment effect estimates, even when both
components of the doubly robust estimator are correctly specified. We present a
mathematical framework for doubly robust estimation combined with multiple
imputation, establish the theoretical requirements for proper imputation in
this setting, and demonstrate the consequences of misspecification through
simulation. Based on these findings, we offer concrete recommendations to
ensure valid inference when using multiple imputation with doubly robust
methods in applied causal analyses.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Lucy D'Agostino McGowan</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2510.11633v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2510.11633v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="stat.ME" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ME" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.AP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2510.11628v1</id>
    <updated>2025-10-13T17:10:25Z</updated>
    <published>2025-10-13T17:10:25Z</published>
    <title>Bayesian Self-Calibration and Parametric Channel Estimation for 6G
  Antenna Arrays</title>
    <summary>  Accurate channel estimation is essential for both high-rate communication and
high-precision sensing in 6G wireless systems. However, a major performance
limitation arises from calibration mismatches when operating phased-array
antennas under real-world conditions. To address this issue, we propose to
integrate antenna element self-calibration into a variational sparse Bayesian
learning (VSBL) algorithm for parametric channel estimation. We model antenna
gain and phase deviations as latent variables and derive explicit update
equations to jointly infer these calibration parameters and the channel
parameters: the model order, complex amplitudes, delays, angles, and the noise
variance. The resulting algorithm operates online and adapts in real time to
hardware-induced mismatches. We assess its performance in terms of the root
mean square error (RMSE) and the optimal subpattern-assignment (OSPA) metric,
demonstrating consistent improvements over conventional VSBL without
calibration. Our results demonstrate that embedding self-calibration within
Bayesian inference significantly enhances the robustness of channel estimation.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Patrick Hödl</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jakob Möderl</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Erik Leitinger</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Klaus Witrisal</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2510.11628v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2510.11628v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="eess.SP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="eess.SP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2510.11620v1</id>
    <updated>2025-10-13T17:02:41Z</updated>
    <published>2025-10-13T17:02:41Z</published>
    <title>Enhancing Long Chain-of-Thought Reasoning through Multi-Path Plan
  Aggregation</title>
    <summary>  Inference-time scaling enhances the reasoning ability of a language model
(LM) by extending its chain-of-thought (CoT). However, existing approaches
typically generate the entire reasoning chain in a single forward pass, which
often leads to CoT derailment, i.e., the reasoning trajectory drifting off
course due to compounding errors. This problem is particularly severe for
smaller LMs with long CoTs due to their limited capacity. To address this, we
analyze raw long CoTs and uncover a reasoning hierarchy consisting of planning
and execution steps. Our analysis reveals that most reasoning errors stem from
incorrect planning. Motivated by this observation, we propose Multi-Path Plan
Aggregation (MPPA), a framework that augments single-pass reasoning with plan
exploration and aggregation. Following a variable interval schedule based on
the token position, MPPA generates multiple candidate plans and aggregates them
into a refined planning step. To maintain efficiency, we adopt a minimal design
in which the base LM serves as the primary policy, while a lightweight LoRA
module implements the plan aggregation policy. We further observe that
outcome-reward RL is inefficient for long trajectories (e.g., exceeding 4K
tokens). To overcome this, we introduce online Step-DPO, a process-level
preference optimization scheme that leverages Twisted Sequential Monte Carlo
(TSMC) to provide scalable stepwise supervision using small LMs. This yields
more efficient training, improved stability, and higher accuracy. Extensive
experiments on challenging math, science, and logical reasoning benchmarks
demonstrate that, with only 10% SFT data and 5% of preference pairs, our method
outperforms both the DeepSeek-R1 distillation baseline and the outcome-reward
RL baseline across multiple base models and tasks.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Siheng Xiong</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ali Payani</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Faramarz Fekri</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2510.11620v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2510.11620v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2510.11600v1</id>
    <updated>2025-10-13T16:40:44Z</updated>
    <published>2025-10-13T16:40:44Z</published>
    <title>A framework for realisable data-driven active flow control using model
  predictive control applied to a simplified truck wake</title>
    <summary>  We present an efficient and realisable active flow control framework with few
non-intrusive sensors. The method builds upon data-driven, reduced-order
predictive models based on Long-Short-Term Memory (LSTM) networks and efficient
gradient-based Model Predictive Control (MPC). The model uses only
surface-mounted pressure probes to infer the wake state, and is trained
entirely offline on a dataset built with open-loop actuations, thus avoiding
the complexities of online learning. Sparsification of the sensors needed for
control from an initially large set is achieved using SHapley Additive
exPlanations. A parsimonious set of sensors is then deployed in closed-loop
control with MPC. The framework is tested in numerical simulations of a 2D
truck model at Reynolds number 500, with pulsed-jet actuators placed in the
rear of the truck to control the wake. The parsimonious LSTM-MPC achieved a
drag reduction of 12.8%.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Alberto Solera-Rico</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Carlos Sanmiguel Vila</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Stefano Discetti</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">28 pages, 15 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2510.11600v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2510.11600v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="physics.flu-dyn" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.flu-dyn" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="76D55" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="I.2.8; J.2" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
