<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Last updated: 2025-05-02T00:55:28Z -->
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3Dall%3Acausal%20inference%26id_list%3D%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=all:causal inference&amp;id_list=&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/SsRksLzRb0LuVhSmQ+N8WbAs+f8</id>
  <updated>2025-05-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">111501</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.21856v1</id>
    <updated>2025-04-30T17:59:59Z</updated>
    <published>2025-04-30T17:59:59Z</published>
    <title>Holography and Causality in the Karch-Randall Braneworld</title>
    <summary>  It has been argued that the existence of a geodesic shortcut in the
Karch-Randall (KR) braneworld rules out the possibility for a low-energy
intermediate theory, even when gravity is turned off. We study this problem in
an explicit example with two symmetrically placed KR branes. We find that there
can be a consistent quantization of bulk matter fields with a holographic
intermediate description. In our model, there is no causality violation. We use
this example to study potential implications of the bulk geodesic shortcut. We
find that there are possible enhancements of the correlation or entanglement
between the two branes that is directly correlated with the extra-dimensional
geometry. This could affect the low-energy regime when there are interactions
between low and high energy modes. Our model makes it clear that any possible
causality violation can only arise from the UV. Independently of the
quantization, an intermediate description should be valid as an EFT.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Hao Geng</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lisa Randall</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">43 pages, 7 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.21856v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2504.21856v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="hep-th" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="hep-th" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="gr-qc" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="hep-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.21853v1</id>
    <updated>2025-04-30T17:59:02Z</updated>
    <published>2025-04-30T17:59:02Z</published>
    <title>A Survey of Interactive Generative Video</title>
    <summary>  Interactive Generative Video (IGV) has emerged as a crucial technology in
response to the growing demand for high-quality, interactive video content
across various domains. In this paper, we define IGV as a technology that
combines generative capabilities to produce diverse high-quality video content
with interactive features that enable user engagement through control signals
and responsive feedback. We survey the current landscape of IGV applications,
focusing on three major domains: 1) gaming, where IGV enables infinite
exploration in virtual worlds; 2) embodied AI, where IGV serves as a
physics-aware environment synthesizer for training agents in multimodal
interaction with dynamically evolving scenes; and 3) autonomous driving, where
IGV provides closed-loop simulation capabilities for safety-critical testing
and validation. To guide future development, we propose a comprehensive
framework that decomposes an ideal IGV system into five essential modules:
Generation, Control, Memory, Dynamics, and Intelligence. Furthermore, we
systematically analyze the technical challenges and future directions in
realizing each component for an ideal IGV system, such as achieving real-time
generation, enabling open-domain control, maintaining long-term coherence,
simulating accurate physics, and integrating causal reasoning. We believe that
this systematic analysis will facilitate future research and development in the
field of IGV, ultimately advancing the technology toward more sophisticated and
practical applications.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Jiwen Yu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yiran Qin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Haoxuan Che</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Quande Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xintao Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Pengfei Wan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Di Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kun Gai</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hao Chen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xihui Liu</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.21853v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2504.21853v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.21844v1</id>
    <updated>2025-04-30T17:53:08Z</updated>
    <published>2025-04-30T17:53:08Z</published>
    <title>Scalable Multi-Task Learning for Particle Collision Event Reconstruction
  with Heterogeneous Graph Neural Networks</title>
    <summary>  The growing luminosity frontier at the Large Hadron Collider is challenging
the reconstruction and analysis of particle collision events. Increased
particle multiplicities are straining latency and storage requirements at the
data acquisition stage, while new complications are emerging, including higher
background levels and more frequent particle vertex misassociations. This in
turn necessitates the development of more holistic and scalable reconstruction
methods that take advantage of recent advances in machine learning. We propose
a novel Heterogeneous Graph Neural Network (HGNN) architecture featuring unique
representations for diverse particle collision relationships and integrated
graph pruning layers for scalability. Trained with a multi-task paradigm in an
environment mimicking the LHCb experiment, this HGNN significantly improves
beauty hadron reconstruction performance. Notably, it concurrently performs
particle vertex association and graph pruning within a single framework. We
quantify reconstruction and pruning performance, demonstrate enhanced inference
time scaling with event complexity, and mitigate potential performance loss
using a weighted message passing scheme.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>William Sutcliffe</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Marta Calvi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Simone Capelli</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jonas Eschle</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Julián García Pardiñas</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Abhijit Mathad</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Azusa Uzuki</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Nicola Serra</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">21 pages, 10 figures, 4 tables</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.21844v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2504.21844v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="physics.data-an" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.data-an" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="hep-ex" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.21840v1</id>
    <updated>2025-04-30T17:50:47Z</updated>
    <published>2025-04-30T17:50:47Z</published>
    <title>Parameter Inference of Black Hole Images using Deep Learning in
  Visibility Space</title>
    <summary>  Using very long baseline interferometry, the Event Horizon Telescope (EHT)
collaboration has resolved the shadows of two supermassive black holes. Model
comparison is traditionally performed in image space, where imaging algorithms
introduce uncertainties in the recovered structure. Here, we develop a deep
learning framework to perform parameter inference in visibility space, directly
using the data measured by the interferometer without introducing potential
errors and biases from image reconstruction. First, we train and validate our
framework on synthetic data derived from general relativistic
magnetohydrodynamics (GRMHD) simulations that vary in magnetic field state,
spin, and $R_\mathrm{high}$. Applying these models to the real data obtained
during the 2017 EHT campaign, and only considering total intensity, we do not
derive meaningful constraints on either of these parameters. At present, our
method is limited both by theoretical uncertainties in the GRMHD simulations
and variation between snapshots of the same underlying physical model. However,
we demonstrate that spin and $R_\mathrm{high}$ could be recovered using this
framework through continuous monitoring of our sources, which mitigates
variations due to turbulence. In future work, we anticipate that including
spectral or polarimetric information will greatly improve the performance of
this framework.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Franc O</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Pavlos Protopapas</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Dominic W. Pesce</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Angelo Ricarte</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sheperd S. Doeleman</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Cecilia Garraffo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lindy Blackburn</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mauricio Santillana</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.21840v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2504.21840v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.21831v1</id>
    <updated>2025-04-30T17:37:55Z</updated>
    <published>2025-04-30T17:37:55Z</published>
    <title>Early Exit and Multi Stage Knowledge Distillation in VLMs for Video
  Summarization</title>
    <summary>  We introduce DEEVISum (Distilled Early Exit Vision language model for
Summarization), a lightweight, efficient, and scalable vision language model
designed for segment wise video summarization. Leveraging multi modal prompts
that combine textual and audio derived signals, DEEVISum incorporates Multi
Stage Knowledge Distillation (MSKD) and Early Exit (EE) to strike a balance
between performance and efficiency. MSKD offers a 1.33% absolute F1 improvement
over baseline distillation (0.5%), while EE reduces inference time by
approximately 21% with a 1.3 point drop in F1. Evaluated on the TVSum dataset,
our best model PaLI Gemma2 3B + MSKD achieves an F1 score of 61.1, competing
the performance of significantly larger models, all while maintaining a lower
computational footprint. We publicly release our code and processed dataset to
support further research.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Anas Anwarul Haq Khan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Utkarsh Verma</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Prateek Chanda</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ganesh Ramakrishnan</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.21831v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2504.21831v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.21812v1</id>
    <updated>2025-04-30T17:15:55Z</updated>
    <published>2025-04-30T17:15:55Z</published>
    <title>Easily Computed Marginal Likelihoods for Multivariate Mixture Models
  Using the THAMES Estimator</title>
    <summary>  We present a new version of the truncated harmonic mean estimator (THAMES)
for univariate or multivariate mixture models. The estimator computes the
marginal likelihood from Markov chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) samples, is
consistent, asymptotically normal and of finite variance. In addition, it is
invariant to label switching, does not require posterior samples from hidden
allocation vectors, and is easily approximated, even for an arbitrarily high
number of components. Its computational efficiency is based on an
asymptotically optimal ordering of the parameter space, which can in turn be
used to provide useful visualisations. We test it in simulation settings where
the true marginal likelihood is available analytically. It performs well
against state-of-the-art competitors, even in multivariate settings with a high
number of components. We demonstrate its utility for inference and model
selection on univariate and multivariate data sets.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Martin Metodiev</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Nicholas J. Irons</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Marie Perrot-Dockès</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Pierre Latouche</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Adrian E. Raftery</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">36 pages, 6 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.21812v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2504.21812v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="stat.ME" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ME" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.21725v1</id>
    <updated>2025-04-30T15:11:02Z</updated>
    <published>2025-04-30T15:11:02Z</published>
    <title>New {\em ab initio} constrained extended Skyrme equations of state for
  simulations of neutron stars, supernovae and binary mergers: I. Subsaturation
  density domain</title>
    <summary>  In numerical simulations of core-collapse supernova and binary neutron stars
mergers information about the energetics and composition of matter is
implemented via external tables covering the huge ranges of thermodynamic
conditions explored during the astrophysical evolution. More than 120 general
purpose equation of state tables have been contributed so far. Not all of them
comply with current constraints from theoretical and experimental nuclear
physics and astrophysical observations of neutron stars. Systematic
investigations of the role that dense matter properties play in the evolution
of these astrophysical phenomena require that more equation of state tables are
provided. We build a set of general purpose equation of state tables. At zero
temperature, they comply with all currently accepted constraints, including ab
initio chiral effective field theory calculations of pure neutron and symmetric
nuclear matter. This set is designed to explore a wide variety of the behaviors
of the effective masses as functions of density, which is reflected into a wide
range of thermal behaviors. We employ Brussels extended Skyrme interactions
generated by means of Bayesian inference techniques. An extended nuclear
statistical equilibrium model is developed for modeling sub-saturated
inhomogeneous nuclear matter. We study the properties of sub-saturated
inhomogeneous nuclear matter over wide ranges of density, temperature and
proton fraction. We analyze the mechanisms of transition to homogeneous matter
and estimate the transition density. Our key results include the presence of a
think $^{14}$He layer in the inner crusts of (neo-)neutron stars, significant
abundance of other exotic isotopes of H and He in warm and neutron rich matter
and a detailed study of the thermodynamic stability of cold stellar matter. The
equation of state tables will be publicly available in the Compose online
database.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Adriana R. Raduta</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mikhail V. Beznogov</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">20 pages, 12 figures, 2 tables; submitted to A&amp;A</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.21725v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2504.21725v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="nucl-th" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="nucl-th" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.HE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.21688v1</id>
    <updated>2025-04-30T14:23:50Z</updated>
    <published>2025-04-30T14:23:50Z</published>
    <title>Assessing Racial Disparities in Healthcare Expenditures Using Causal
  Path-Specific Effects</title>
    <summary>  Racial disparities in healthcare expenditures are well-documented, yet the
underlying drivers remain complex and require further investigation. This study
employs causal and counterfactual path-specific effects to quantify how various
factors, including socioeconomic status, insurance access, health behaviors,
and health status, mediate these disparities. Using data from the Medical
Expenditures Panel Survey, we estimate how expenditures would differ under
counterfactual scenarios in which the values of specific mediators were aligned
across racial groups along selected causal pathways. A key challenge in this
analysis is ensuring robustness against model misspecification while addressing
the zero-inflation and right-skewness of healthcare expenditures. For reliable
inference, we derive asymptotically linear estimators by integrating influence
function-based techniques with flexible machine learning methods, including
super learners and a two-part model tailored to the zero-inflated, right-skewed
nature of healthcare expenditures.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Xiaxian Ou</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xinwei He</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>David Benkeser</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Razieh Nabi</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.21688v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2504.21688v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="stat.AP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.AP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ME" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.21668v1</id>
    <updated>2025-04-30T14:10:02Z</updated>
    <published>2025-04-30T14:10:02Z</published>
    <title>Traceback of Poisoning Attacks to Retrieval-Augmented Generation</title>
    <summary>  Large language models (LLMs) integrated with retrieval-augmented generation
(RAG) systems improve accuracy by leveraging external knowledge sources.
However, recent research has revealed RAG's susceptibility to poisoning
attacks, where the attacker injects poisoned texts into the knowledge database,
leading to attacker-desired responses. Existing defenses, which predominantly
focus on inference-time mitigation, have proven insufficient against
sophisticated attacks. In this paper, we introduce RAGForensics, the first
traceback system for RAG, designed to identify poisoned texts within the
knowledge database that are responsible for the attacks. RAGForensics operates
iteratively, first retrieving a subset of texts from the database and then
utilizing a specially crafted prompt to guide an LLM in detecting potential
poisoning texts. Empirical evaluations across multiple datasets demonstrate the
effectiveness of RAGForensics against state-of-the-art poisoning attacks. This
work pioneers the traceback of poisoned texts in RAG systems, providing a
practical and promising defense mechanism to enhance their security.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Baolei Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Haoran Xin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Minghong Fang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zhuqing Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Biao Yi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tong Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zheli Liu</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Accepted by The Web Conference 2025</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.21668v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2504.21668v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.IR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.21659v1</id>
    <updated>2025-04-30T14:01:45Z</updated>
    <published>2025-04-30T14:01:45Z</published>
    <title>AdaR1: From Long-CoT to Hybrid-CoT via Bi-Level Adaptive Reasoning
  Optimization</title>
    <summary>  Recently, long-thought reasoning models achieve strong performance on complex
reasoning tasks, but often incur substantial inference overhead, making
efficiency a critical concern. Our empirical analysis reveals that the benefit
of using Long-CoT varies across problems: while some problems require elaborate
reasoning, others show no improvement, or even degraded accuracy. This
motivates adaptive reasoning strategies that tailor reasoning depth to the
input. However, prior work primarily reduces redundancy within long reasoning
paths, limiting exploration of more efficient strategies beyond the Long-CoT
paradigm. To address this, we propose a novel two-stage framework for adaptive
and efficient reasoning. First, we construct a hybrid reasoning model by
merging long and short CoT models to enable diverse reasoning styles. Second,
we apply bi-level preference training to guide the model to select suitable
reasoning styles (group-level), and prefer concise and correct reasoning within
each style group (instance-level). Experiments demonstrate that our method
significantly reduces inference costs compared to other baseline approaches,
while maintaining performance. Notably, on five mathematical datasets, the
average length of reasoning is reduced by more than 50%, highlighting the
potential of adaptive strategies to optimize reasoning efficiency in large
language models. Our code is coming soon at https://github.com/StarDewXXX/AdaR1
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Haotian Luo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Haiying He</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yibo Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jinluan Yang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Rui Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Naiqiang Tan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xiaochun Cao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Dacheng Tao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Li Shen</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2504.21659v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2504.21659v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
