<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Last updated: 2025-05-14T00:56:06Z -->
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3Dall%3Acausal%20inference%26id_list%3D%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=all:causal inference&amp;id_list=&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/SsRksLzRb0LuVhSmQ+N8WbAs+f8</id>
  <updated>2025-05-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">112076</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.07818v1</id>
    <updated>2025-05-12T17:59:34Z</updated>
    <published>2025-05-12T17:59:34Z</published>
    <title>DanceGRPO: Unleashing GRPO on Visual Generation</title>
    <summary>  Recent breakthroughs in generative models-particularly diffusion models and
rectified flows-have revolutionized visual content creation, yet aligning model
outputs with human preferences remains a critical challenge. Existing
reinforcement learning (RL)-based methods for visual generation face critical
limitations: incompatibility with modern Ordinary Differential Equations
(ODEs)-based sampling paradigms, instability in large-scale training, and lack
of validation for video generation. This paper introduces DanceGRPO, the first
unified framework to adapt Group Relative Policy Optimization (GRPO) to visual
generation paradigms, unleashing one unified RL algorithm across two generative
paradigms (diffusion models and rectified flows), three tasks (text-to-image,
text-to-video, image-to-video), four foundation models (Stable Diffusion,
HunyuanVideo, FLUX, SkyReel-I2V), and five reward models (image/video
aesthetics, text-image alignment, video motion quality, and binary reward). To
our knowledge, DanceGRPO is the first RL-based unified framework capable of
seamless adaptation across diverse generative paradigms, tasks, foundational
models, and reward models. DanceGRPO demonstrates consistent and substantial
improvements, which outperform baselines by up to 181% on benchmarks such as
HPS-v2.1, CLIP Score, VideoAlign, and GenEval. Notably, DanceGRPO not only can
stabilize policy optimization for complex video generation, but also enables
generative policy to better capture denoising trajectories for Best-of-N
inference scaling and learn from sparse binary feedback. Our results establish
DanceGRPO as a robust and versatile solution for scaling Reinforcement Learning
from Human Feedback (RLHF) tasks in visual generation, offering new insights
into harmonizing reinforcement learning and visual synthesis. The code will be
released.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Zeyue Xue</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jie Wu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yu Gao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Fangyuan Kong</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lingting Zhu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mengzhao Chen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zhiheng Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Wei Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Qiushan Guo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Weilin Huang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ping Luo</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Project Page: https://dancegrpo.github.io/</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.07818v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2505.07818v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.07802v1</id>
    <updated>2025-05-12T17:50:10Z</updated>
    <published>2025-05-12T17:50:10Z</published>
    <title>Improving Trajectory Stitching with Flow Models</title>
    <summary>  Generative models have shown great promise as trajectory planners, given
their affinity to modeling complex distributions and guidable inference
process. Previous works have successfully applied these in the context of
robotic manipulation but perform poorly when the required solution does not
exist as a complete trajectory within the training set. We identify that this
is a result of being unable to plan via stitching, and subsequently address the
architectural and dataset choices needed to remedy this. On top of this, we
propose a novel addition to the training and inference procedures to both
stabilize and enhance these capabilities. We demonstrate the efficacy of our
approach by generating plans with out of distribution boundary conditions and
performing obstacle avoidance on the Franka Panda in simulation and on real
hardware. In both of these tasks our method performs significantly better than
the baselines and is able to avoid obstacles up to four times as large.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Reece O'Mahoney</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Wanming Yu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ioannis Havoutis</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.07802v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2505.07802v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.07793v1</id>
    <updated>2025-05-12T17:45:05Z</updated>
    <published>2025-05-12T17:45:05Z</published>
    <title>Overflow Prevention Enhances Long-Context Recurrent LLMs</title>
    <summary>  A recent trend in LLMs is developing recurrent sub-quadratic models that
improve long-context processing efficiency. We investigate leading large
long-context models, focusing on how their fixed-size recurrent memory affects
their performance. Our experiments reveal that, even when these models are
trained for extended contexts, their use of long contexts remains
underutilized. Specifically, we demonstrate that a chunk-based inference
procedure, which identifies and processes only the most relevant portion of the
input can mitigate recurrent memory failures and be effective for many
long-context tasks: On LongBench, our method improves the overall performance
of Falcon3-Mamba-Inst-7B by 14%, Falcon-Mamba-Inst-7B by 28%,
RecurrentGemma-IT-9B by 50%, and RWKV6-Finch-7B by 51%. Surprisingly, this
simple approach also leads to state-of-the-art results in the challenging
LongBench v2 benchmark, showing competitive performance with equivalent size
Transformers. Furthermore, our findings raise questions about whether recurrent
models genuinely exploit long-range dependencies, as our single-chunk strategy
delivers stronger performance - even in tasks that presumably require
cross-context relations.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Assaf Ben-Kish</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Itamar Zimerman</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>M. Jehanzeb Mirza</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>James Glass</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Leonid Karlinsky</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Raja Giryes</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.07793v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2505.07793v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.07787v1</id>
    <updated>2025-05-12T17:39:56Z</updated>
    <published>2025-05-12T17:39:56Z</published>
    <title>Learning from Peers in Reasoning Models</title>
    <summary>  Large Reasoning Models (LRMs) have the ability to self-correct even when they
make mistakes in their reasoning paths. However, our study reveals that when
the reasoning process starts with a short but poor beginning, it becomes
difficult for the model to recover. We refer to this phenomenon as the "Prefix
Dominance Trap". Inspired by psychological findings that peer interaction can
promote self-correction without negatively impacting already accurate
individuals, we propose **Learning from Peers** (LeaP) to address this
phenomenon. Specifically, every tokens, each reasoning path summarizes its
intermediate reasoning and shares it with others through a routing mechanism,
enabling paths to incorporate peer insights during inference. However, we
observe that smaller models sometimes fail to follow summarization and
reflection instructions effectively. To address this, we fine-tune them into
our **LeaP-T** model series. Experiments on AIME 2024, AIME 2025, AIMO 2025,
and GPQA Diamond show that LeaP provides substantial improvements. For
instance, QwQ-32B with LeaP achieves nearly 5 absolute points higher than the
baseline on average, and surpasses DeepSeek-R1-671B on three math benchmarks
with an average gain of 3.3 points. Notably, our fine-tuned LeaP-T-7B matches
the performance of DeepSeek-R1-Distill-Qwen-14B on AIME 2024. In-depth analysis
reveals LeaP's robust error correction by timely peer insights, showing strong
error tolerance and handling varied task difficulty. LeaP marks a milestone by
enabling LRMs to collaborate during reasoning. Our code, datasets, and models
are available at https://learning-from-peers.github.io/ .
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Tongxu Luo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Wenyu Du</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jiaxi Bi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Stephen Chung</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zhengyang Tang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hao Yang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Min Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Benyou Wang</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">29 pages, 32 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.07787v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2505.07787v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.07785v1</id>
    <updated>2025-05-12T17:38:09Z</updated>
    <published>2025-05-12T17:38:09Z</published>
    <title>Conditions for accretion favoring an unmelted Callisto and a
  differentiated Ganymede</title>
    <summary>  Analysis of Callisto's moments of inertia, derived from Galileo's gravity
data, suggests that its structure is not fully differentiated. This possibly
undifferentiated state contrasts sharply with the globally molten state
inferred in its counterpart, Ganymede, and poses unique challenges to theories
of the formation and evolution of the Galilean moons. During their formation,
both moons experienced multiple heating mechanisms, including tidal heating,
radiogenic heating from short-lived radionuclides, accretional heating from
impacts, and heat from the surrounding circumplanetary disk. Our study
investigates the optimal conditions required to account for Callisto's
partially differentiated state in contrast to Ganymede's complete
differentiation. We investigate crucial accretion parameters, such as the
timing of accretion onset, the duration of accretion, and the impactor size
distribution. We find that the observed dichotomy between Ganymede and Callisto
can be attributed to similar formation conditions, assuming an identical
impactor size distribution and composition in the Jovian circumplanetary disk.
The key differences in the formation of Ganymede and Callisto are the disk
temperature at their respective formation locations and their final radii. Our
results indicate that both moons accreted gradually over more than 2 Myr,
concluding at least 5.5 Myr after the formation of calcium-aluminum-rich
inclusions in the protosolar nebula. Our model demonstrates that Callisto can
remain undifferentiated despite accreting a substantial influx of
kilometer-sized impactors, potentially contributing up to 30% of the total mass
inflow, while still allowing for the complete differentiation of Ganymede.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Yannis Bennacer</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Olivier Mousis</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Marc Monnereau</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Vincent Hue</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Antoine Schneeberger</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Accepted for publication in the Planetary Science Journal</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.07785v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2505.07785v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="astro-ph.EP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.EP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.07751v1</id>
    <updated>2025-05-12T16:58:08Z</updated>
    <published>2025-05-12T16:58:08Z</published>
    <title>Naturalistic Metaphysics and the Parity Thesis: Why Scientific Realism
  Doesn't Lead to Realism about Metaphysics</title>
    <summary>  In recent work, Nina Emery has defended the view that, in the context of
naturalistic metaphysics, one should maintain the same epistemic attitude
towards science and metaphysics. That is, naturalists who are scientific
realists ought to be realists about metaphysics as well; and naturalists who
are antirealists about science should also be antirealists about metaphysics.
We call this the `parity thesis'. This paper suggests that the parity thesis is
widely, albeit often implicitly, accepted among naturalistically inclined
philosophers, and essentially for reasons similar to Emery's. Then, reasons are
provided for resisting Emery's specific inference from scientific realism to
realism about metaphysics. The resulting picture is a more nuanced view of the
relationship between science and metaphysics within the naturalistic setting
than the one which is currently most popular.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Raoni Arroyo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Matteo Morganti</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Accepted manuscript, forthcoming in Synthese</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.07751v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2505.07751v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="physics.hist-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.hist-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.07730v1</id>
    <updated>2025-05-12T16:37:47Z</updated>
    <published>2025-05-12T16:37:47Z</published>
    <title>Reproducibility, Replicability, and Insights into Visual Document
  Retrieval with Late Interaction</title>
    <summary>  Visual Document Retrieval (VDR) is an emerging research area that focuses on
encoding and retrieving document images directly, bypassing the dependence on
Optical Character Recognition (OCR) for document search. A recent advance in
VDR was introduced by ColPali, which significantly improved retrieval
effectiveness through a late interaction mechanism. ColPali's approach
demonstrated substantial performance gains over existing baselines that do not
use late interaction on an established benchmark. In this study, we investigate
the reproducibility and replicability of VDR methods with and without late
interaction mechanisms by systematically evaluating their performance across
multiple pre-trained vision-language models. Our findings confirm that late
interaction yields considerable improvements in retrieval effectiveness;
however, it also introduces computational inefficiencies during inference.
Additionally, we examine the adaptability of VDR models to textual inputs and
assess their robustness across text-intensive datasets within the proposed
benchmark, particularly when scaling the indexing mechanism. Furthermore, our
research investigates the specific contributions of late interaction by looking
into query-patch matching in the context of visual document retrieval. We find
that although query tokens cannot explicitly match image patches as in the text
retrieval scenario, they tend to match the patch contains visually similar
tokens or their surrounding patches.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Jingfen Qiao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jia-Huei Ju</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xinyu Ma</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Evangelos Kanoulas</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Yates</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.07730v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2505.07730v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.IR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.IR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.07729v1</id>
    <updated>2025-05-12T16:36:55Z</updated>
    <published>2025-05-12T16:36:55Z</published>
    <title>Nonparametric Instrumental Variable Inference with Many Weak Instruments</title>
    <summary>  We study inference on linear functionals in the nonparametric instrumental
variable (NPIV) problem with a discretely-valued instrument under a
many-weak-instruments asymptotic regime, where the number of instrument values
grows with the sample size. A key motivating example is estimating long-term
causal effects in a new experiment with only short-term outcomes, using past
experiments to instrument for the effect of short- on long-term outcomes. Here,
the assignment to a past experiment serves as the instrument: we have many past
experiments but only a limited number of units in each. Since the structural
function is nonparametric but constrained by only finitely many moment
restrictions, point identification typically fails. To address this, we
consider linear functionals of the minimum-norm solution to the moment
restrictions, which is always well-defined. As the number of instrument levels
grows, these functionals define an approximating sequence to a target
functional, replacing point identification with a weaker asymptotic notion
suited to discrete instruments. Extending the Jackknife Instrumental Variable
Estimator (JIVE) beyond the classical parametric setting, we propose npJIVE, a
nonparametric estimator for solutions to linear inverse problems with many weak
instruments. We construct automatic debiased machine learning estimators for
linear functionals of both the structural function and its minimum-norm
projection, and establish their efficiency in the many-weak-instruments regime.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Lars van der Laan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Nathan Kallus</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Aurélien Bibaut</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.07729v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2505.07729v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="stat.ME" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ME" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.ST" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.TH" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.07721v1</id>
    <updated>2025-05-12T16:28:22Z</updated>
    <published>2025-05-12T16:28:22Z</published>
    <title>Gameplay Highlights Generation</title>
    <summary>  In this work, we enable gamers to share their gaming experience on social
media by automatically generating eye-catching highlight reels from their
gameplay session Our automation will save time for gamers while increasing
audience engagement. We approach the highlight generation problem by first
identifying intervals in the video where interesting events occur and then
concatenate them. We developed an in-house gameplay event detection dataset
containing interesting events annotated by humans using VIA video annotator.
Traditional techniques for highlight detection such as game engine integration
requires expensive collaboration with game developers. OCR techniques which
detect patches of specific images or texts require expensive per game
engineering and may not generalize across game UI and different language. We
finetuned a multimodal general purpose video understanding model such as X-CLIP
using our dataset which generalizes across multiple games in a genre without
per game engineering. Prompt engineering was performed to improve the
classification performance of this multimodal model. Our evaluation showed that
such a finetuned model can detect interesting events in first person shooting
games from unseen gameplay footage with more than 90% accuracy. Moreover, our
model performed significantly better on low resource games (small dataset) when
trained along with high resource games, showing signs of transfer learning. To
make the model production ready, we used ONNX libraries to enable cross
platform inference. These libraries also provide post training quantization
tools to reduce model size and inference time for deployment. ONNX runtime
libraries with DirectML backend were used to perform efficient inference on
Windows OS. We show that natural language supervision in the X-CLIP model leads
to data efficient and highly performant video recognition models.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Vignesh Edithal</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Le Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ilia Blank</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Imran Junejo</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.07721v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2505.07721v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.07713v1</id>
    <updated>2025-05-12T16:19:03Z</updated>
    <published>2025-05-12T16:19:03Z</published>
    <title>Routing Attacks in Ethereum PoS: A Systematic Exploration</title>
    <summary>  With the promise of greater decentralization and sustainability, Ethereum
transitioned from a Proof-of-Work (PoW) to a Proof-of-Stake (PoS) consensus
mechanism. The new consensus protocol introduces novel vulnerabilities that
warrant further investigation. The goal of this paper is to investigate the
security of Ethereum's PoS system from an Internet routing perspective.
  To this end, this paper makes two contributions: First, we devise a novel
framework for inferring the distribution of validators on the Internet without
disturbing the real network. Second, we introduce a class of network-level
attacks on Ethereum's PoS system that jointly exploit Internet routing
vulnerabilities with the protocol's reward and penalty mechanisms. We describe
two representative attacks: StakeBleed, where the attacker triggers an
inactivity leak, halting block finality and causing financial losses for all
validators; and KnockBlock, where the attacker increases her expected MEV gains
by preventing targeted blocks from being included in the chain. We find that
both attacks are practical and effective. An attacker executing StakeBleed can
inflict losses of almost 300 ETH in just 2 hours by hijacking as few as 30 IP
prefixes. An attacker implementing KnockBlock could increase their MEV expected
gains by 44.5% while hijacking a single prefix for less than 2 minutes.
  Our paper serves as a call to action for validators to reinforce their
Internet routing infrastructure and for the Ethereum P2P protocol to implement
stronger mechanisms to conceal validator locations.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Constantine Doumanidis</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Maria Apostolaki</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">15 pages, 16 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.07713v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2505.07713v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.NI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.NI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
