<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Last updated: 2025-09-17T00:51:54Z -->
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3Dall%3Acausal%20inference%26id_list%3D%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=all:causal inference&amp;id_list=&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/SsRksLzRb0LuVhSmQ+N8WbAs+f8</id>
  <updated>2025-09-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">120958</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.12199v1</id>
    <updated>2025-09-15T17:58:22Z</updated>
    <published>2025-09-15T17:58:22Z</published>
    <title>Deriving accurate galaxy cluster masses using X-ray thermodynamic
  profiles and graph neural networks</title>
    <summary>  Precise determination of galaxy cluster masses is crucial for establishing
reliable mass-observable scaling relations in cluster cosmology. We employ
graph neural networks (GNNs) to estimate galaxy cluster masses from radially
sampled profiles of the intra-cluster medium (ICM) inferred from X-ray
observations. GNNs naturally handle inputs of variable length and resolution by
representing each ICM profile as a graph, enabling accurate and flexible
modeling across diverse observational conditions. We trained and tested GNN
model using state-of-the-art hydrodynamical simulations of galaxy clusters from
The Three Hundred Project. The mass estimates using our method exhibit no
systematic bias compared to the true cluster masses in the simulations.
Additionally, we achieve a scatter in recovered mass versus true mass of about
6\%, which is a factor of six smaller than obtained from a standard hydrostatic
equilibrium approach. Our algorithm is robust to both data quality and cluster
morphology and it is capable of incorporating model uncertainties alongside
observational uncertainties. Finally, we apply our technique to XMM-Newton
observed galaxy cluster samples and compare the GNN derived mass estimates with
those obtained with $Y_{\rm SZ}$-M$_{500}$ scaling relations. Our results
provide strong evidence, at 5$\sigma$ level, for a mass-dependent bias in SZ
derived masses, with higher mass clusters exhibiting a greater degree of
deviation. Furthermore, we find the median bias to be $(1-b)=0.85_{-14}^{+34}$,
albeit with significant dispersion due to its mass dependence. This work takes
a significant step towards establishing unbiased observable mass scaling
relations by integrating X-ray, SZ and optical datasets using deep learning
techniques, thereby enhancing the role of galaxy clusters in precision
cosmology.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Asif Iqbal</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Subhabrata Majumdar</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Elena Rasia</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Gabriel W. Pratt</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Daniel de Andres</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jean-Baptiste Melin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Weiguang Cui</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">20 pages, 15 figures, 6 tables, resubmitted to A&amp;A after revision,
  comments welcome</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.12199v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2509.12199v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="astro-ph.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.12187v1</id>
    <updated>2025-09-15T17:50:57Z</updated>
    <published>2025-09-15T17:50:57Z</published>
    <title>HoloGarment: 360° Novel View Synthesis of In-the-Wild Garments</title>
    <summary>  Novel view synthesis (NVS) of in-the-wild garments is a challenging task due
significant occlusions, complex human poses, and cloth deformations. Prior
methods rely on synthetic 3D training data consisting of mostly unoccluded and
static objects, leading to poor generalization on real-world clothing. In this
paper, we propose HoloGarment (Hologram-Garment), a method that takes 1-3
images or a continuous video of a person wearing a garment and generates
360{\deg} novel views of the garment in a canonical pose. Our key insight is to
bridge the domain gap between real and synthetic data with a novel implicit
training paradigm leveraging a combination of large-scale real video data and
small-scale synthetic 3D data to optimize a shared garment embedding space.
During inference, the shared embedding space further enables dynamic
video-to-360{\deg} NVS through the construction of a garment "atlas"
representation by finetuning a garment embedding on a specific real-world
video. The atlas captures garment-specific geometry and texture across all
viewpoints, independent of body pose or motion. Extensive experiments show that
HoloGarment achieves state-of-the-art performance on NVS of in-the-wild
garments from images and videos. Notably, our method robustly handles
challenging real-world artifacts -- such as wrinkling, pose variation, and
occlusion -- while maintaining photorealism, view consistency, fine texture
details, and accurate geometry. Visit our project page for additional results:
https://johannakarras.github.io/HoloGarment
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Johanna Karras</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yingwei Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yasamin Jafarian</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ira Kemelmacher-Shlizerman</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.12187v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2509.12187v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.GR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.12176v1</id>
    <updated>2025-09-15T17:40:19Z</updated>
    <published>2025-09-15T17:40:19Z</published>
    <title>From Autoencoders to CycleGAN: Robust Unpaired Face Manipulation via
  Adversarial Learning</title>
    <summary>  Human face synthesis and manipulation are increasingly important in
entertainment and AI, with a growing demand for highly realistic,
identity-preserving images even when only unpaired, unaligned datasets are
available. We study unpaired face manipulation via adversarial learning, moving
from autoencoder baselines to a robust, guided CycleGAN framework. While
autoencoders capture coarse identity, they often miss fine details. Our
approach integrates spectral normalization for stable training, identity- and
perceptual-guided losses to preserve subject identity and high-level structure,
and landmark-weighted cycle constraints to maintain facial geometry across pose
and illumination changes. Experiments show that our adversarial trained
CycleGAN improves realism (FID), perceptual quality (LPIPS), and identity
preservation (ID-Sim) over autoencoders, with competitive cycle-reconstruction
SSIM and practical inference times, which achieved high quality without paired
datasets and approaching pix2pix on curated paired subsets. These results
demonstrate that guided, spectrally normalized CycleGANs provide a practical
path from autoencoders to robust unpaired face manipulation.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Collin Guo</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">8 pages, 7 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.12176v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2509.12176v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.12175v1</id>
    <updated>2025-09-15T17:38:12Z</updated>
    <published>2025-09-15T17:38:12Z</published>
    <title>An Optomechanical Accelerometer Search for Ultralight Dark Matter</title>
    <summary>  We use a cavity optomechanical accelerometer to perform a resonant search for
ultralight dark matter at acoustic frequencies near 39 kHz (a particle mass of
$0.16$ neV/$c^2$). The accelerometer is based on a Si$_3$N$_4$ membrane,
cryogenically cooled to 4 K, with photothermal heating employed to scan the
resonance frequency by $10^2$ detector linewidths. Leveraging
shot-noise-limited displacement readout and radiation pressure feedback
cooling, we realize an acceleration resolution of $\sim
10\;\text{n}g_0/\sqrt{\text{Hz}}$ over a bandwidth of $30$ Hz near the
fundamental test mass resonance. We find no evidence of a dark matter signal
and infer an upper bound on the coupling to normal matter that is several
orders of magnitude above the stringent bounds set by equivalence principle
experiments. We outline a path toward novel dark matter constraints in future
experiments by exploiting arrays of mass-loaded optomechanical sensors at lower
temperature probed with distributed squeezed light.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>M. Dey Chowdhury</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>J. P. Manley</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>C. A. Condos</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>A. R. Agrawal</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>D. J. Wilson</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">17 pages, 12 figures, 2 tables</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.12175v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2509.12175v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="hep-ex" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="hep-ex" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.IM" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.ins-det" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.optics" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.12168v1</id>
    <updated>2025-09-15T17:31:15Z</updated>
    <published>2025-09-15T17:31:15Z</published>
    <title>RAGs to Riches: RAG-like Few-shot Learning for Large Language Model
  Role-playing</title>
    <summary>  Role-playing Large language models (LLMs) are increasingly deployed in
high-stakes domains such as healthcare, education, and governance, where
failures can directly impact user trust and well-being. A cost effective
paradigm for LLM role-playing is few-shot learning, but existing approaches
often cause models to break character in unexpected and potentially harmful
ways, especially when interacting with hostile users. Inspired by
Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG), we reformulate LLM role-playing into a
text retrieval problem and propose a new prompting framework called
RAGs-to-Riches, which leverages curated reference demonstrations to condition
LLM responses. We evaluate our framework with LLM-as-a-judge preference voting
and introduce two novel token-level ROUGE metrics: Intersection over Output
(IOO) to quantity how much an LLM improvises and Intersection over References
(IOR) to measure few-shot demonstrations utilization rate during the evaluation
tasks. When simulating interactions with a hostile user, our prompting strategy
incorporates in its responses during inference an average of 35% more tokens
from the reference demonstrations. As a result, across 453 role-playing
interactions, our models are consistently judged as being more authentic, and
remain in-character more often than zero-shot and in-context Learning (ICL)
methods. Our method presents a scalable strategy for building robust,
human-aligned LLM role-playing frameworks.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Timothy Rupprecht</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Enfu Nan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Arash Akbari</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Arman Akbari</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lei Lu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Priyanka Maan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Duffy</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Pu Zhao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yumei He</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>David Kaeli</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yanzhi Wang</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.12168v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2509.12168v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.12166v1</id>
    <updated>2025-09-15T17:30:31Z</updated>
    <published>2025-09-15T17:30:31Z</published>
    <title>MMM: Clustering Multivariate Longitudinal Mixed-type Data</title>
    <summary>  Multivariate longitudinal data of mixed-type are increasingly collected in
many science domains. However, algorithms to cluster this kind of data remain
scarce, due to the challenge to simultaneously model the within- and
between-time dependence structures for multivariate data of mixed kind. We
introduce the Mixture of Mixed-Matrices (MMM) model: reorganizing the data in a
three-way structure and assuming that the non-continuous variables are
observations of underlying latent continuous variables, the model relies on a
mixture of matrix-variate normal distributions to perform clustering in the
latent dimension. The MMM model is thus able to handle continuous, ordinal,
binary, nominal and count data and to concurrently model the heterogeneity, the
association among the responses and the temporal dependence structure in a
parsimonious way and without assuming conditional independence. The inference
is carried out through an MCMC-EM algorithm, which is detailed. An evaluation
of the model through synthetic data shows its inference abilities. A real-world
application on financial data is presented.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Francesco Amato</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Julien Jacques</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.12166v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2509.12166v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ME" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.12164v1</id>
    <updated>2025-09-15T17:26:36Z</updated>
    <published>2025-09-15T17:26:36Z</published>
    <title>Anomalous electron heating in laboratory magnetized quasi-perpendicular
  collisionless shocks</title>
    <summary>  We present laboratory results from supercritical, magnetized collisionless
shock experiments ($M_A \lesssim 10$, $\beta\sim 1$). We report the first
observation of fully-developed shocks ($R=4$ compression ratio and a downstream
region decoupled from the piston) after seven upstream ion gyration periods. A
foot ahead of the shock exhibits super-adiabatic electron and ion heating. We
measure the electron temperature $T_e = 115$ eV and ion temperature $T_i = 15$
eV upstream of the shock; whereas, downstream, we measure $T_e=390$ eV and
infer $T_i=340$ eV, consistent with both Thomson scattering ion-acoustic wave
spectral broadening and Rankine-Hugoniot conditions. The downstream electron
temperature has a $30$-percent excess from adiabatic and collisional
electron-ion heating, implying significant collisionless anomalous electron
heating. Furthermore, downstream electrons and ions are in equipartition, with
a unity electron-ion temperature ratio $T_e/T_i = 1.2$.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>V. Valenzuela-Villaseca</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>S. Totorica</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>J. Griff-McMahon</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>L. -J. Chen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>S. Malko</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>P. V. Heuer</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>P. Pongkitiwanichakul</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>W. Fox</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>D. B. Schaeffer</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Main body: 7 pages, 4 Figures, 59 references. Supplemental material:
  12 pages, 5 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.12164v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2509.12164v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="physics.plasm-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.plasm-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.HE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.SR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.12162v1</id>
    <updated>2025-09-15T17:25:12Z</updated>
    <published>2025-09-15T17:25:12Z</published>
    <title>Quantifying Mental States in Work Environment: Mathematical Perspectives</title>
    <summary>  This article presents a study involving 87 participants exposed to a
stressful scenario in a virtual reality (VR) environment. An algorithm was
developed to assign a positive or negative valence based on questionnaire
responses. EEG signals were recorded, and a k-nearest neighbors (KNN) algorithm
was trained to infer emotional valence from these signals. Our objective is to
further develop mathematical models capable of describing the dynamic evolution
of emotional and mental states.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Aymen Balti</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Assane Wade</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Abdelatif Oujbara</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>M. A.</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name> Aziz-Alaoui</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hicham Bellarabi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Frederic Dutertre</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Benjamin Ambrosio</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.12162v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2509.12162v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="q-bio.NC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="q-bio.NC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.12159v1</id>
    <updated>2025-09-15T17:23:46Z</updated>
    <published>2025-09-15T17:23:46Z</published>
    <title>EfficientUICoder: Efficient MLLM-based UI Code Generation via Input and
  Output Token Compression</title>
    <summary>  Multimodal Large Language Models have demonstrated exceptional performance in
UI2Code tasks, significantly enhancing website development efficiency. However,
these tasks incur substantially higher computational overhead than traditional
code generation due to the large number of input image tokens and extensive
output code tokens required. Our comprehensive study identifies significant
redundancies in both image and code tokens that exacerbate computational
complexity and hinder focus on key UI elements, resulting in excessively
lengthy and often invalid HTML files. We propose EfficientUICoder, a
compression framework for efficient UI code generation with three key
components. First, Element and Layout-aware Token Compression preserves
essential UI information by detecting element regions and constructing UI
element trees. Second, Region-aware Token Refinement leverages attention scores
to discard low-attention tokens from selected regions while integrating
high-attention tokens from unselected regions. Third, Adaptive Duplicate Token
Suppression dynamically reduces repetitive generation by tracking HTML/CSS
structure frequencies and applying exponential penalties. Extensive experiments
show EfficientUICoderachieves a 55%-60% compression ratio without compromising
webpage quality and delivers superior efficiency improvements: reducing
computational cost by 44.9%, generated tokens by 41.4%, prefill time by 46.6%,
and inference time by 48.8% on 34B-level MLLMs. Code is available at
https://github.com/WebPAI/EfficientUICoder.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Jingyu Xiao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zhongyi Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yuxuan Wan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yintong Huo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yang Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Michael R. Lyu</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.12159v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2509.12159v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.SE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.SE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.12157v1</id>
    <updated>2025-09-15T17:22:22Z</updated>
    <published>2025-09-15T17:22:22Z</published>
    <title>Chandra Large Project Observations of the Supernova Remnant N132D:
  Measuring the Expansion of the Forward Shock</title>
    <summary>  We present results from the Chandra X-ray Observatory Large Project (878 ks
in 28 observations) of the Large Magellanic Cloud supernova remnant N132D. We
measure the expansion of the forward shock in the bright southern rim to be
$0.\!^{\prime\prime}10 \pm 0.\!^{\prime\prime}02$ over the $\sim14.5$ yr
baseline, which corresponds to a velocity of $1620\pm400~\mathrm{km\,s^{-1}}$
after accounting for several instrumental effects. We measure an expansion of
$0.\!^{\prime\prime}23 \pm 0.\!^{\prime\prime}02$ and a shock velocity of
$3840\pm260~\mathrm{km\,s^{-1}}$ for two features in an apparent blowout region
in the northeast. The emission-measure-weighted average temperature inferred
from X-ray spectral fits to regions in the southern rim is $0.95\pm0.17$ keV,
consistent with the electron temperature implied by the shock velocity after
accounting for Coulomb equilibration and adiabatic expansion. In contrast, the
emission-measure-weighted average temperature for the northeast region is
$0.77\pm0.04$ keV, which is significantly lower than the value inferred from
the shock velocity. We fit 1-D evolutionary models for the shock in the
southern rim and northeast region, using the measured radius and propagation
velocity into a constant density and power-law profile circumstellar medium. We
find good agreement with the age of $\sim2500$ years derived from optical
expansion measurements for explosion energies of $1.5-3.0 \times
10^{51}\,\mathrm{erg}$, ejecta masses of $2-6 \,\mathrm{M_{\odot}}$ and ambient
medium densities of $\sim0.33-0.66$ $\mathrm{amu~cm}^{-3}$ in the south and
$\sim0.01-0.02$ $\mathrm{amu~cm}^{-3}$ in the northeast assuming a constant
density medium. These results are consistent with previous studies that
suggested the progenitor of N132D was an energetic supernova that exploded into
a pre-existing cavity.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Xi Long</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Paul P. Plucinsky</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Terrance J. Gaetz</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Vinay L. Kashyap</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Aya Bamba</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>William P. Blair</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Daniel Castro</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Adam R. Foster</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Charles J. Law</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Milisavljevic</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Eric Miller</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Daniel J. Patnaude</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Manami Sasaki</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hidetoshi Sano</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Piyush Sharda</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Benjamin F. Williams</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Brian J. Williams</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hiroya Yamaguchi</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Accepted for publication in ApJ, 31 pages, 21 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2509.12157v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2509.12157v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="astro-ph.HE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.HE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
