<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Last updated: 2025-10-28T00:53:56Z -->
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3Dall%3Acausal%20inference%26id_list%3D%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=all:causal inference&amp;id_list=&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/SsRksLzRb0LuVhSmQ+N8WbAs+f8</id>
  <updated>2025-10-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">124567</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2510.21706v1</id>
    <updated>2025-10-24T17:59:46Z</updated>
    <published>2025-10-24T17:59:46Z</published>
    <title>Equivariance by Contrast: Identifiable Equivariant Embeddings from
  Unlabeled Finite Group Actions</title>
    <summary>  We propose Equivariance by Contrast (EbC) to learn equivariant embeddings
from observation pairs $(\mathbf{y}, g \cdot \mathbf{y})$, where $g$ is drawn
from a finite group acting on the data. Our method jointly learns a latent
space and a group representation in which group actions correspond to
invertible linear maps -- without relying on group-specific inductive biases.
We validate our approach on the infinite dSprites dataset with structured
transformations defined by the finite group $G:= (R_m \times \mathbb{Z}_n
\times \mathbb{Z}_n)$, combining discrete rotations and periodic translations.
The resulting embeddings exhibit high-fidelity equivariance, with group
operations faithfully reproduced in latent space. On synthetic data, we further
validate the approach on the non-abelian orthogonal group $O(n)$ and the
general linear group $GL(n)$. We also provide a theoretical proof for
identifiability. While broad evaluation across diverse group types on
real-world data remains future work, our results constitute the first
successful demonstration of general-purpose encoder-only equivariant learning
from group action observations alone, including non-trivial non-abelian groups
and a product group motivated by modeling affine equivariances in computer
vision.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Tobias Schmidt</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Steffen Schneider</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Matthias Bethge</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Accepted at NeurIPS 2025. The last two authors contributed equally.
  Code is available at https://github.com/dynamical-inference/ebc</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2510.21706v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2510.21706v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2510.21703v1</id>
    <updated>2025-10-24T17:59:01Z</updated>
    <published>2025-10-24T17:59:01Z</published>
    <title>An Hα Transit of HD 189733b to Assess Stellar Activity Across the
  Transit Chord Close to JWST Observations</title>
    <summary>  Transmission spectroscopy allows us to detect molecules in planetary
atmospheres, but is subject to contamination from inhomogeneities on the
stellar surface. Quantifying the extent of this contamination is essential for
accurate measurements of atmospheric composition, as stellar activity can
manifest as false atmospheric signals in planetary transmission spectra. We
present a study of hot Jupiter HD 189733b, which has over 50 hours of JWST
observations scheduled or taken, to measure the activity level of the host star
at the current epoch. We utilize high-resolution spectra of the H${\alpha}$
line from the MEGARA spectrograph on the 10-m GTC to examine the activity level
of HD 189733 during a transit. We measure H${\alpha}$ becoming shallower
mid-transit by an H${\alpha}$ index of ${\delta}$ = 0.00156 ${\pm}$ 0.00026,
which suggests that HD 189733b crosses an active region as it transits. We
posit this deviation is likely caused by a spot along the transit chord with an
approximate radius of $R_{spot}$ = 3.47 ${\pm}$ 0.30R${\oplus}$ becoming
occulted during transit. Including an approximation for unocculted spots, we
estimate that this spot could result in transit depth variations of ${\sim}$17
ppm at the 4.3 micron CO2 feature. Since this is comparable to JWST NIRCam
Grism mode's noise floor of ${\sim}$20 ppm, it could bias atmospheric studies
by altering the inferred depths of the planet's features. Thus, we suggest
ground-based high-resolution monitoring of activity indicator species
concurrently taken with JWST data when feasible to disentangle stellar activity
signals from planetary atmospheric signals during transit.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Kingsley E. Ehrich</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jason A. Dittmann</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Samuel P. Halverson</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alejandro Camazón-Pinilla</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:doi xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">10.3847/1538-3881/ae169b</arxiv:doi>
    <link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.3847/1538-3881/ae169b" rel="related"/>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">12 pages, 8 figures, accepted for publication in AJ</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2510.21703v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2510.21703v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="astro-ph.EP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.EP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.SR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2510.21686v1</id>
    <updated>2025-10-24T17:44:40Z</updated>
    <published>2025-10-24T17:44:40Z</published>
    <title>Multimodal Datasets with Controllable Mutual Information</title>
    <summary>  We introduce a framework for generating highly multimodal datasets with
explicitly calculable mutual information between modalities. This enables the
construction of benchmark datasets that provide a novel testbed for systematic
studies of mutual information estimators and multimodal self-supervised
learning techniques. Our framework constructs realistic datasets with known
mutual information using a flow-based generative model and a structured causal
framework for generating correlated latent variables.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Raheem Karim Hashmani</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Garrett W. Merz</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Helen Qu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mariel Pettee</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kyle Cranmer</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">15 pages, 4 figures, 1 table. Our code is publicly available at
  https://github.com/RKHashmani/MmMi-Datasets</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2510.21686v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2510.21686v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2510.21668v1</id>
    <updated>2025-10-24T17:24:24Z</updated>
    <published>2025-10-24T17:24:24Z</published>
    <title>Privacy Guarantee for Nash Equilibrium Computation of Aggregative Games
  Based on Pointwise Maximal Leakage</title>
    <summary>  Privacy preservation has served as a key metric in designing Nash equilibrium
(NE) computation algorithms. Although differential privacy (DP) has been widely
employed for privacy guarantees, it does not exploit prior distributional
knowledge of datasets and is ineffective in assessing information leakage for
correlated datasets. To address these concerns, we establish a pointwise
maximal leakage (PML) framework when computing NE in aggregative games. By
incorporating prior knowledge of players' cost function datasets, we obtain a
precise and computable upper bound of privacy leakage with PML guarantees. In
the entire view, we show PML refines DP by offering a tighter privacy
guarantee, enabling flexibility in designing NE computation. Also, in the
individual view, we reveal that the lower bound of PML can exceed the upper
bound of DP by constructing specific correlated datasets. The results emphasize
that PML is a more proper privacy measure than DP since the latter fails to
adequately capture privacy leakage in correlated datasets. Moreover, we conduct
experiments with adversaries who attempt to infer players' private information
to illustrate the effectiveness of our framework.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Zhaoyang Cheng</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Guanpu Chen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tobias J. Oechtering</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mikael Skoglund</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2510.21668v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2510.21668v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.GT" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.GT" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.IT" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.IT" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2510.21661v1</id>
    <updated>2025-10-24T17:15:24Z</updated>
    <published>2025-10-24T17:15:24Z</published>
    <title>MECfda: An R Package for Bias Correction Due to Measurement Error in
  Functional and Scalar Covariates in Scalar-on-Function Regression Models</title>
    <summary>  Functional data analysis (FDA) deals with high-resolution data recorded over
a continuum, such as time, space or frequency. Device-based assessments of
physical activity or sleep are objective yet still prone to measurement error.
We present MECfda, an R package that (i) fits scalar-on-function, generalized
scalar-on-function, and functional quantile regression models, and (ii)
provides bias-corrected estimation when functional covariates are measured with
error. By unifying these tools under a consistent syntax, MECfda enables robust
inference for FDA applications that involve noisy functional data.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Heyang Ji</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Carmen Tekwe</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2510.21661v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2510.21661v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="stat.ME" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ME" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2510.21659v1</id>
    <updated>2025-10-24T17:14:12Z</updated>
    <published>2025-10-24T17:14:12Z</published>
    <title>Smule Renaissance Small: Efficient General-Purpose Vocal Restoration</title>
    <summary>  Vocal recordings on consumer devices commonly suffer from multiple concurrent
degradations: noise, reverberation, band-limiting, and clipping. We present
Smule Renaissance Small (SRS), a compact single-stage model that performs
end-to-end vocal restoration directly in the complex STFT domain. By
incorporating phase-aware losses, SRS enables large analysis windows for
improved frequency resolution while achieving 10.5x real-time inference on
iPhone 12 CPU at 48 kHz. On the DNS 5 Challenge blind set, despite no speech
training, SRS outperforms a strong GAN baseline and closely matches a
computationally expensive flow-matching system. To enable evaluation under
realistic multi-degradation scenarios, we introduce the Extreme Degradation
Bench (EDB): 87 singing and speech recordings captured under severe acoustic
conditions. On EDB, SRS surpasses all open-source baselines on singing and
matches commercial systems, while remaining competitive on speech despite no
speech-specific training. We release both SRS and EDB under the MIT License.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Yongyi Zang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Manchester</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>David Young</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ivan Ivanov</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jeffrey Lufkin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Martin Vladimirov</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>PJ Solomon</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Svetoslav Kepchelev</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Fei Yueh Chen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Dongting Cai</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Teodor Naydenov</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Randal Leistikow</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Technical Report</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2510.21659v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2510.21659v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.SD" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.SD" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2510.21651v1</id>
    <updated>2025-10-24T17:10:10Z</updated>
    <published>2025-10-24T17:10:10Z</published>
    <title>Foundations of Carrollian Geometry</title>
    <summary>  Carrollian physics provides the natural framework for describing null
hypersurfaces. This review explores the geometry of Carrollian manifolds --
spaces endowed with a degenerate metric. We begin with an algebraic overview of
the Carroll group, its conformal extension, and its relation to the BMS group.
Then, in the core of the review, we follow the standard pseudo-Riemannian
narrative: metric $\to$ connection $\to$ curvature. We first introduce the
modern, general definition of a Carrollian structure, the analogue of the
metric on such manifolds, reviewing the historical developments, symmetries,
and link with the algebraic groups. The second part concerns connections. We
show the breakdown of the Levi-Civita theorem in the Carrollian setting and
construct the most general intrinsic Carrollian connection. A preferred
connection is then identified intrinsically and later shown to coincide with
the one induced by embedding a null hypersurface in an ambient spacetime. The
third part develops the associated curvature tensors. We include novel results
presented here for the first time.
  Two advanced topics highlight the broader scope of this framework. The first
treats null hypersurfaces via the rigging technique, deriving the induced
geometry from the ambient space. This provides a unified language for
spacelike, timelike, and null hypersurfaces, and shows that the induced rigged
connection exactly reproduces the intrinsic Carrollian one. From this, the
Gauss and Codazzi-Mainardi equations follow, and the Einstein equations emerge
as conservation laws for the null Brown-York stress tensor. The second topic
extends the Carrollian setup to generic, non-null hypersurfaces, enabling a
smooth null limit and completing the unified geometric description of
hypersurfaces of all causal characters.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Luca Ciambelli</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Puttarak Jai-akson</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Review prepared for Physics Reports</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2510.21651v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2510.21651v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="hep-th" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="hep-th" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="gr-qc" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2510.21632v1</id>
    <updated>2025-10-24T16:37:07Z</updated>
    <published>2025-10-24T16:37:07Z</published>
    <title>Exploring the statistical properties of double radio relics in the
  TNG-Cluster and TNG300 simulations</title>
    <summary>  Double radio relics, pairs of diffuse radio features located on opposite
sides of merging galaxy clusters, are a rare subclass of radio relics that are
believed to trace merger shocks and provide valuable constraints on plasma
acceleration models and merger history. With the number of known double relics
growing in recent and upcoming radio surveys, statistical analyses of their
properties are becoming feasible. In this study, we utilize the cosmological
magnetohydrodynamics zoom-in simulations TNG-Cluster, in combination with
TNG300-1, to examine the statistical properties of double radio relics. The
simulated double relic pairs exhibit a wide range of luminosity ratios, broadly
consistent with the observations. We find that the two relics in a given double
system often differ significantly in their shock properties and magnetic field
strengths. This diversity implies that the observed brightness asymmetry in the
pair cannot be explained by a single factor alone, but instead reflects an
interplay of multiple physical parameters. Nevertheless, double radio relics
tend to align with the collision axis within $\sim30^{\circ}$ and their
separation ($d_{\rm drr}$) correlates tightly with the time since collision
(TSC) as ${\rm TSC~[Gyr]} = 0.52 d_{\rm drr}/R_{500\rm c} - 0.24$, allowing it
to be inferred with an accuracy of $\sim0.2~\rm Gyr$. With the statistical
samples of simulated radio relics, we predict that low-mass clusters will
constitute the dominant population of double radio relic systems detected with
upcoming surveys such as SKA. These results demonstrate that double radio
relics can serve as robust probes of merger dynamics and plasma acceleration,
and that simulations provide critical guidance for interpreting the large
samples expected from next-generation radio surveys.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Wonki Lee</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Annalisa Pillepich</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Dylan Nelson</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Myungkook James Jee</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Daisuke Nagai</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kyle Finner</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>John ZuHone</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">22 pages, 16 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2510.21632v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2510.21632v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2510.21608v1</id>
    <updated>2025-10-24T16:14:31Z</updated>
    <published>2025-10-24T16:14:31Z</published>
    <title>Generalised Flow Maps for Few-Step Generative Modelling on Riemannian
  Manifolds</title>
    <summary>  Geometric data and purpose-built generative models on them have become
ubiquitous in high-impact deep learning application domains, ranging from
protein backbone generation and computational chemistry to geospatial data.
Current geometric generative models remain computationally expensive at
inference -- requiring many steps of complex numerical simulation -- as they
are derived from dynamical measure transport frameworks such as diffusion and
flow-matching on Riemannian manifolds. In this paper, we propose Generalised
Flow Maps (GFM), a new class of few-step generative models that generalises the
Flow Map framework in Euclidean spaces to arbitrary Riemannian manifolds. We
instantiate GFMs with three self-distillation-based training methods:
Generalised Lagrangian Flow Maps, Generalised Eulerian Flow Maps, and
Generalised Progressive Flow Maps. We theoretically show that GFMs, under
specific design decisions, unify and elevate existing Euclidean few-step
generative models, such as consistency models, shortcut models, and meanflows,
to the Riemannian setting. We benchmark GFMs against other geometric generative
models on a suite of geometric datasets, including geospatial data, RNA torsion
angles, and hyperbolic manifolds, and achieve state-of-the-art sample quality
for single- and few-step evaluations, and superior or competitive
log-likelihoods using the implicit probability flow.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Oscar Davis</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Michael S. Albergo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Nicholas M. Boffi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Michael M. Bronstein</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Avishek Joey Bose</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Under review</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2510.21608v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2510.21608v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2510.21604v1</id>
    <updated>2025-10-24T16:08:33Z</updated>
    <published>2025-10-24T16:08:33Z</published>
    <title>RETuning: Upgrading Inference-Time Scaling for Stock Movement Prediction
  with Large Language Models</title>
    <summary>  Recently, large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated outstanding
reasoning capabilities on mathematical and coding tasks. However, their
application to financial tasks-especially the most fundamental task of stock
movement prediction-remains underexplored. We study a three-class
classification problem (up, hold, down) and, by analyzing existing reasoning
responses, observe that: (1) LLMs follow analysts' opinions rather than exhibit
a systematic, independent analytical logic (CoTs). (2) LLMs list summaries from
different sources without weighing adversarial evidence, yet such
counterevidence is crucial for reliable prediction. It shows that the model
does not make good use of its reasoning ability to complete the task. To
address this, we propose Reflective Evidence Tuning (RETuning), a cold-start
method prior to reinforcement learning, to enhance prediction ability. While
generating CoT, RETuning encourages dynamically constructing an analytical
framework from diverse information sources, organizing and scoring evidence for
price up or down based on that framework-rather than on contextual
viewpoints-and finally reflecting to derive the prediction. This approach
maximally aligns the model with its learned analytical framework, ensuring
independent logical reasoning and reducing undue influence from context. We
also build a large-scale dataset spanning all of 2024 for 5,123 A-share stocks,
with long contexts (32K tokens) and over 200K samples. In addition to price and
news, it incorporates analysts' opinions, quantitative reports, fundamental
data, macroeconomic indicators, and similar stocks. Experiments show that
RETuning successfully unlocks the model's reasoning ability in the financial
domain. Inference-time scaling still works even after 6 months or on
out-of-distribution stocks, since the models gain valuable insights about stock
movement prediction.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Xueyuan Lin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Cehao Yang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ye Ma</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ming Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Rongjunchen Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yang Ni</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xiaojun Wu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Chengjin Xu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jian Guo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hui Xiong</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2510.21604v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2510.21604v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
