<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Last updated: 2026-02-06T01:11:34Z -->
<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>https://arxiv.org/api/p6EyKyP4fMY/66n9Ev8E79F7KlI</id>
  <title>arXiv Query: search_query=all:causal OR all:inference&amp;id_list=&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <updated>2026-02-06T01:11:34Z</updated>
  <link href="https://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query=all:causal+OR+all:inference&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10&amp;id_list=" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage>10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <opensearch:totalResults>133043</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex>0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04864v1</id>
    <title>When LLaVA Meets Objects: Token Composition for Vision-Language-Models</title>
    <updated>2026-02-04T18:50:46Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04864v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2602.04864v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Current autoregressive Vision Language Models (VLMs) usually rely on a large number of visual tokens to represent images, resulting in a need for more compute especially at inference time. To address this problem, we propose Mask-LLaVA, a framework that leverages different levels of visual features to create a compact yet information-rich visual representation for autoregressive VLMs. Namely, we combine mask-based object representations together with global tokens and local patch tokens. While all tokens are used during training, it shows that the resulting model can flexibly drop especially the number of mask-based object-tokens at test time, allowing to adapt the number of tokens during inference without the need to retrain the model and without a significant drop in performance. We evaluate the proposed approach on a suite of standard benchmarks showing results competitive to current token efficient methods and comparable to the original LLaVA baseline using only a fraction of visual tokens. Our analysis demonstrates that combining multi-level features enables efficient learning with fewer tokens while allowing dynamic token selection at test time for good performance.</summary>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-02-04T18:50:46Z</published>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="cs.CV"/>
    <author>
      <name>Soumya Jahagirdar</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Walid Bousselham</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Anna Kukleva</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hilde Kuehne</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04855v1</id>
    <title>Marginal Likelihood Inference for Fitting Dynamical Survival Analysis Models to Epidemic Count Data</title>
    <updated>2026-02-04T18:42:39Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04855v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2602.04855v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Stochastic compartmental models are prevalent tools for describing disease spread, but inference under these models is challenging for many types of surveillance data when the marginal likelihood function becomes intractable due to missing information. To address this, we develop a closed-form likelihood for discretely observed incidence count data under the dynamical survival analysis (DSA) paradigm. The method approximates the stochastic population-level hazard by a large population limit while retaining a count-valued stochastic model, and leads to survival analytic inferential strategies that are both computationally efficient and flexible to model generalizations. Through simulation, we show that parameter estimation is competitive with recent exact but computationally expensive likelihood-based methods in partially observed settings. Previous work has shown that the DSA approximation is generalizable, and we show that the inferential developments here also carry over to models featuring individual heterogeneity, such as frailty models. We consider case studies of both Ebola and COVID-19 data on variants of the model, including a network-based epidemic model and a model with distributions over susceptibility, demonstrating its flexibility and practical utility on real, partially observed datasets.</summary>
    <category term="stat.ME" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-02-04T18:42:39Z</published>
    <arxiv:comment>25 pages, 2 figures and 6 tables</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="stat.ME"/>
    <author>
      <name>Suchismita Roy</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alexander A. Fisher</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jason Xu</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04843v1</id>
    <title>Fluid Representations in Reasoning Models</title>
    <updated>2026-02-04T18:34:50Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04843v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2602.04843v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Reasoning language models, which generate long chains of thought, dramatically outperform non-reasoning language models on abstract problems. However, the internal model mechanisms that allow this superior performance remain poorly understood. We present a mechanistic analysis of how QwQ-32B - a model specifically trained to produce extensive reasoning traces - process abstract structural information. On Mystery Blocksworld - a semantically obfuscated planning domain - we find that QwQ-32B gradually improves its internal representation of actions and concepts during reasoning. The model develops abstract encodings that focus on structure rather than specific action names. Through steering experiments, we establish causal evidence that these adaptations improve problem solving: injecting refined representations from successful traces boosts accuracy, while symbolic representations can replace many obfuscated encodings with minimal performance loss. We find that one of the factors driving reasoning model performance is in-context refinement of token representations, which we dub Fluid Reasoning Representations.</summary>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-02-04T18:34:50Z</published>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="cs.AI"/>
    <author>
      <name>Dmitrii Kharlapenko</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alessandro Stolfo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Arthur Conmy</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mrinmaya Sachan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zhijing Jin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04821v1</id>
    <title>Safe Urban Traffic Control via Uncertainty-Aware Conformal Prediction and World-Model Reinforcement Learning</title>
    <updated>2026-02-04T18:10:59Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04821v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2602.04821v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Urban traffic management demands systems that simultaneously predict future conditions, detect anomalies, and take safe corrective actions -- all while providing reliability guarantees. We present STREAM-RL, a unified framework that introduces three novel algorithmic contributions: (1) PU-GAT+, an Uncertainty-Guided Adaptive Conformal Forecaster that uses prediction uncertainty to dynamically reweight graph attention via confidence-monotonic attention, achieving distribution-free coverage guarantees; (2) CRFN-BY, a Conformal Residual Flow Network that models uncertainty-normalized residuals via normalizing flows with Benjamini-Yekutieli FDR control under arbitrary dependence; and (3) LyCon-WRL+, an Uncertainty-Guided Safe World-Model RL agent with Lyapunov stability certificates, certified Lipschitz bounds, and uncertainty-propagated imagination rollouts. To our knowledge, this is the first framework to propagate calibrated uncertainty from forecasting through anomaly detection to safe policy learning with end-to-end theoretical guarantees. Experiments on multiple real-world traffic trajectory data demonstrate that STREAM-RL achieves 91.4\% coverage efficiency, controls FDR at 4.1\% under verified dependence, and improves safety rate to 95.2\% compared to 69\% for standard PPO while achieving higher reward, with 23ms end-to-end inference latency.</summary>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-02-04T18:10:59Z</published>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="cs.LG"/>
    <author>
      <name>Joydeep Chandra</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Satyam Kumar Navneet</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Aleksandr Algazinov</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yong Zhang</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04820v1</id>
    <title>Toward Reliable and Explainable Nail Disease Classification: Leveraging Adversarial Training and Grad-CAM Visualization</title>
    <updated>2026-02-04T18:08:13Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04820v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2602.04820v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Human nail diseases are gradually observed over all age groups, especially among older individuals, often going ignored until they become severe. Early detection and accurate diagnosis of such conditions are important because they sometimes reveal our body's health problems. But it is challenging due to the inferred visual differences between disease types. This paper presents a machine learning-based model for automated classification of nail diseases based on a publicly available dataset, which contains 3,835 images scaling six categories. In 224x224 pixels, all images were resized to ensure consistency. To evaluate performance, four well-known CNN models-InceptionV3, DenseNet201, EfficientNetV2, and ResNet50 were trained and analyzed. Among these, InceptionV3 outperformed the others with an accuracy of 95.57%, while DenseNet201 came next with 94.79%. To make the model stronger and less likely to make mistakes on tricky or noisy images, we used adversarial training. To help understand how the model makes decisions, we used SHAP to highlight important features in the predictions. This system could be a helpful support for doctors, making nail disease diagnosis more accurate and faster.</summary>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-02-04T18:08:13Z</published>
    <arxiv:comment>6 pages, 12 figures. This is the author's accepted manuscript of a paper accepted for publication in the Proceedings of the 16th International IEEE Conference on Computing, Communication and Networking Technologies (ICCCNT 2025). The final published version will be available via IEEE Xplore</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="cs.CV"/>
    <author>
      <name>Farzia Hossain</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Samanta Ghosh</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Shahida Begum</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>B. M. Shahria Alam</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mohammad Tahmid Noor</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Md Parvez Mia</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Nishat Tasnim Niloy</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04798v1</id>
    <title>Score-Based Change-Point Detection and Region Localization for Spatio-Temporal Point Processes</title>
    <updated>2026-02-04T17:44:41Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04798v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2602.04798v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>We study sequential change-point detection for spatio-temporal point processes, where actionable detection requires not only identifying when a distributional change occurs but also localizing where it manifests in space. While classical quickest change detection methods provide strong guarantees on detection delay and false-alarm rates, existing approaches for point-process data predominantly focus on temporal changes and do not explicitly infer affected spatial regions. We propose a likelihood-free, score-based detection framework that jointly estimates the change time and the change region in continuous space-time without assuming parametric knowledge of the pre- or post-change dynamics. The method leverages a localized and conditionally weighted Hyvärinen score to quantify event-level deviations from nominal behavior and aggregates these scores using a spatio-temporal CUSUM-type statistic over a prescribed class of spatial regions. Operating sequentially, the procedure outputs both a stopping time and an estimated change region, enabling real-time detection with spatial interpretability. We establish theoretical guarantees on false-alarm control, detection delay, and spatial localization accuracy, and demonstrate the effectiveness of the proposed approach through simulations and real-world spatio-temporal event data.</summary>
    <category term="stat.ME" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-02-04T17:44:41Z</published>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="stat.ME"/>
    <author>
      <name>Wenbin Zhou</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Liyan Xie</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Shixiang Zhu</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04794v1</id>
    <title>A Hierarchical Bayesian Analysis of Neutron-Skin Thicknesses and Implications for the Symmetry-Energy Slope</title>
    <updated>2026-02-04T17:43:02Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04794v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2602.04794v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Neutron-skin thicknesses provide a sensitive probe of the isovector sector of the nuclear equation of state and its density dependence, commonly characterized by the symmetry-energy slope parameter L. A wide variety of experimental and observational methods have been used to extract neutron skins, ranging from hadronic and electromagnetic probes of finite nuclei to inferences from neutron-star observations. Each approach carries distinct theoretical and systematic uncertainties, complicating global interpretations and obscuring genuine physical trends. In this work we present a hierarchical Bayesian framework for the statistically consistent synthesis of heterogeneous neutron-skin constraints. The neutron-skin thickness is modeled as a smooth latent function of isospin asymmetry and nuclear size, while method-dependent bias parameters and intrinsic nuisance widths are introduced to account for unmodeled experimental and theoretical systematics. Focusing on the tin isotopes, we infer probabilistic neutron-skin trends from 100Sn to 140Sn, finding minimal uncertainties near stability and increasing uncertainties toward the proton-rich and neutron-rich extremes. We assess the consistency of nuclear energy-density functionals and obtain conditional constraints on the symmetry-energy parameters. The resulting posterior exhibits a pronounced compression of the symmetry-energy slope parameter L, reflecting the dominant sensitivity of neutron skins to sub-saturation symmetry pressure. We demonstrate that our hierarchical Bayesian framework provides robust and transparent constraints on the sub-saturation isovector sector of the nuclear equation of state.</summary>
    <category term="nucl-th" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-02-04T17:43:02Z</published>
    <arxiv:comment>10 pages, 4 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="nucl-th"/>
    <author>
      <name>A. Azizi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>C. A. Bertulani</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>C. Davila</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04770v1</id>
    <title>Generative Modeling via Drifting</title>
    <updated>2026-02-04T17:06:49Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04770v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2602.04770v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Generative modeling can be formulated as learning a mapping f such that its pushforward distribution matches the data distribution. The pushforward behavior can be carried out iteratively at inference time, for example in diffusion and flow-based models. In this paper, we propose a new paradigm called Drifting Models, which evolve the pushforward distribution during training and naturally admit one-step inference. We introduce a drifting field that governs the sample movement and achieves equilibrium when the distributions match. This leads to a training objective that allows the neural network optimizer to evolve the distribution. In experiments, our one-step generator achieves state-of-the-art results on ImageNet at 256 x 256 resolution, with an FID of 1.54 in latent space and 1.61 in pixel space. We hope that our work opens up new opportunities for high-quality one-step generation.</summary>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-02-04T17:06:49Z</published>
    <arxiv:comment>Project page: https://lambertae.github.io/projects/drifting/</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="cs.LG"/>
    <author>
      <name>Mingyang Deng</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>He Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tianhong Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yilun Du</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kaiming He</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04769v1</id>
    <title>NeuroCanvas: VLLM-Powered Robust Seizure Detection by Reformulating Multichannel EEG as Image</title>
    <updated>2026-02-04T17:06:38Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04769v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2602.04769v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Accurate and timely seizure detection from Electroencephalography (EEG) is critical for clinical intervention, yet manual review of long-term recordings is labor-intensive. Recent efforts to encode EEG signals into large language models (LLMs) show promise in handling neural signals across diverse patients, but two significant challenges remain: (1) multi-channel heterogeneity, as seizure-relevant information varies substantially across EEG channels, and (2) computing inefficiency, as the EEG signals need to be encoded into a massive number of tokens for the prediction. To address these issues, we draw the EEG signal and propose the novel NeuroCanvas framework. Specifically, NeuroCanvas consists of two modules: (i) The Entropy-guided Channel Selector (ECS) selects the seizure-relevant channels input to LLM and (ii) the following Canvas of Neuron Signal (CNS) converts selected multi-channel heterogeneous EEG signals into structured visual representations. The ECS module alleviates the multi-channel heterogeneity issue, and the CNS uses compact visual tokens to represent the EEG signals that improve the computing efficiency. We evaluate NeuroCanvas across multiple seizure detection datasets, demonstrating a significant improvement of $20\%$ in F1 score and reductions of $88\%$ in inference latency. These results highlight NeuroCanvas as a scalable and effective solution for real-time and resource-efficient seizure detection in clinical practice.The code will be released at https://github.com/Yanchen30247/seizure_detect.</summary>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-02-04T17:06:38Z</published>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="cs.LG"/>
    <author>
      <name>Yan Chen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jie Peng</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Moajjem Hossain Chowdhury</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tianlong Chen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yunmei Liu</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04766v1</id>
    <title>Measurement of the Hubble constant using the Dark Energy Survey Year 6 Gold galaxy catalog and the fourth Gravitational-Wave Transient Catalog</title>
    <updated>2026-02-04T17:02:33Z</updated>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04766v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2602.04766v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" title="pdf"/>
    <summary>Gravitational wave standard sirens enable independent measurements of the Hubble constant $H_0$. In the absence of electromagnetic counterparts, the "dark siren" method statistically correlates GW events with potential host galaxies. We present a measurement of $H_0$ using 142 compact binary coalescences from the fourth Gravitational-Wave Transient Catalog (GWTC-4.0) combined with the Dark Energy Survey Year 6 Gold photometric galaxy catalog. Using the gwcosmo pipeline, we jointly infer cosmological and GW population parameters. We analyze the impact of galaxy catalog properties on the inference, identifying significant features in the galaxy redshift distribution which can introduce biases. By restricting the galaxy catalog to $0.05&lt;z&lt;0.35$ to maintain consistency with a uniform in comoving volume galaxy distribution, we obtain a result of $H_0 = 70.9^{+22.3}_{-18.6}\;\text{km}\;\text{s}^{-1}\;\text{Mpc}^{-1}$ from dark sirens and $H_0=73.1^{+11.7}_{-8.6}\;\text{km}\;\text{s}^{-1}\;\text{Mpc}^{-1}$ when combined with the bright siren GW170817. This study demonstrates the adaptation of deep galaxy catalogs for GW cosmology, highlighting key challenges and methodologies essential for maximizing the potential of next-generation galaxy surveys.</summary>
    <category term="astro-ph.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <published>2026-02-04T17:02:33Z</published>
    <arxiv:primary_category term="astro-ph.CO"/>
    <author>
      <name>Isaac McMahon</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Danny Laghi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Marcelle Soares-Santos</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kendall Ackley</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Gergely Dálya</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yavuz Gençel</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>David Sánchez-Cid</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Felipe Andrade-Oliveira</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sean MacBride</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Christian Chapman-Bird</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Rachel Gray</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alexander Papadopoulos</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
