<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Last updated: 2025-09-02T00:54:42Z -->
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3Dall%3Acausal%20inference%26id_list%3D%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=all:causal inference&amp;id_list=&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/SsRksLzRb0LuVhSmQ+N8WbAs+f8</id>
  <updated>2025-09-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">119950</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.21818v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-29T17:52:48Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-29T17:52:48Z</published>
    <title>First constraints on the local ionization topology in front of two
  quasars at z ~ 7.5</title>
    <summary>  Thus far, Lyman-$\alpha$ damping wings towards quasars have been used to
probe the \textit{global} ionization state of the foreground intergalactic
medium (IGM). A new parameterization has demonstrated that the damping wing
signature also carries \textit{local} information about the distribution of
neutral hydrogen (HI) in front of the quasar before it started shining.
Leveraging a recently introduced Bayesian \texttt{JAX}-based Hamiltonian Monte
Carlo (HMC) inference framework, we derive constraints on the
Lorentzian-weighted HI column density $N_\mathrm{HI}^\mathrm{DW}$, the quasar's
distance $r_\mathrm{patch}$ to the first neutral patch and its lifetime
$t_\mathrm{Q}$ based on JWST/NIRSpec spectra of the two $z \sim 7.5$ quasars
J1007+2115 and J1342+0928. After folding in model-dependent topology
information, we find that J1007+2115 (and J1342+0928) is most likely to reside
in a $\langle x_\mathrm{HI} \rangle = 0.32_{-0.20}^{+0.22}$
($0.58_{-0.23}^{+0.23}$) neutral IGM while shining for a remarkably short
lifetime of $\log_{10} t_\mathrm{Q} /\mathrm{yr} = 4.14_{-0.18}^{+0.74}$ (an
intermediate lifetime of $5.64_{-0.43}^{+0.25}$) along a sightline with
$\log_{10} N_\mathrm{HI}^\mathrm{DW} /\mathrm{cm}^{-2} = 19.70_{-0.86}^{+0.35}$
($20.24_{-0.22}^{+0.25}$) and $r_\mathrm{patch} = 28.9_{-14.4}^{+54.0}
\,\mathrm{cMpc}$ ($10.9_{-5.9}^{+5.6} \,\mathrm{cMpc}$). In light of the
potential presence of local absorbers in the foreground of J1342+0928 as has
been recently suggested, we also demonstrate how the Lorentzian-weighted column
density $N_\mathrm{HI}^\mathrm{DW}$ provides a natural means for quantifying
their contribution to the observed damping wing signal.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Timo Kist</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Joseph F. Hennawi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Frederick B. Davies</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Eduardo Bañados</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sarah E. I. Bosman</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zheng Cai</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Anna-Christina Eilers</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xiaohui Fan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zoltán Haiman</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hyunsung D. Jun</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yichen Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jinyi Yang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Feige Wang</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">submitted to MNRAS</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.21818v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.21818v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="astro-ph.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.21812v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-29T17:50:37Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-29T17:50:37Z</published>
    <title>Inferring local quasar IGM damping wing constraints</title>
    <summary>  Lyman-$\alpha$ damping wings towards quasars are a highly sensitive probe of
the neutral hydrogen (HI) content in the foreground intergalactic medium (IGM),
not only constraining the global timing of reionization but also the
\textit{local} ionization topology near the quasar. Near-optimal extraction of
this information is possible with the help of two recently introduced
reionization model-independent summary statistics of the HI distribution in the
IGM \textit{before} the quasar started shining, complemented with the quasar's
lifetime encoding the effect of its ionizing radiation as a third parameter. We
introduce a fully Bayesian JAX-based Hamiltonian Monte Carlo (HMC) inference
framework that allows us to jointly reconstruct the quasar's unknown continuum
and constrain these local damping wing statistics. We put forward a
probabilistic framework that allows us to tie these local constraints to any
specific reionization model and obtain model-dependent constraints on the
global timing of reionization. We demonstrate that we are able to constrain the
(Lorentzian-weighted) HI column density in front of the quasar to a precision
of $0.69_{-0.30}^{+0.06}\,\mathrm{dex}$ and its original distance to the first
neutral patch before the quasar started shining to
$31.4_{-28.1}^{+10.7}\,\mathrm{cMpc}$ (if a noticeable damping wing is present
in the spectrum), extracting hitherto unused local information from the IGM
damping wing imprint. Once tied to a specific reionization model, we find that
the statistical fidelity of our constraints on the global IGM neutral fraction
and the lifetime of the quasar improves, while retaining the same precision as
achieved by pipelines that infer these parameters directly.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Timo Kist</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Joseph F. Hennawi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Frederick B. Davies</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">submitted to MNRAS</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.21812v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.21812v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="astro-ph.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.21804v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-29T17:32:47Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-29T17:32:47Z</published>
    <title>Considerations for Estimating Causal Effects of Informatively Timed
  Treatments</title>
    <summary>  Epidemiological studies are often concerned with estimating causal effects of
a sequence of treatment decisions on survival outcomes. In many settings,
treatment decisions do not occur at fixed, pre-specified followup times.
Rather, timing varies across subjects in ways that may be informative of
subsequent treatment decisions and potential outcomes. Awareness of the issue
and its potential solutions is lacking in the literature, which motivate this
work. Here, we formalize the issue of informative timing, problems associated
with ignoring it, and show how g-methods can be used to analyze sequential
treatments that are informatively timed. As we describe, in such settings, the
waiting times between successive treatment decisions may be properly viewed as
a time-varying confounders. Using synthetic examples, we illustrate how
g-methods that do not adjust for these waiting times may be biased and how
adjustment can be done in scenarios where patients may die or be censored in
between treatments. We draw connections between adjustment and identification
with discrete-time versus continuous-time models. Finally, we provide
implementation guidance and examples using publicly available software. Our
concluding message is that 1) considering timing is important for valid
inference and 2) correcting for informative timing can be done with g-methods
that adjust for waiting times between treatments as time-varying confounders.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Arman Oganisian</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.21804v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.21804v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="stat.ME" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ME" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.21802v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-29T17:31:14Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-29T17:31:14Z</published>
    <title>An Adaptive Real-Time Forecasting Framework for Cryogenic Fluid
  Management in Space Systems</title>
    <summary>  Accurate real-time forecasting of cryogenic tank behavior is essential for
the safe and efficient operation of propulsion and storage systems in future
deep-space missions. While cryogenic fluid management (CFM) systems
increasingly require autonomous capabilities, conventional simulation methods
remain hindered by high computational cost, model imperfections, and
sensitivity to unanticipated boundary condition changes. To address these
limitations, this study proposes an Adaptive Real-Time Forecasting Framework
for Cryogenic Propellant Management in Space Systems, featuring a lightweight,
non-intrusive method named ARCTIC (Adaptive Real-time Cryogenic Tank Inference
and Correction). ARCTIC integrates real-time sensor data with precomputed nodal
simulations through a data-driven correction layer that dynamically refines
forecast accuracy without modifying the underlying model. Two updating
mechanisms, auto-calibration and observation and correction, enable continuous
adaptation to evolving system states and transient disturbances. The method is
first assessed through synthetic scenarios representing self-pressurization,
sloshing, and periodic operations, then validated using experimental data from
NASA's Multipurpose Hydrogen Test Bed and K-Site facilities. Results
demonstrate that ARCTIC significantly improves forecast accuracy under model
imperfections, data noise, and boundary fluctuations, offering a robust
real-time forecasting capability to support autonomous CFM operations. The
framework's compatibility with existing simulation tools and its low
computational overhead make it especially suited for onboard implementation in
space systems requiring predictive autonomy.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Qiyun Cheng</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Huihua Yang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Wei Ji</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.21802v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.21802v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="physics.flu-dyn" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.flu-dyn" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.21801v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-29T17:28:07Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-29T17:28:07Z</published>
    <title>DMGIN: How Multimodal LLMs Enhance Large Recommendation Models for
  Lifelong User Post-click Behaviors</title>
    <summary>  Modeling user interest based on lifelong user behavior sequences is crucial
for enhancing Click-Through Rate (CTR) prediction. However, long post-click
behavior sequences themselves pose severe performance issues: the sheer volume
of data leads to high computational costs and inefficiencies in model training
and inference. Traditional methods address this by introducing two-stage
approaches, but this compromises model effectiveness due to incomplete
utilization of the full sequence context. More importantly, integrating
multimodal embeddings into existing large recommendation models (LRM) presents
significant challenges: These embeddings often exacerbate computational burdens
and mismatch with LRM architectures. To address these issues and enhance the
model's efficiency and accuracy, we introduce Deep Multimodal Group Interest
Network (DMGIN). Given the observation that user post-click behavior sequences
contain a large number of repeated items with varying behaviors and timestamps,
DMGIN employs Multimodal LLMs(MLLM) for grouping to reorganize complete
lifelong post-click behavior sequences more effectively, with almost no
additional computational overhead, as opposed to directly introducing
multimodal embeddings. To mitigate the potential information loss from
grouping, we have implemented two key strategies. First, we analyze behaviors
within each group using both interest statistics and intra-group transformers
to capture group traits. Second, apply inter-group transformers to temporally
ordered groups to capture the evolution of user group interests. Our extensive
experiments on both industrial and public datasets confirm the effectiveness
and efficiency of DMGIN. The A/B test in our LBS advertising system shows that
DMGIN improves CTR by 4.7% and Revenue per Mile by 2.3%.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Zhuoxing Wei</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Qingchen Xie</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Qi Liu</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">8 pages, 5 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.21801v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.21801v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.IR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.IR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.21755v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-29T16:30:16Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-29T16:30:16Z</published>
    <title>Analysis of Semantic Communication for Logic-based Hypothesis Deduction</title>
    <summary>  This work presents an analysis of semantic communication in the context of
First-Order Logic (FOL)-based deduction. Specifically, the receiver holds a set
of hypotheses about the State of the World (SotW), while the transmitter has
incomplete evidence about the true SotW but lacks access to the ground truth.
The transmitter aims to communicate limited information to help the receiver
identify the hypothesis most consistent with true SotW. We formulate the
objective as approximating the posterior distribution at the transmitter to the
receiver. Using Stirling's approximation, this reduces to a constrained,
finite-horizon resource allocation problem. Applying the Karush-Kuhn-Tucker
conditions yields a truncated water-filling solution. Despite the problem's
non-convexity, symmetry and permutation invariance ensure global optimality.
Based on this, we design message selection strategies, both for single- and
multi-round communication, and model the receiver's inference as an m-ary
Bayesian hypothesis testing problem. Under the Maximum A Posteriori (MAP) rule,
our communication strategy achieves optimal performance within budget
constraints. We further analyze convergence rates and validate the theoretical
findings through experiments, demonstrating reduced error over random selection
and prior methods.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ahmet Faruk Saz</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Siheng Xiong</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Faramarz Fekri</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Accepted to 2025 IEEE Global Communications Conference</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.21755v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.21755v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.IT" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.IT" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.IT" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.21748v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-29T16:20:50Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-29T16:20:50Z</published>
    <title>A direct black hole mass measurement in a Little Red Dot at the Epoch of
  Reionization</title>
    <summary>  Recent discoveries of faint active galactic nuclei (AGN) at the redshift
frontier have revealed a plethora of broad \Halpha emitters with optically red
continua, named Little Red Dots (LRDs), which comprise 15-30\% of the high
redshift broad line AGN population. Due to their peculiar spectral properties
and X-ray weakness, modeling LRDs with standard AGN templates has proven
challenging. In particular, the validity of single-epoch virial mass estimates
in determining the black hole (BH) masses of LRDs has been called into
question, with some models claiming that masses might be overestimated by up to
2 orders of magnitude, and other models claiming that LRDs may be entirely
stellar in nature. We report the direct, dynamical BH mass measurement in a
strongly lensed LRD at $z = 7.04$. The combination of lensing with deep
spectroscopic data reveals a rotation curve that is inconsistent with a nuclear
star cluster, yet can be well explained by Keplerian rotation around a point
mass of 50 million Solar masses, consistent with virial BH mass estimates from
the Balmer lines. The Keplerian rotation leaves little room for any stellar
component in a host galaxy, as we conservatively infer $M_{\rm BH}/M_{*}&gt;2$.
Such a ''naked'' black hole, together with its near-pristine environment,
indicates that this LRD is a massive black hole seed caught in its earliest
accretion phase.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ignas Juodžbalis</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Cosimo Marconcini</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Francesco D'Eugenio</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Roberto Maiolino</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alessandro Marconi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hannah Übler</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jan Scholtz</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xihan Ji</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Santiago Arribas</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jake S. Bennett</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Volker Bromm</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Bunker</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Stefano Carniani</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Stéphane Charlot</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Giovanni Cresci</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Eiichi Egami</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Fabian</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kohei Inayoshi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yuki Isobe</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lucy Ivey</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Gareth C. Jones</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sophie Koudmani</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Nicolas Laporte</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Boyuan Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jianwei Lyu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Giovanni Mazzolari</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Stephanie Monty</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Eleonora Parlanti</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Pablo G. Pérez-González</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Michele Perna</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Brant Robertson</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Raffaella Schneider</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Debora Sijacki</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sandro Tacchella</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alessandro Trinca</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Rosa Valiante</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Marta Volonteri</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Joris Witstok</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Saiyang Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">17 pages, 11 figures. Submitted</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.21748v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.21748v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.21742v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-29T16:08:35Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-29T16:08:35Z</published>
    <title>Orientability of Causal Relations in Time Series using Summary Causal
  Graphs and Faithful Distributions</title>
    <summary>  Understanding causal relations between temporal variables is a central
challenge in time series analysis, particularly when the full causal structure
is unknown. Even when the full causal structure cannot be fully specified,
experts often succeed in providing a high-level abstraction of the causal
graph, known as a summary causal graph, which captures the main causal
relations between different time series while abstracting away micro-level
details. In this work, we present conditions that guarantee the orientability
of micro-level edges between temporal variables given the background knowledge
encoded in a summary causal graph and assuming having access to a faithful and
causally sufficient distribution with respect to the true unknown graph. Our
results provide theoretical guarantees for edge orientation at the micro-level,
even in the presence of cycles or bidirected edges at the macro-level. These
findings offer practical guidance for leveraging SCGs to inform causal
discovery in complex temporal systems and highlight the value of incorporating
expert knowledge to improve causal inference from observational time series
data.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Timothée Loranchet</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Charles K. Assaad</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.21742v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.21742v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ME" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.21739v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-29T16:04:15Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-29T16:04:15Z</published>
    <title>Neural Network Acceleration on MPSoC board: Integrating SLAC's SNL,
  Rogue Software and Auto-SNL</title>
    <summary>  The LCLS-II Free Electron Laser (FEL) will generate X-ray pulses for beamline
experiments at rates of up to 1~MHz, with detectors producing data throughputs
exceeding 1 TB/s. Managing such massive data streams presents significant
challenges, as transmission and storage infrastructures become prohibitively
expensive. Machine learning (ML) offers a promising solution for real-time data
reduction, but conventional implementations introduce excessive latency, making
them unsuitable for high-speed experimental environments. To address these
challenges, SLAC developed the SLAC Neural Network Library (SNL), a specialized
framework designed to deploy real-time ML inference models on
Field-Programmable Gate Arrays (FPGA). SNL's key feature is the ability to
dynamically update model weights without requiring FPGA resynthesis, enhancing
flexibility for adaptive learning applications. To further enhance usability
and accessibility, we introduce Auto-SNL, a Python extension that streamlines
the process of converting Python-based neural network models into
SNL-compatible high-level synthesis code. This paper presents a benchmark
comparison against hls4ml, the current state-of-the-art tool, across multiple
neural network architectures, fixed-point precisions, and synthesis
configurations targeting a Xilinx ZCU102 FPGA. The results showed that SNL
achieves competitive or superior latency in most tested architectures, while in
some cases also offering FPGA resource savings. This adaptation demonstrates
SNL's versatility, opening new opportunities for researchers and academics in
fields such as high-energy physics, medical imaging, robotics, and many more.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Hamza Ezzaoui Rahali</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Abhilasha Dave</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Larry Ruckman</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mohammad Mehdi Rahimifar</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Audrey C. Therrien</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>James J. Russel</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ryan T. Herbst</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.21739v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.21739v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.21727v1</id>
    <updated>2025-08-29T15:50:59Z</updated>
    <published>2025-08-29T15:50:59Z</published>
    <title>OptMark: Robust Multi-bit Diffusion Watermarking via Inference Time
  Optimization</title>
    <summary>  Watermarking diffusion-generated images is crucial for copyright protection
and user tracking. However, current diffusion watermarking methods face
significant limitations: zero-bit watermarking systems lack the capacity for
large-scale user tracking, while multi-bit methods are highly sensitive to
certain image transformations or generative attacks, resulting in a lack of
comprehensive robustness. In this paper, we propose OptMark, an
optimization-based approach that embeds a robust multi-bit watermark into the
intermediate latents of the diffusion denoising process. OptMark strategically
inserts a structural watermark early to resist generative attacks and a detail
watermark late to withstand image transformations, with tailored regularization
terms to preserve image quality and ensure imperceptibility. To address the
challenge of memory consumption growing linearly with the number of denoising
steps during optimization, OptMark incorporates adjoint gradient methods,
reducing memory usage from O(N) to O(1). Experimental results demonstrate that
OptMark achieves invisible multi-bit watermarking while ensuring robust
resilience against valuemetric transformations, geometric transformations,
editing, and regeneration attacks.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Jiazheng Xing</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hai Ci</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hongbin Xu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hangjie Yuan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yong Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mike Zheng Shou</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2508.21727v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2508.21727v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
